<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD JATS (Z39.96) Journal Archiving and Interchange DTD with MathML3 v1.2 20190208//EN" "JATS-archivearticle1-mathml3.dtd"> 
<article xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" article-type="research-article"><?properties open_access?><?DTDIdentifier.IdentifierValue -//Springer-Verlag//DTD A++ V2.4//EN?><?DTDIdentifier.IdentifierType public?><?SourceDTD.DTDName A++V2.4.dtd?><?SourceDTD.Version 2.4?><?ConverterInfo.XSLTName springer2nlmx2.xsl?><?ConverterInfo.Version 1?><front><journal-meta><journal-id journal-id-type="nlm-ta">Nat Commun</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="iso-abbrev">Nat Commun</journal-id><journal-title-group><journal-title>Nature Communications</journal-title></journal-title-group><issn pub-type="epub">2041-1723</issn><publisher><publisher-name>Nature Publishing Group UK</publisher-name><publisher-loc>London</publisher-loc></publisher></journal-meta><article-meta><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid">6978343</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">14121</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1038/s41467-019-14121-1</article-id><article-categories><subj-group subj-group-type="heading"><subject>Article</subject></subj-group></article-categories><title-group><article-title>Synergistic effect of quinary molten salts and ruthenium catalyst for high-power-density lithium-carbon dioxide cell</article-title></title-group><contrib-group><contrib contrib-type="author" equal-contrib="yes"><name><surname>Baek</surname><given-names>Kyungeun</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff1"/></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author" equal-contrib="yes"><name><surname>Jeon</surname><given-names>Woo Cheol</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff1"/></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Woo</surname><given-names>Seongho</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff1"/></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>Jin Chul</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff1"/></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>Jun Gyeong</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff1"/></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author" corresp="yes"><contrib-id contrib-id-type="orcid">http://orcid.org/0000-0002-5239-0296</contrib-id><name><surname>An</surname><given-names>Kwangjin</given-names></name><address><email>kjan@unist.ac.kr</email></address><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff1"/></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author" corresp="yes"><contrib-id contrib-id-type="orcid">http://orcid.org/0000-0002-0332-1534</contrib-id><name><surname>Kwak</surname><given-names>Sang Kyu</given-names></name><address><email>skkwak@unist.ac.kr</email></address><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff1"/></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author" corresp="yes"><contrib-id contrib-id-type="orcid">http://orcid.org/0000-0002-9921-6674</contrib-id><name><surname>Kang</surname><given-names>Seok Ju</given-names></name><address><email>sjkang@unist.ac.kr</email></address><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff1"/></contrib><aff id="Aff1"><institution-wrap><institution-id institution-id-type="ISNI">0000 0004 0381 814X</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="GRID">grid.42687.3f</institution-id><institution>Department of Energy Engineering, </institution><institution>School of Energy and Chemical Engineering, Ulsan National Institute of Science and Technology (UNIST), </institution></institution-wrap>Ulsan, 44919 Republic of Korea </aff></contrib-group><pub-date pub-type="epub"><day>23</day><month>1</month><year>2020</year></pub-date><pub-date pub-type="pmc-release"><day>23</day><month>1</month><year>2020</year></pub-date><pub-date pub-type="collection"><year>2020</year></pub-date><volume>11</volume><elocation-id>456</elocation-id><history><date date-type="received"><day>20</day><month>6</month><year>2019</year></date><date date-type="accepted"><day>16</day><month>12</month><year>2019</year></date></history><permissions><copyright-statement>&#x000a9; The Author(s) 2020</copyright-statement><license license-type="OpenAccess"><license-p><bold>Open Access</bold> This article is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International License, which permits use, sharing, adaptation, distribution and reproduction in any medium or format, as long as you give appropriate credit to the original author(s) and the source, provide a link to the Creative Commons license, and indicate if changes were made. The images or other third party material in this article are included in the article&#x02019;s Creative Commons license, unless indicated otherwise in a credit line to the material. If material is not included in the article&#x02019;s Creative Commons license and your intended use is not permitted by statutory regulation or exceeds the permitted use, you will need to obtain permission directly from the copyright holder. To view a copy of this license, visit <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</ext-link>.</license-p></license></permissions><abstract id="Abs1"><p id="Par1">With a recent increase in interest in metal-gas batteries, the lithium-carbon dioxide cell has attracted considerable attention because of its extraordinary carbon dioxide-capture ability during the discharge process and its potential application as a power source for Mars exploration. However, owing to the stable lithium carbonate discharge product, the cell enables operation only at low current densities, which significantly limits the application of lithium-carbon dioxide batteries and effective carbon dioxide-capture cells. Here, we investigate a high-performance lithium-carbon dioxide cell using a quinary molten salt electrolyte and ruthenium nanoparticles on the carbon cathode. The nitrate-based molten salt electrolyte allows us to observe the enhanced carbon dioxide-capture rate and the reduced discharge-charge over-potential gap with that of conventional lithium-carbon dioxide cells. Furthermore, owing to the ruthernium catalyst, the cell sustains its performance over more than 300 cycles at a current density of 10.0&#x02009;A&#x02009;g<sup>&#x02212;1</sup> and exhibits a peak power density of 33.4&#x02009;mW&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;2</sup>.</p></abstract><abstract id="Abs2" abstract-type="web-summary"><p id="Par2">Lithium-carbon dioxide cells are challenging due to the sluggish electron transfer in the Lithium carbonate in aprotic electrolyte. Here, the authors report synergistic effect of molten salt electrolyte and Ruthenium catalyst to enhance the electrochemical performance of Lithium-carbon dioxide batteries</p></abstract><kwd-group kwd-group-type="npg-subject"><title>Subject terms</title><kwd>Carbon capture and storage</kwd><kwd>Batteries</kwd><kwd>Materials for energy and catalysis</kwd></kwd-group><funding-group><award-group><funding-source><institution-wrap><institution-id institution-id-type="FundRef">https://doi.org/10.13039/501100007053</institution-id><institution>Ministry of Knowledge Economy | Korea Institute of Energy Technology Evaluation and Planning (KETEP)</institution></institution-wrap></funding-source><award-id>20194010201890</award-id><principal-award-recipient><name><surname>Kang</surname><given-names>Seok Ju</given-names></name></principal-award-recipient></award-group></funding-group><funding-group><award-group><funding-source><institution-wrap><institution-id institution-id-type="FundRef">https://doi.org/10.13039/501100003725</institution-id><institution>National Research Foundation of Korea (NRF)</institution></institution-wrap></funding-source><award-id>2018M3D3A1A01055761</award-id><principal-award-recipient><name><surname>Kang</surname><given-names>Seok Ju</given-names></name></principal-award-recipient></award-group></funding-group><custom-meta-group><custom-meta><meta-name>issue-copyright-statement</meta-name><meta-value>&#x000a9; The Author(s) 2020</meta-value></custom-meta></custom-meta-group></article-meta></front><body><sec id="Sec1" sec-type="introduction"><title>Introduction</title><p id="Par3">Rechargeable alkali metal&#x02013;gas cells have attracted considerable interest for high-energy-density storage systems because of their ultralightweight air cathodes such as O<sub>2</sub> and CO<sub>2</sub> gases<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR1">1</xref>&#x02013;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR8">8</xref></sup>. When directly using the lightest Li metal anode, a specific energy of 3860&#x02009;mAh&#x02009;g<sup>&#x02212;1</sup> can be achieved with an O<sub>2</sub> cathode, which undoubtedly solves the energy constraints of the current Li-ion batteries<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR1">1</xref>&#x02013;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR3">3</xref></sup>. However, an unwanted side reaction elicited by the aprotic electrolyte and the carbon current collector significantly erodes the Li&#x02013;O<sub>2</sub> battery performance<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR9">9</xref>&#x02013;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR11">11</xref></sup>. This limitation has ultimately led to intensive research on electrochemically inert electrolytes and novel cathode materials. Among the many innovative proposed material candidates, the nitrate-based molten salt electrolyte and the porous Au cathode exhibited a promising oxygen-evolution reaction (OER)/oxygen-reduction reaction (ORR) ratio, measured by differential electrochemical mass spectrometry (DEMS)<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR12">12</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR13">13</xref></sup>. The key finding behind these studies is that the stable components against the Li&#x02013;O<sub>2</sub> electrochemical reaction effectively minimize the detrimental side reactions and allow operation of the battery cycle without significant degradation.</p><p id="Par4">However, there is still one cumbersome problem: the accumulation of the parasitic product Li<sub>2</sub>CO<sub>3</sub> during the discharge&#x02013;charge processes<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR9">9</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR14">14</xref></sup>. In particular, it is well known that the stable nature of Li<sub>2</sub>CO<sub>3</sub> inevitably induces dead space in the cathode side, which eventually causes decreased cycle ability and increased charge potential. In order to cope with this fatal issue, paradoxically, researchers have successfully proposed a Li&#x02013;CO<sub>2</sub> cell and suggested the importance of its application as both a rechargeable secondary battery and CO<sub>2</sub> capture device to retard global warming<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR5">5</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR15">15</xref>&#x02013;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR22">22</xref></sup>. The proposed CO<sub>2</sub> reduction reaction (CO<sub>2</sub>RR) in the Li&#x02013;CO<sub>2</sub> battery is based on the following electrochemical reaction: 4Li<sup>+</sup> +&#x02009;3CO<sub>2</sub>&#x02009;+&#x02009;4e<sup>&#x02212;</sup>&#x02009;&#x02192;&#x02009;2Li<sub>2</sub>CO<sub>3</sub>&#x02009;+&#x02009;C (2.80&#x02009;V vs. Li/Li<sup>+</sup>)<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR5">5</xref></sup>. During the galvanostatic discharge process, the Li&#x02013;CO<sub>2</sub> cell needs 4/3 electron to capture a single CO<sub>2</sub> gas molecule and produces the 2Li<sub>2</sub>CO<sub>3</sub> and amorphous carbon on the cathode side, indicating that the electron-to-CO<sub>2</sub> ratio (e<sup>&#x02013;</sup>/CO<sub>2</sub>) is 1.33.</p><p id="Par5">Although the Li&#x02013;CO<sub>2</sub> cell effectively captures CO<sub>2</sub> gas during the discharge process, the high charge overpotential caused by the insulating and insoluble characteristics of Li<sub>2</sub>CO<sub>3</sub> in the aprotic electrolyte should be reduced to prevent the severe parasitic reaction<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR7">7</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR15">15</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR16">16</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR23">23</xref></sup>. Therefore, most recent research on Li&#x02013;CO<sub>2</sub> cells has focused on developing air-breathing cathodes such as metal catalysts, mediators, and metal oxide materials for reducing the charge overpotential and increasing the cycle ability<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR8">8</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR18">18</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR24">24</xref>&#x02013;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR28">28</xref></sup>. However, because of the sluggish electron transfer in the Li<sub>2</sub>CO<sub>3</sub> insulator, most of the reported studies investigated Li&#x02013;CO<sub>2</sub> cells with mild current densities (Supplementary Table&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">1</xref>), which are not appropriate for high-performance battery applications, the limiting factor for the CO<sub>2</sub> capture rate; thus, enhancement of the rate performance certainly is advantageous to facilitate practical future battery and CO<sub>2</sub> storage applications of Li&#x02013;CO<sub>2</sub> cell.</p><p id="Par6">Here, we report the demonstration of a high-power-density Li&#x02013;CO<sub>2</sub> cell based on a quinary-molten salt electrolyte containing Ru nanoparticles on the carbon cathode. The employed nitrate-based quinary-molten salt allows high-temperature operation of the Li&#x02013;CO<sub>2</sub> battery, which reduces the discharge&#x02013;charge overpotential. Moreover, the presence of Ru nanoparticles on the carbon cathode prepared by the Joule heating method further improves the electrochemical characteristics of the Li&#x02013;CO<sub>2</sub> cell, resulting in a long cycle life of more than 300 cycles at a high-current density of 10.0&#x02009;A&#x02009;g<sup>&#x02212;1</sup>. In addition, a high-power-density of 33.4&#x02009;mW&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;2</sup> is successfully achieved; this is a potentially decisive factor for next-generation high-rate rechargeable Li&#x02013;CO<sub>2</sub> batteries and efficient CO<sub>2</sub>-capture electrochemical cells.</p></sec><sec id="Sec2" sec-type="results"><title>Results</title><sec id="Sec3"><title>Aprotic electrolyte-based Li&#x02013;CO<sub>2</sub> cell</title><p id="Par7">Following recent Li&#x02013;CO<sub>2</sub> battery studies (Supplementary Table&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">1</xref>), we first fabricated a cell consisting of a Li metal anode, carbon cathode, and 1&#x02009;M lithium bis(trifluoromethanesulfonyl)imide (LiTFSI) in tetraethylene glycol dimethyl ether (TEGDME) electrolyte to monitor the CO<sub>2</sub>RR during the galvanostatic discharge process by using pressure decay measurement. As shown in Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig1" ref-type="fig">1a</xref>, the linear drop of consumed CO<sub>2</sub> molecules indicates that the value of the electrons per CO<sub>2</sub> ratio is ~1.32, which agrees well with the previously proposed discharge electrochemical reaction of 4Li<sup>+</sup> +&#x02009;3CO<sub>2</sub>&#x02009;+&#x02009;4e<sup>&#x02212;</sup>&#x02009;&#x02192;&#x02009;2Li<sub>2</sub>CO<sub>3</sub>&#x02009;+&#x02009;C (2.80&#x02009;V vs. Li/Li<sup>+</sup>)<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR5">5</xref></sup>. In addition, the C1s X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS) spectra of a 1 mAh discharged carbon cathode presented a strong peak at 290&#x02009;eV as shown in Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig1" ref-type="fig">1b</xref>, revealing the formation of Li<sub>2</sub>CO<sub>3</sub> during the discharge process (Supplementary Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">1</xref>)<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR8">8</xref></sup>. However, the amount of CO<sub>2</sub> evolution during the charge process measured by DEMS in Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig1" ref-type="fig">1c</xref> shows that the electrochemical reaction clearly does not follow the discharge reaction of 4Li<sup>+</sup> +&#x02009;3CO<sub>2</sub>&#x02009;+&#x02009;4e<sup>&#x02212;</sup>&#x02009;&#x02192;&#x02009;2Li<sub>2</sub>CO<sub>3</sub>&#x02009;+&#x02009;C (2.80&#x02009;V vs. Li/Li<sup>+</sup>)<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR5">5</xref></sup>. In particular, the different electrochemical reactions and multiple charging plateaus during the charging process have been reported<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR5">5</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR7">7</xref></sup>. For instance, Qiao et al. showed that there are several different pathways to decompose the stable Li<sub>2</sub>CO<sub>3</sub><sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR5">5</xref></sup>. Depending on the applied current and charging voltage, the electrons per CO<sub>2</sub> can be either 1.5 or 2.0 e<sup>&#x02212;</sup>/CO<sub>2</sub> during the charging process, implying an irreversible electrochemical reaction in the Li&#x02013;CO<sub>2</sub> battery. In addition, Zhang et al. observed multiple plateaus with fluctuating evolution rates of CO<sub>2</sub> gas during the charging process<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR7">7</xref></sup>. Nevertheless, to further understand this irreversible electrochemical reaction, we employed a carbon isotope (<sup>13</sup>C) cathode and performed linear-sweep voltammetry with the corresponding DEMS measurements (Supplementary Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">2</xref>). Although both <sup>12</sup>CO<sub>2</sub> and <sup>13</sup>CO<sub>2</sub> (mass weight of 45) are evolved at the same potential, the trace of the mass weight of 45 may not originate from <sup>13</sup>CO<sub>2</sub> because a previous study clearly showed that the decomposition of TEGDME generates fragment-45 owing to the generation of superoxide radicals during the decomposition of Li<sub>2</sub>CO<sub>3</sub>; these results are in good agreement with ours<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR29">29</xref></sup>. In addition, low peak power density of 2.9&#x02009;mW&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;2</sup> (Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig1" ref-type="fig">1d</xref>) and the evolution of H<sub>2</sub> and CO<sub>2</sub> gases at the potentials of 4.2 and 4.7&#x02009;V in a fresh cell before discharging (Supplementary Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">3</xref>) clearly reveal further disadvantages of using aprotic solvent, which ultimately leads us to attempt an alternative electrolyte for high-performance Li&#x02013;CO<sub>2</sub> cell. It is noted that the H<sub>2</sub> evolution from the fresh cell is presumably due to the parasitic reaction between the aprotic electrolyte and the Li metal<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR30">30</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR31">31</xref></sup>.<fig id="Fig1"><label>Fig. 1</label><caption><title>Electrochemical characterizations of Li&#x02013;CO<sub>2</sub> cell by using an aprotic electrolyte.</title><p><bold>a</bold> Plot of CO<sub>2</sub> gas consumption during the galvanostatic discharge (200&#x02009;&#x003bc;A). The Li&#x02013;CO<sub>2</sub> cell contains 1&#x02009;M LiTFSI in TEGDME electrolyte. The red dots indicate the ideal electron-to-CO<sub>2</sub> ratio of 1.33. <bold>b</bold> C1s XPS result of the carbon cathode after 1-mAh discharge. <bold>c</bold> Galvanostatic charge plot and the corresponding DEMS results of the Li&#x02013;CO<sub>2</sub> cell containing 1&#x02009;M LiTFSI in TEGDME electrolyte. The green dots correspond to the theoretical amount of CO<sub>2</sub> evolution. <bold>d</bold> Polarization and power-density curves of 1&#x02009;M LiTFSI in TEGDME with a scan rate of 0.01&#x02009;mA&#x02009;s<sup>&#x02212;1</sup>.</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="41467_2019_14121_Fig1_HTML" id="d29e757"/></fig></p></sec><sec id="Sec4"><title>Molten salt-based Li&#x02013;CO<sub>2</sub> cell</title><p id="Par8">In order to reduce the overpotential at high-current densities during the charge process, we prepared a cell with nitrate-based quinary-molten salt for an aprotic solvent-free electrolyte. The low eutectic melting temperature of the quinary-molten electrolyte allows us not only to perform a systematic study of the Li<sub>2</sub>CO<sub>3</sub> decomposition process in a wide temperature range from 100 to 150&#x02009;&#x000b0;C but also to potentially use for CO<sub>2</sub> capture from the high-temperature power plant flue gas (Supplementary Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">4</xref>)<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR32">32</xref></sup>. As shown in the galvanostatic discharge&#x02013;charge profiles in Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig2" ref-type="fig">2a</xref>, we observed that the operating temperature plays a critical role in reducing the discharge and charge overpotential of the Li&#x02013;CO<sub>2</sub> battery. For instance, the Li&#x02013;CO<sub>2</sub> cell at 150&#x02009;&#x000b0;C exhibits a discharge&#x02013;charge potential gap of 0.7&#x02009;V, whereas the cell at 100&#x02009;&#x000b0;C exhibits an ~2.1&#x02009;V potential gap. In addition, the multiple charging plateaus may be due to the parasitic reaction between the discharge product and the carbon surface, which we will discuss later in Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig4" ref-type="fig">4</xref>. The pressure-drop measurement and Li1s XPS analysis further verify the electrochemical reaction of Li&#x02013;CO<sub>2</sub> cell in the nitrate-based electrolyte (Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig2" ref-type="fig">2b</xref> and Supplementary Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">5</xref>). Although we observed a strong signal at 55.3&#x02009;eV for the Li<sub>2</sub>CO<sub>3</sub> compound, the measured electron-to-CO<sub>2</sub> ratio of 2.0 is in contrast to the aprotic electrolyte-based Li&#x02013;CO<sub>2</sub> cell in Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig1" ref-type="fig">1</xref>. This different electrochemical reaction can be explained by the previous nitrate molten electrolyte-based Li&#x02013;O<sub>2</sub> battery studies because the regeneration of NO<sub>3</sub><sup>&#x02212;</sup> from NO<sub>2</sub><sup>&#x02212;</sup> leads to alter the conventional electrochemical reaction of Li&#x02013;O<sub>2</sub> cell<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR33">33</xref>&#x02013;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR35">35</xref></sup>. In the case of nitrate molten salt in Li&#x02013;CO<sub>2</sub> cell, N1s XPS analysis in Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig2" ref-type="fig">2c</xref> shows the existence of NO<sub>2</sub> compound after the discharge process, which is evidence that the nitrate anion is involved in the electrochemical reaction and altered the electrochemical reaction and discharge potential of Li&#x02013;CO<sub>2</sub> cell (Supplementary Table&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">2</xref>, Supplementary Figs.&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">6</xref>&#x02013;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">7</xref>)<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR33">33</xref>&#x02013;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR35">35</xref></sup>. However, during the charging process, the DEMS results in Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig2" ref-type="fig">2d</xref> found that the CO<sub>2</sub> evolution rates varied with operating temperature. The CO<sub>2</sub> evolution rate increases with decreasing operating temperature, ranging from ~2.0&#x02009;e<sup>&#x02212;</sup>/CO<sub>2</sub> at 100&#x02009;&#x000b0;C to ~6.0&#x02009;e<sup>&#x02212;</sup>/CO<sub>2</sub> at 150&#x02009;&#x000b0;C. The value of 0.02&#x02009;&#x003bc;mol&#x02009;min<sup>&#x02212;1</sup> at 150&#x02009;&#x000b0;C during the galvanostatic charging process indicates that the electrochemical reaction is irreversible and different from the discharge process. In addition, the shifted Li<sub>2</sub>CO<sub>3</sub> peak and the remaining NO<sub>2</sub> compound in the XPS analysis after discharge and charge cycles at 150&#x02009;&#x000b0;C suggests the formation of a new adduct during the charging process that significantly reduces CO<sub>2</sub> evolution (Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig2" ref-type="fig">2e&#x02013;f</xref>). It is noted that the molten salt electrolyte exhibits monotonically increasing CO<sub>2</sub> rate that may be due to the enhanced CO<sub>2</sub> solubility at high temperature. We observed a sharp increase in the gas evolution after CO<sub>2</sub> gas saturation by using a deep discharged cell that also provides electron-to-CO<sub>2</sub> ratio in the molten electrolyte (Supplementary Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">8</xref>). Furthermore, we performed linear-sweep voltammetry and carried out the galvanostatic charging process with the corresponding DEMS measurements at 100&#x02009;&#x000b0;C to confirm the contribution of CO<sub>2</sub> evolution by using the <sup>13</sup>CO<sub>2</sub>&#x02013;<sup>12</sup>C and <sup>12</sup>CO<sub>2</sub>&#x02013;<sup>13</sup>C systems (Supplementary Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">9</xref>). Although we observed evidence of carbon decomposition in the linear-sweep voltammetry results for both systems, the galvanostatic charging process with the corresponding DEMS measurements showed marginal CO<sub>2</sub> evolution from the carbon cathode, which indicates that CO<sub>2</sub> evolution predominantly occurs from Li<sub>2</sub>CO<sub>3</sub> decomposition at 100&#x02009;&#x000b0;C (Supplementary Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">10</xref>).<fig id="Fig2"><label>Fig. 2</label><caption><title>Characterizations of Li&#x02013;CO<sub>2</sub> battery by using quinary-molten salt electrolyte.</title><p><bold>a</bold> Galvanostatic discharge and charge profiles of a Li&#x02013;CO<sub>2</sub> battery with quinary-molten salt electrolyte at different operating temperatures (100&#x02013;150&#x02009;&#x000b0;C) at current density of 0.4&#x02009;A&#x02009;g<sup>&#x02212;1</sup>. <bold>b</bold>&#x02013;<bold>c</bold> High-resolution XPS Li1s (<bold>b</bold>) and N1s (<bold>c</bold>) spectra of the carbon cathode after 1000&#x02009;mAh&#x02009;g<sup>&#x02212;1</sup> discharge. <bold>d</bold> DEMS result of the Li&#x02013;CO<sub>2</sub> cell containing quinary-molten salt electrolyte at different operating temperatures during charge process in <bold>a</bold>. <bold>e</bold>&#x02013;<bold>f</bold> The green dots correspond to the theoretical amount of CO<sub>2</sub> evolution. High-resolution XPS Li1s (<bold>e</bold>) and N1s (<bold>f</bold>) spectra of the carbon cathodes after 1000&#x02009;mAh&#x02009;g<sup>&#x02212;1</sup> discharge and charge processes. The black and red lines indicate the results at operating temperatures of 100 and 150&#x02009;&#x000b0;C, respectively.</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="41467_2019_14121_Fig2_HTML" id="d29e1037"/></fig></p></sec><sec id="Sec5"><title>Reaction mechanism of Li<sub>2</sub>CO<sub>3</sub> decomposition</title><p id="Par9">Although the exact electrochemical reaction remains unclear, we examined the Li<sub>2</sub>CO<sub>3</sub> decomposition mechanism by the density functional theory (DFT) calculation to explain the variation of generating the amount of CO<sub>2</sub> depending on the operating temperature (i.e., 100&#x02009;&#x000b0;C and 150&#x02009;&#x000b0;C) of Li&#x02013;CO<sub>2</sub> cells (see the &#x0201c;Supplementary Methods&#x0201d; section and Supplementary Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">11</xref>). The Li<sub>2</sub>CO<sub>3</sub> decomposition mechanism under implicit quinary-molten salt condition was divided into the electrochemical reaction step, where Li ion is extracted by the charge potential, and the thermodynamic reaction step, where the carbonate on the surface participates in the reaction. We compared the Li extraction energy and activation energy of CO<sub>2</sub> formation reaction by NO<sub>2</sub><sup>&#x02212;</sup> to determine the reaction priority (Supplementary Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">12</xref>). Since the Li extraction energy (i.e., 2.79 and 3.24&#x02009;eV for the first and second Li extraction, respectively) was lower than the activation energy of CO<sub>2</sub> formation reaction (i.e., 4.01&#x02009;eV), it was predicted that the CO<sub>2</sub> formation reaction could occur after the Li extraction reaction. Thus, we suggest path a (Li<sub>2</sub>CO<sub>3</sub>&#x02009;+&#x02009;NO<sub>2</sub><sup>&#x02212;</sup> &#x02192; 2Li<sup>+</sup> +&#x02009;CO<sub>2</sub>&#x02009;+&#x02009;NO<sub>3</sub><sup>&#x02212;&#x02009;</sup>+&#x02009;2e<sup>&#x02212;</sup>) for the decomposition mechanism of Li<sub>2</sub>CO<sub>3</sub> at 100&#x02009;&#x000b0;C (Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig3" ref-type="fig">3a&#x02013;c</xref>). In path a, after the two Li atoms were extracted, carbonate ion reacted with NO<sub>2</sub><sup>&#x02212;</sup> to produce [CO<sub>3</sub>NO<sub>2</sub>]<sup>&#x02212;</sup> at the first intermediate state (IM1). From IM1 to IM2, a bridge O atom bonded to C and N atoms was moved to form NO<sub>3</sub><sup>&#x02212;</sup> and produce CO<sub>2</sub>. Then, CO<sub>2</sub> was desorbed from the surface in the final state (FS). The full-charge N1s XPS analysis showed no peak of NO<sub>2</sub><sup>&#x02212;</sup> because of the generation of NO<sub>3</sub><sup>&#x02212;</sup> as we conjectured (Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig2" ref-type="fig">2f</xref>). At 150&#x02009;&#x000b0;C, as shown in Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig3" ref-type="fig">3b&#x02013;c</xref>, the Li<sub>2</sub>CO<sub>3</sub> decomposition mechanism initially followed the same reaction process of path a. However, after CO<sub>2</sub> and NO<sub>3</sub><sup>&#x02212;</sup> are formed on the surface (IM2&#x02019;) in path b (2Li<sub>2</sub>CO<sub>3</sub>&#x02009;+&#x02009;NO<sub>2</sub><sup>&#x02212;</sup> &#x02192; 4Li<sup>+</sup> +&#x02009;C<sub>2</sub>O<sub>5</sub><sup>2&#x02212;</sup>&#x02009;+&#x02009;NO<sub>3</sub><sup>&#x02212;&#x02009;</sup>+&#x02009;2e<sup>&#x02212;</sup>), CO<sub>2</sub> could react further with the adjacent carbonate to form C<sub>2</sub>O<sub>5</sub><sup>2&#x02212;</sup> (FS&#x02019;). Separately, the unstable carbonate could react with the adjacent carbonate to form C<sub>2</sub>O<sub>6</sub><sup>2&#x02212;</sup> (FS&#x0201d;) in path c (2Li<sub>2</sub>CO<sub>3</sub> &#x02192; 4Li<sup>+</sup> +&#x02009;C<sub>2</sub>O<sub>6</sub><sup>2&#x02212;</sup>&#x02009;+&#x02009;2e<sup>&#x02212;</sup>), where NO<sub>2</sub><sup>&#x02212;</sup> was not used as the reactant in the Li<sub>2</sub>CO<sub>3</sub> decomposition mechanism. The three paths in the reaction mechanisms predicted to be occurred at 150&#x02009;&#x000b0;C were consistent with experimental results, where NO<sub>2</sub><sup>&#x02212;</sup> and NO<sub>3</sub><sup>&#x02212;</sup> presented on the surface and a small amount of CO<sub>2</sub> was released (Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig2" ref-type="fig">2d&#x02013;f</xref>). We speculated that the thermal energy at the higher temperature could promote the reactions of paths b and c; the activation energies of the two mechanisms (i.e., 1.39&#x02009;eV for path b and 1.54&#x02009;eV for path c at 150&#x02009;&#x000b0;C) were higher than the activation energy for the mechanism to produce CO<sub>2</sub> gas (i.e., 0.99&#x02009;eV for path a at 100&#x02009;&#x000b0;C). Interestingly, CO<sub>2</sub> was favored in the adsorbed state considering the endothermic heat of reaction from IM2 to FS in path a without a transition state. This also could be a reason for CO<sub>2</sub> to undergo the reaction step from IM2 to FS at 150&#x02009;&#x000b0;C. All of the optimized configurations in each reaction mechanism are depicted in Supplementary Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">13</xref>. It should be noted that because the proposed pre-equilibrium electrochemical reactions are not the complete reaction mechanism of the charge process, the generation of the short-lived intermediate C<sub>2</sub>O<sub>6</sub><sup>2&#x02212;</sup> produces new adducts, resulting in irreversible CO<sub>2</sub> evolution at 150&#x02009;&#x000b0;C in the DEMS measurements in Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig2" ref-type="fig">2</xref>.<fig id="Fig3"><label>Fig. 3</label><caption><title>Reaction mechanism of Li<sub>2</sub>CO<sub>3</sub> decomposition.</title><p><bold>a</bold> Reaction coordinate of one possible path a to produce CO<sub>2</sub> and NO<sub>3</sub><sup>&#x02212;</sup> (black line) at 100&#x02009;&#x000b0;C. <bold>b</bold> Reaction coordinate of three plausible pathways (i.e., path a, path b to produce C<sub>2</sub>O<sub>5</sub><sup>2&#x02212;</sup> and NO<sub>3</sub><sup>&#x02212;</sup> (red line), and path c to produce C<sub>2</sub>O<sub>6</sub><sup>2&#x02212;</sup> (blue line)) at 150&#x02009;&#x000b0;C. <bold>c</bold> Optimized configurations on three plausible pathways for the reaction step corresponding to (<bold>a</bold>) and (<bold>b</bold>). IS, IM, and FS in each reaction mechanism represent the initial state, intermediate state, and final state, respectively. The yellow dotted line is the boundary between the Li extraction step and the reaction step, and the numbers represent the relative free energies based on those of bare surface in (<bold>a</bold>) and (<bold>b</bold>). Nitrogen, potassium, carbon, oxygen, and lithium atoms are colored in green, purple, light gray, pink, and sky blue. For a clear view, the carbon, oxygen, and lithium atoms, which participate in the reaction, are colored in dark gray, red, and blue. Arrow dotted lines represent the movement of molecules from state to state. For a clear view, the molecules, except reacting molecules, were made to be translucent in (<bold>c</bold>).</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="41467_2019_14121_Fig3_HTML" id="d29e1382"/></fig></p></sec><sec id="Sec6"><title>Electrochemical performance of Li&#x02013;CO<sub>2</sub> cell</title><p id="Par10">To investigate the high-current performance of the quinary-molten salt electrolyte, we evaluated the galvanostatic discharge&#x02013;charge characteristics of the Li&#x02013;CO<sub>2</sub> cell under a current-density range of 1.0&#x02013;20.0&#x02009;A&#x02009;g<sup>&#x02212;1</sup> (Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig4" ref-type="fig">4a</xref>). As shown in the plots, the discharge&#x02013;charge overpotentials were dominantly affected by the applied current densities. For instance, the Li&#x02013;CO<sub>2</sub> battery at an applied current density of 1.0&#x02009;A&#x02009;g<sup>&#x02212;1</sup> had the lowest discharge&#x02013;charge potential gap of 1.0&#x02009;V, whereas that at an applied current of 20.0&#x02009;A&#x02009;g<sup>&#x02212;1</sup> showed the highest potential gap of 1.7&#x02009;V (Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig4" ref-type="fig">4b</xref>). Although the discharge&#x02013;charge overpotential gap monotonically increases with increasing applied current density, the stable discharge&#x02013;charge profiles at 20.0&#x02009;A&#x02009;g<sup>&#x02212;1</sup> clearly suggest that the high-temperature operation of quinary-molten salt at 150&#x02009;&#x000b0;C efficiently enhances the rate performance of the Li&#x02013;CO<sub>2</sub> battery, which is one of the desired battery characteristics and also has the advantage of capturing CO<sub>2</sub> gas from power plants because the high-current density increases the CO<sub>2</sub> capture rate (Supplementary Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">14</xref>). In addition, we observed a high peak power density of 19.7&#x02009;mW&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;2</sup> from the quinary-molten salt-based Li&#x02013;CO<sub>2</sub> cell (Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig4" ref-type="fig">4c</xref>); this value is approximately seven times higher than that of the conventional Li&#x02013;CO<sub>2</sub> battery with 1&#x02009;M LiTFSI in the TEGDME electrolyte (Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig1" ref-type="fig">1d</xref>). We also measured the power density with another ternary-molten salt (37&#x02009;mol% LiNO<sub>3</sub>, 39&#x02009;mol% KNO<sub>2</sub>, and 24&#x02009;mol% CsNO<sub>3</sub>) electrolyte at 150&#x02009;&#x000b0;C (Supplementary Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">15</xref>). Although the peak power density of 16.2&#x02009;mW&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;2</sup> is slightly lower than that of the quinary-molten salt electrolyte, the ternary-molten salt also increases the electrochemical performance in the Li&#x02013;CO<sub>2</sub> battery. The Li&#x02013;CO<sub>2</sub> battery with quinary-molten salt further allows us to observe the long-term cycle capability. As shown in Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig4" ref-type="fig">4d</xref>, the results show stable discharge&#x02013;charge plots over 100 cycles at a high-current density of 2.0&#x02009;A&#x02009;g<sup>&#x02212;1</sup>. We observed that the charge overpotential decreases as the number of cycles increases in Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig4" ref-type="fig">4d</xref>. One plausible explanation is the parasitic reaction between Li<sub>2</sub>CO<sub>3</sub> and the carbon defect sites. Because most metal&#x02013;gas batteries use the capacity cutoff for cycle measurement, a discharge product is formed on a fresh carbon surface every cycle, which causes a parasitic reaction and multiple plateaus during the charging process. Thus, to mitigate the effect of the carbon surface, we also monitored the second cycle after the potential cutoff operation at the first cycle and observed a single charging plateau, indicating that the carbon surface is important for reducing the parasitic reaction during the charging process (Supplementary Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">16</xref>).<fig id="Fig4"><label>Fig. 4</label><caption><title>Electrochemical performance of Li&#x02013;CO<sub>2</sub> cell with quinary-molten salt electrolyte.</title><p><bold>a</bold> Galvanostatic discharge&#x02013;charge profiles of the Li&#x02013;CO<sub>2</sub> battery with quinary-molten salt electrolyte at different current densities from 1.0 to 20.0&#x02009;A&#x02009;g<sup>&#x02212;1</sup> at 150&#x02009;&#x000b0;C. <bold>b</bold> Plots of discharge&#x02013;charge overpotential measured at 500&#x02009;mAh&#x02009;g<sup>&#x02212;1</sup> as a function of current density. <bold>c</bold> Plots of operating voltage and power density versus current density of the Li&#x02013;CO<sub>2</sub> battery at 150&#x02009;&#x000b0;C with scan rate of 0.01&#x02009;mA&#x02009;s<sup>&#x02212;1</sup>. <bold>d</bold> Galvanostatic discharge&#x02013;charge profiles of a Li&#x02013;CO<sub>2</sub> cell with 2.0&#x02009;A&#x02009;g<sup>&#x02212;1</sup> current density over up to 100 cycles.</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="41467_2019_14121_Fig4_HTML" id="d29e1532"/></fig></p></sec><sec id="Sec7"><title>Synthesis of Ru nanoparticles by using Joule heating</title><p id="Par11">Further enhancement of the Li&#x02013;CO<sub>2</sub> cell can be achieved by a carbon cathode with Ru catalyst, because previous reports of Li&#x02013;CO<sub>2</sub> batteries by using aprotic electrolytes indicate that the cathode catalyst efficiently promotes the decomposition of Li<sub>2</sub>CO<sub>3</sub><sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR18">18</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR24">24</xref></sup>. As schematically shown in Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig5" ref-type="fig">5a</xref>, RuCl<sub>3</sub> in H<sub>2</sub>O solution was mixed thoroughly with Super P carbon powder by a Thinky mixer for 10&#x02009;min; then, the composite slurry was coated onto the carbon paper to apply the high current. In particular, the Joule heating method allows us not only to homogeneously disperse the Ru nanoparticles with a controlled size but also to reduce the thermal decomposition time of RuCl<sub>3</sub><sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR36">36</xref>&#x02013;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR38">38</xref></sup>. After a systematic study of Ru nanoparticles with various particle sizes and populations (Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig5" ref-type="fig">5b</xref> (inset) and Supplementary Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">17</xref>), we found well-developed Ru nanoparticles on the carbon cathode from the optimum conditions of 2:1 weight ratio (Super P:Ru) slurry at 8&#x02009;A for 1&#x02009;s. A high-resolution transmission electron microscopy (HR-TEM) measurement further showed well-dispersed Ru particles on the carbon cathode (Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig5" ref-type="fig">5b</xref>). The magnified image in Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig5" ref-type="fig">5c</xref> shows the fringes of the crystalline structure of Ru nanoparticles, where the <italic>d</italic>-spacing of 0.21&#x02009;nm represents the (101) plane of the Ru crystal<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR39">39</xref></sup>. Moreover, the energy-dispersive spectroscopy (EDS) mapping of Ru further supports the well-dispersed Ru nanoparticles on the carbon cathode surface in Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig5" ref-type="fig">5d</xref> (inset image is the mapping of the carbon element), confirming that the Joule heating method is a simple but potent way to develop the Ru catalyst, making it a suitable cathode for Li&#x02013;CO<sub>2</sub> batteries without a polymeric binder<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR40">40</xref></sup>.<fig id="Fig5"><label>Fig. 5</label><caption><title>Joule heating induced Ru nanoparticles.</title><p><bold>a</bold> Schematic illustration of the fabrication procedure of Ru nanoparticles on the carbon cathode by using the Joule heating method. The inset shows a photograph of light emitting from the carbon cathode during Joule heating. Scale bar is 1&#x02009;cm. <bold>b</bold> Bright-field TEM micrograph and SEM image (inset) of the carbon cathode with Ru nanoparticles after applying 8&#x02009;A for 1&#x02009;s. Scale bars are 200&#x02009;nm. <bold>c</bold> High-resolution TEM image of Ru nanoparticles on the carbon cathode. Scale bar is 5&#x02009;nm. <bold>d</bold> EDS mapping of Ru and C (inset) elements of the TEM image in (<bold>b</bold>). Scale bars are 200&#x02009;nm.</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="41467_2019_14121_Fig5_HTML" id="d29e1630"/></fig></p></sec><sec id="Sec8"><title>Synergistic effect of the molten salts and Ru nanoparticles</title><p id="Par12">To evaluate the synergistic effect of the quinary-molten salts and Ru nanoparticles on the carbon cathode on the Li&#x02013;CO<sub>2</sub> cell performance, we performed galvanostatic discharge&#x02013;charge measurements with current density ranging from 1.0 to 20.0&#x02009;A&#x02009;g<sup>&#x02212;1</sup> at 150&#x02009;&#x000b0;C (Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig6" ref-type="fig">6a</xref>). The Ru nanoparticles on the carbon cathode were observed to further reduce the overpotential with a high discharge capacity to form a Li<sub>2</sub>CO<sub>3</sub> discharge product (44,000&#x02009;mAh&#x02009;g<sup>&#x02212;1</sup> at 10.0&#x02009;A&#x02009;g<sup>&#x02212;1</sup> (Supplementary Figs.&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">18</xref>&#x02013;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">19</xref>)). Although the proposed discharge reaction shows continuous consumption of NO<sub>3</sub><sup>&#x02212;</sup> during the discharge process, highly concentrated NO<sub>3</sub><sup>&#x02212;</sup> in the molten salt electrolyte does not significantly alter the electrochemical performance during the discharge process. In addition, the cell operates even at a high-current density of 20.0&#x02009;A&#x02009;g<sup>&#x02212;1</sup> and enhances the CO<sub>2</sub>-capturing capacity, in contrast to the aprotic electrolyte-based Li&#x02013;CO<sub>2</sub> battery with a Ru catalyst (Supplementary Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">20</xref>)<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR24">24</xref></sup>. We observed a sufficiently stable cycle capability of the Li&#x02013;CO<sub>2</sub> battery at a current density at 2.0&#x02009;A&#x02009;g<sup>&#x02212;1</sup> (Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig6" ref-type="fig">6b</xref>), 5.0&#x02009;A&#x02009;g<sup>&#x02212;1</sup> (Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig6" ref-type="fig">6c</xref>), and 10.0&#x02009;A&#x02009;g<sup>&#x02212;1</sup> (Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig6" ref-type="fig">6d</xref>) at 150&#x02009;&#x000b0;C. In particular, the cells are sustained for over 300 cycles at 10.0&#x02009;A&#x02009;g<sup>&#x02212;1</sup> without significant alteration of the voltage potential. Moreover, the Ru nanoparticles in quinary-molten salt exhibited a peak power density approximately two times that of quinary-molten salt without Ru nanoparticles, indicating that the synergistic effect of Ru nanoparticles further reduces the energy barrier during the electrochemical reaction of the Li&#x02013;CO<sub>2</sub> battery (Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig6" ref-type="fig">6e</xref>). In particular, we theoretically revealed that the addition of the Ru surface induced the electron transfer from CO<sub>2</sub><sup>&#x02212;</sup> to Ru particles to stabilize CO<sub>2</sub><sup>&#x02212;</sup>, reducing the energy of the thermodynamic barrier (i.e., overpotential) (Supplementary Figs.&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">21</xref>&#x02013;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">23</xref>). Consequently, the power density of Li&#x02212;CO<sub>2</sub> battery was enhanced. As summarized in Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig6" ref-type="fig">6f</xref>, the peak power density of 33.4&#x02009;mW&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;2</sup> is 13 times higher than that of the conventional Li&#x02013;CO<sub>2</sub> battery with the aprotic electrolyte (Supplementary Figs.&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">24</xref>&#x02013;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">25</xref>), suggesting that the quinary-molten salts and the Ru nanoparticles on the carbon cathode make the Li&#x02013;CO<sub>2</sub> cell a feasible high-performance CO<sub>2</sub> capture and energy-storage system.<fig id="Fig6"><label>Fig. 6</label><caption><title>Electrochemical performance of Li&#x02013;CO<sub>2</sub> cell by using molten salt and Ru nanoparticle.</title><p><bold>a</bold> Galvanostatic discharge&#x02013;charge profiles of the Li&#x02013;CO<sub>2</sub> battery with quinary-molten salt electrolyte with a Ru nanoparticle cathode at different current densities from 1.0 to 20.0&#x02009;A&#x02009;g<sup>&#x02212;1</sup> at 150&#x02009;&#x000b0;C. Cycling performance of the Li&#x02013;CO<sub>2</sub> battery at current rates of 2.0&#x02009;A&#x02009;g<sup>&#x02212;1</sup> (<bold>b</bold>), 5.0&#x02009;A&#x02009;g<sup>&#x02212;1</sup> (<bold>c</bold>), and 10.0&#x02009;A&#x02009;g<sup>&#x02212;1</sup> (<bold>d</bold>). <bold>e</bold> Polarization and power-density curves of quinary-molten salt electrolyte with the Ru nanoparticle cathode with a scan rate of 0.01&#x02009;mA&#x02009;s<sup>&#x02212;1</sup>. <bold>f</bold> Plots of peak power density of 1&#x02009;M LiTFSI in TEGDME (gray); quinary-molten salt at 100, 110, 130, and 150&#x02009;&#x000b0;C (blue); quinary-molten salt electrolyte with a Ru nanoparticle cathode at 150&#x02009;&#x000b0;C (orange).</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="41467_2019_14121_Fig6_HTML" id="d29e1819"/></fig></p></sec></sec><sec id="Sec9" sec-type="discussion"><title>Discussion</title><p id="Par13">We have demonstrated a high-performance Li&#x02013;CO<sub>2</sub> cell based on the quinary-molten salt electrolyte with Ru nanoparticles on the carbon cathode. From the systematic DEMS investigation with in-depth theoretical investigation, we suggested a newly proposed decomposing reaction mechanism of the Li<sub>2</sub>CO<sub>3</sub> compound in the nitrate-based molten salt at a high temperature. In addition, the synergistic effect of the quinary-molten salt and the well-distributed Ru catalyst on the carbon cathode allowed us to observe high-rate performance and long-term cycle capability over more than 300 cycles without significant alteration. The Li&#x02013;CO<sub>2</sub> battery ultimately achieved the highest peak power density of 33.4&#x02009;mW&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;2</sup>, confirming that the Li&#x02013;CO<sub>2</sub> cell is suitable as a high-current-rate rechargeable battery and a high-rate CO<sub>2</sub> capture device.</p></sec><sec id="Sec10"><title>Methods</title><sec id="Sec11"><title>Preparation of nitrate-based molten salt electrolyte</title><p id="Par14">Lithium nitrate (LiNO<sub>3</sub>), potassium nitrate (KNO<sub>3</sub>), potassium nitrite (KNO<sub>2</sub>), sodium nitrate (NaNO<sub>3</sub>), calcium nitrate (Ca(NO<sub>3</sub>)<sub>2</sub>), and cesium nitrate (CsNO<sub>3</sub>) salts were purchased from Sigma-Aldrich (USA), with purity <inline-formula id="IEq1"><alternatives><tex-math id="M1">\documentclass[12pt]{minimal}
				\usepackage{amsmath}
				\usepackage{wasysym} 
				\usepackage{amsfonts} 
				\usepackage{amssymb} 
				\usepackage{amsbsy}
				\usepackage{mathrsfs}
				\usepackage{upgreek}
				\setlength{\oddsidemargin}{-69pt}
				\begin{document}$$\ge$$\end{document}</tex-math><mml:math id="M2"><mml:mo>&#x02265;</mml:mo></mml:math><inline-graphic xlink:href="41467_2019_14121_Article_IEq1.gif"/></alternatives></inline-formula>99%, and vacuum-dried at 60&#x02009;&#x000b0;C for 24&#x02009;h. We used a specific eutectic composition of 15&#x02009;mol% LiNO<sub>3</sub>, 30&#x02009;mol% KNO<sub>3</sub>, 30&#x02009;mol% CsNO<sub>3</sub>, 10&#x02009;mol% NaNO<sub>3</sub>, and 15&#x02009;mol% Ca(NO<sub>3</sub>)<sub>2</sub> for the quinary-molten salt, and 37&#x02009;mol% LiNO<sub>3</sub>, 39&#x02009;mol% KNO<sub>2</sub>, and 24&#x02009;mol% CsNO<sub>3</sub> for the ternary-molten salt. The mixture was heated in a ceramic crucible with a torch<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR32">32</xref></sup>. The glass microfiber (GF) separator (GF/C, Whatman, UK) with diameter 16&#x02009;mm was then dipped in the molten eutectic salt (eutectic temperatures, <italic>T</italic><sub>e</sub>: 75 and 98&#x02009;&#x000b0;C for the quinary and ternary-molten salts, respectively, Supplementary Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">4</xref>) to infuse the GF separator and cooled to room temperature. The infused GF separator was dried at ~50&#x02009;&#x000b0;C in vacuum in an oven for 12&#x02009;h and transferred into an Ar-filled glove box. The mass of the infused electrolyte was ~160&#x02009;mg.</p></sec><sec id="Sec12"><title>Synthesis of Ru nanoparticles</title><p id="Par15">Ruthenium(III) chloride hydrate (RuCl<sub>3</sub>&#x000b7;xH<sub>2</sub>O, Sigma-Aldrich (USA)) solution (50&#x02009;mg&#x02009;ml<sup>&#x02212;1</sup> in H<sub>2</sub>O) was mixed with carbon (Super P, Timcal (Imerys Graphite &#x00026; Carbon), Switzerland) at a weight ratio of 2:1 (Super P:Ru) by a Thinky mixer for 10&#x02009;min. The homogenously mixed carbon with Ru solution was coated onto the carbon paper (AvCarb P50, FuelCellStore (USA)) using a doctor blade. The coated electrode was then dried at 120&#x02009;&#x000b0;C in a vacuum oven for 6&#x02009;h to completely eliminate the residual solvent. The RuCl<sub>3</sub>&#x02013;carbon electrodes were treated by electric Joule heating to form Ru nanoparticles on the carbon. To perform the Joule heating, the sample was connected to copper electrodes and electrically connected to an external power source (Regulated DC Power Supply TDP-3010B, TOYOTECH, Korea) in an argon-filled glove box. A current pulse of 8&#x02009;A was applied through the sample, which created a Joule heating time of 1&#x02009;s. The loading mass of Ru on Super P (Ru&#x02009;+&#x02009;Super P) was ~0.45&#x02009;mg&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;2</sup>.</p></sec><sec id="Sec13"><title>Li&#x02013;CO<sub>2</sub> cell assembly</title><p id="Par16">For the preparation of the cathode for the aprotic electrolyte, the air cathode was fabricated using a mixture of Ketjen black carbon (EC-300J) or a carbon isotope (Carbon-<sup>13</sup>C, Sigma-Aldrich (USA)) with a 60&#x02009;wt% polytetrafluoroethylene (PTFE, Sigma-Aldrich, USA) binder at a weight ratio 9:1 (carbon:binder). The mixture was dispersed in water solution and cast on a SUS mesh (stainless-steel mesh, Shinmyung Science Inc.) current collector. The mixture was dried overnight at 120&#x02009;&#x000b0;C in a vacuum oven to eliminate the residual solvents. The cathode-loading mass was ~0.3&#x02009;mg&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;2</sup>.</p><p id="Par17">For the preparation of cathodes for the quinary-molten salt electrolyte, Super P porous carbon was homogeneously mixed with a 60&#x02009;wt% PTFE binder (weight ratio&#x02009;=&#x02009;9:1) in a water solution. A P50 carbon cathode was then coated with the Super P mixture using a doctor blade, and the coated electrode was then dried at 120&#x02009;&#x000b0;C in a vacuum oven for 6&#x02009;h to completely eliminate the residual solvent. The loading mass weight of Super P carbon was ~0.45&#x02009;mg&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;2</sup>.</p><p id="Par18">In all, 1&#x02009;M LiTFSI in the TEGDME was purchased from Enchem (Korea) and stored in an Ar-filled glove box with moisture and oxygen levels of &#x0003c;1&#x02009;ppm. The Li&#x02013;CO<sub>2</sub> cell was assembled into a 2032-format coin cell (Hohsen, CR2032, Japan) containing 30 holes with diameters of 1&#x02009;mm for the Li&#x02013;CO<sub>2</sub> electrochemical test. The pure-Li metal anode with thickness of 300&#x02009;&#x003bc;m was purchased from FMC (Korea) and used as received. The GF separator was dried overnight at 150&#x02009;&#x000b0;C in a vacuum oven. The cell fabrication was carried out in an Ar atmosphere (H<sub>2</sub>O and O<sub>2</sub>&#x02009;&#x0003c;&#x02009;1&#x02009;ppm). A quinary- or ternary-molten-salt-based Li&#x02013;CO<sub>2</sub> cell was fabricated by placing an electrolyte-infused GF separator on Li metal having a diameter of 11&#x02009;mm using a 2032 coin cell with 30 holes with diameters of 1&#x02009;mm. Li metal/electrolyte-infused GF separator/carbon cathode cells were pressurized by using a crimping machine.</p></sec><sec id="Sec14"><title>Material characterization</title><p id="Par19">The morphology of the Ru nanoparticles on the carbon cathode was characterized using high-resolution transmission electron microscopy (HR-TEM; JEM-2100F, JEOL, Japan) at an accelerating voltage of 200&#x02009;kV. The discharge products for carbon with and without the Ru nanoparticle cathode were analyzed by using a scanning electron microscope (SEM; S-4800, Hitachi High Technologies, Japan) at an acceleration voltage of 5.0&#x02009;kV, and X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS) experiments were performed on a scanning X-ray microprobe (ESCALAB 250XI, Thermo Fisher Scientific, USA). The Raman spectrum data were collected using a confocal Raman (WITec, Alpha 300R, 532&#x02009;nm) system with an acceleration voltage of 1.0&#x02009;eV. For the post-discharge analysis of the electrodes, the disassembled cathodes from the cells were then packed in an Ar-filled glove box before they were transferred to the SEM chamber or Raman spectrometer.</p></sec><sec id="Sec15"><title>Electrochemical measurements</title><p id="Par20">Galvanostatic cycling at various current densities (0.05&#x02013;20.0&#x02009;A&#x02009;g<sup>&#x02212;1</sup>) and power analysis were used to evaluate battery performance (capacity, voltage, and power density) by using a computer-controlled battery measurement system (WBCS 3000, WonATech, Korea and VMP3 Multichannel Workstation, BioLogic). For the experiments performed, the aprotic electrolytes were tested at room temperature, and the quinary-molten salt electrolyte was tested at various operating temperatures (100&#x02013;150&#x02009;&#x000b0;C) in a lab-built heating kit. The details of the differential electrochemical mass spectrometer (DEMS) system are described elsewhere<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR41">41</xref></sup>. Prior to measurement of the electrochemical performance of the quinary-molten-salt-based Li&#x02013;CO<sub>2</sub> battery, the cell was maintained at a constant temperature (100&#x02013;150&#x02009;&#x000b0;C) to fully impregnate the quinary salt and stabilize the gas pressure (1050&#x02009;Torr). Carbon dioxide gas with an isotope of carbon (<sup>13</sup>CO<sub>2</sub>) was purchased from Cambridge Isotope Laboratories, Inc. The input power required to maintain a temperature of 150&#x02009;&#x000b0;C was ~0.6&#x02009;mW.</p></sec></sec><sec sec-type="supplementary-material"><title>Supplementary information</title><sec id="Sec16"><p>
<supplementary-material content-type="local-data" id="MOESM1"><media xlink:href="41467_2019_14121_MOESM1_ESM.pdf"><caption><p>Supplementary information</p></caption></media></supplementary-material>
</p></sec></sec></body><back><fn-group><fn><p><bold>Peer review information</bold>
<italic>Nature Communications</italic> thanks Xingbin Yan and other, anonymous, reviewers for their contributions to the peer review of this work.</p></fn><fn><p><bold>Publisher&#x02019;s note</bold> Springer Nature remains neutral with regard to jurisdictional claims in published maps and institutional affiliations.</p></fn><fn><p>These authors contributed equally: Kyungeun Baek, Woo Cheol Jeon</p></fn></fn-group><sec><title>Supplementary information</title><p><bold>Supplementary information</bold> is available for this paper at 10.1038/s41467-019-14121-1.</p></sec><ack><title>Acknowledgements</title><p>This work was supported by &#x0201c;Human Resources Program in Energy Technology&#x0201d; of the Korea Institute of Energy Technology Evaluation and Planning (KETEP), granted financial resource from the Ministry of Trade, Industry &#x00026; Energy, Republic of Korea (No. 20194010201890), and C1 Gas Refinery Program through the National Research Foundation of Korea (NRF) funded by the Ministry of Science and ICT (NRF-2018M3D3A1A01055761).</p></ack><notes notes-type="author-contribution"><title>Author contributions</title><p>K.B. carried out most of the experimental work and characterization. W.C.J., J.C.K., and S.K.K. performed theoretical calculation. S.W. contributed to cell fabrication. J.G.L. and K.A. synthesized the nanoparticles and performed TEM measurement. K.A. and S.K.K. provided comments and conceived the project. S.J.K. supervised the project and analyzed the data. S.J.K and S.K.K. wrote the paper, and all authors discussed the results and commented on the paper.</p></notes><notes notes-type="data-availability"><title>Data availability</title><p>The data that support the findings of this study are available from the corresponding author upon request.</p></notes><notes notes-type="COI-statement"><title>Competing interests</title><p id="Par21">The authors declare no competing interests.</p></notes><ref-list id="Bib1"><title>References</title><ref id="CR1"><label>1.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Girishkumar</surname><given-names>G</given-names></name><name><surname>McCloskey</surname><given-names>B</given-names></name><name><surname>Luntz</surname><given-names>AC</given-names></name><name><surname>Swanson</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name><surname>Wilcke</surname><given-names>W</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Lithium&#x02013;air battery: promise and challenges</article-title><source>J. Phys. Chem., Lett.</source><year>2010</year><volume>1</volume><fpage>2193</fpage><lpage>2203</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/jz1005384</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR2"><label>2.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Bruce</surname><given-names>PG</given-names></name><name><surname>Freunberger</surname><given-names>SA</given-names></name><name><surname>Hardwick</surname><given-names>LJ</given-names></name><name><surname>Tarascon</surname><given-names>J&#x02013;M</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Li&#x02013;O<sub>2</sub> and Li&#x02013;S batteries with high energy storage</article-title><source>Nat. Mater.</source><year>2012</year><volume>11</volume><fpage>19</fpage><lpage>29</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1038/nmat3191</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR3"><label>3.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Lu</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Aprotic and aqueous Li&#x02013;O<sub>2</sub> batteries</article-title><source>Chem. Rev.</source><year>2014</year><volume>11</volume><fpage>5611</fpage><lpage>5640</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/cr400573b</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR4"><label>4.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Kang</surname><given-names>SJ</given-names></name><name><surname>Mori</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name><name><surname>Narizuka</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name><surname>Wilcke</surname><given-names>W</given-names></name><name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>H&#x02013;C</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Deactivation of carbon electrode for elimination of carbon dioxide evolution from rechargeable lithium&#x02013;oxygen cells</article-title><source>Nat. Commun.</source><year>2014</year><volume>5</volume><fpage>3937</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1038/ncomms4937</pub-id><?supplied-pmid 24849589?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">24849589</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR5"><label>5.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Qiao</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Li-CO<sub>2</sub> electrochemistry: a new strategy for CO<sub>2</sub> fixation and energy storage</article-title><source>Joule</source><year>2017</year><volume>1</volume><fpage>359</fpage><lpage>370</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.joule.2017.07.001</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR6"><label>6.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Zhou</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>A quasi-solid-state flexible fiber-shaped Li&#x02013;CO<sub>2</sub> battery with low overpotential and high energy efficiency</article-title><source>Adv. Mater.</source><year>2018</year><volume>31</volume><fpage>1804439</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/adma.201804439</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR7"><label>7.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>Z</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Verifying the rechargeability of Li&#x02013;CO<sub>2</sub> batteries on working cathodes of Ni nanoparticles highly dispersed on N-doped graphene</article-title><source>Adv. Sci.</source><year>2018</year><volume>5</volume><fpage>1700567</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/advs.201700567</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR8"><label>8.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Xing</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Crumpled Ir nanosheets fully covered on porous carbon nanofibers for long-life rechargeable Lithium&#x02013;CO<sub>2</sub> batteries</article-title><source>Adv. Mater.</source><year>2018</year><volume>30</volume><fpage>1803124</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/adma.201803124</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR9"><label>9.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>McCloskey</surname><given-names>BD</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Twin problems of interfacial carbonate formation in nonaqueous Li&#x02013;O<sub>2</sub> batteries</article-title><source>J. Phys. Chem. Lett.</source><year>2012</year><volume>3</volume><fpage>997</fpage><lpage>1001</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/jz300243r</pub-id><?supplied-pmid 26286562?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">26286562</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR10"><label>10.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Ottakam Thotiyl</surname><given-names>MM</given-names></name><name><surname>Freunberger</surname><given-names>SA</given-names></name><name><surname>Peng</surname><given-names>Z</given-names></name><name><surname>Bruce</surname><given-names>PG</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>The carbon electrode in nonaqueous Li&#x02013;O<sub>2</sub> cells</article-title><source>J. Am. Chem. Soc.</source><year>2013</year><volume>135</volume><fpage>494</fpage><lpage>500</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/ja310258x</pub-id><?supplied-pmid 23190204?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">23190204</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR11"><label>11.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>McCloskey</surname><given-names>BD</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Limitations in rechargeability of Li-O<sub>2</sub> batteries and possible origins</article-title><source>J. Phys. Chem. Lett.</source><year>2012</year><volume>3</volume><fpage>3043</fpage><lpage>3047</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/jz301359t</pub-id><?supplied-pmid 26292247?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">26292247</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR12"><label>12.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Giordani</surname><given-names>V</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>A molten salt lithium&#x02013;oxygen battery</article-title><source>J. Am. Chem. Soc.</source><year>2016</year><volume>138</volume><fpage>2656</fpage><lpage>2663</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/jacs.5b11744</pub-id><?supplied-pmid 26871485?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">26871485</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR13"><label>13.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Peng</surname><given-names>Z</given-names></name><name><surname>Freunberger</surname><given-names>SA</given-names></name><name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><name><surname>Bruce</surname><given-names>PG</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>A reversible and higher-rate Li-O<sub>2</sub> battery</article-title><source>Science</source><year>2012</year><volume>337</volume><fpage>1223985</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1126/science.1223985</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR14"><label>14.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Zhao</surname><given-names>Z</given-names></name><name><surname>Huang</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name><surname>Peng</surname><given-names>Z</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Achilles&#x02019; Heel of lithium&#x02013;air batteries: Lithium carbonate</article-title><source>Angew. Chem. Int. Ed.</source><year>2018</year><volume>57</volume><fpage>3874</fpage><lpage>3886</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/anie.201710156</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR15"><label>15.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>X</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Rechargeable Li&#x02013;CO<sub>2</sub> batteries with carbon nanotubes as air cathode</article-title><source>Chem. Commun.</source><year>2015</year><volume>51</volume><fpage>14636</fpage><lpage>14639</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1039/C5CC05767A</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR16"><label>16.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>A rechargeable Li-CO<sub>2</sub> battery with a gel polymer electrolyte</article-title><source>Angew. Chem. Int. Ed.</source><year>2017</year><volume>56</volume><fpage>9126</fpage><lpage>9130</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/anie.201705017</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR17"><label>17.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Hu</surname><given-names>X</given-names></name><name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>Z</given-names></name><name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Flexible Li-CO<sub>2</sub> batteries with liquid-free electrolyte</article-title><source>Angew. Chem. Int. Ed.</source><year>2017</year><volume>129</volume><fpage>5879</fpage><lpage>5883</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/ange.201701928</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR18"><label>18.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Yang</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>A reversible lithium&#x02013;CO<sub>2</sub> battery with Ru nanoparticles as a cathode catalyst</article-title><source>Energy Environ. Sci.</source><year>2017</year><volume>10</volume><fpage>972</fpage><lpage>978</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1039/C6EE03770D</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR19"><label>19.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>B</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Recent advances in understanding Li&#x02013;CO<sub>2</sub> electrochemistry</article-title><source>Energy Environ. Sci.</source><year>2019</year><volume>12</volume><fpage>887</fpage><lpage>922</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1039/C8EE03417F</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR20"><label>20.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>Q</given-names></name><name><surname>Luo</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name><surname>Zhong</surname><given-names>Z</given-names></name><name><surname>Borgna</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>CO<sub>2</sub> capture by solid adsorbents and their applications: current status and new trends</article-title><source>Energy Environ. Sci.</source><year>2011</year><volume>4</volume><fpage>42</fpage><lpage>55</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1039/C0EE00064G</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR21"><label>21.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name><name><surname>Lyu</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name><name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Rechargeable Li/CO<sub>2</sub>-O<sub>2</sub> (2:1) battery and Li/CO<sub>2</sub> battery</article-title><source>Energy Environ. Sci.</source><year>2014</year><volume>7</volume><fpage>677</fpage><lpage>681</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1039/c3ee43318h</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR22"><label>22.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>Z</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>The first introduction of graphene to rechargeable Li-CO<sub>2</sub> batteries</article-title><source>Angew. Chem. Int. Ed.</source><year>2015</year><volume>57</volume><fpage>6550</fpage><lpage>6553</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/anie.201501214</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR23"><label>23.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Qie</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name><name><surname>Lin</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><name><surname>Connell</surname><given-names>JW</given-names></name><name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name><surname>Dai</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Highly rechargeable lithium-CO<sub>2</sub> batteries with a boron- and nitrogen-codoped holey-graphene cathode</article-title><source>Angew. Chem. Int. Ed.</source><year>2017</year><volume>56</volume><fpage>6970</fpage><lpage>6974</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/anie.201701826</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR24"><label>24.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Qiao</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Transient, in situ synthesis of ultrafine ruthenium nanoparticles for a high-rate Li&#x02013;CO<sub>2</sub> battery</article-title><source>Energy Environ. Sci.</source><year>2019</year><volume>12</volume><fpage>1100</fpage><lpage>1107</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1039/C8EE03506G</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR25"><label>25.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Yin</surname><given-names>W</given-names></name><name><surname>Grimaud</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name><surname>Azcarate</surname><given-names>I</given-names></name><name><surname>Yang</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name><name><surname>Tarascon</surname><given-names>J-M</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Electrochemical reduction of CO<sub>2</sub> mediated by quinone derivatives: implication for Li&#x02013;CO<sub>2</sub> battery</article-title><source>J. Phys. Chem. C.</source><year>2018</year><volume>122</volume><fpage>6546</fpage><lpage>6554</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/acs.jpcc.8b00109</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR26"><label>26.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Drawing a pencil-trace cathode for a high-performance polymer-based Li&#x02013;CO<sub>2</sub> battery with redox mediator</article-title><source>Adv. Funct. Mater.</source><year>2019</year><volume>29</volume><fpage>1806863</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/adfm.201806863</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR27"><label>27.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>X</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>High performance Li&#x02013;CO<sub>2</sub> batteries with NiO&#x02013;CNT cathodes</article-title><source>J. Mater. Chem. A</source><year>2018</year><volume>6</volume><fpage>2792</fpage><lpage>2796</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1039/C7TA11015D</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR28"><label>28.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Ma</surname><given-names>W</given-names></name><name><surname>Lu</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name><surname>Lei</surname><given-names>X</given-names></name><name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>X</given-names></name><name><surname>Ding</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Porous Mn<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub> cathode for highly durable Li&#x02013;CO<sub>2</sub> batteries</article-title><source>J. Mater. Chem. A</source><year>2018</year><volume>6</volume><fpage>20829</fpage><lpage>20835</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1039/C8TA06143B</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR29"><label>29.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Yang</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name><surname>He</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name><name><surname>Zhou</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Exploring the electrochemical reaction mechanism of carbonate oxidation in Li&#x02013;air/CO<sub>2</sub> battery through tracing missing oxygen</article-title><source>Energy Environ. Sci.</source><year>2016</year><volume>9</volume><fpage>1650</fpage><lpage>1654</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1039/C6EE00004E</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR30"><label>30.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Walker</surname><given-names>W</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>A rechargeable Li&#x02013;O<sub>2</sub> battery using a lithium nitrate/<italic>N,N</italic>-dimethylacetamide electrolyte</article-title><source>J. Am. Chem. Soc.</source><year>2013</year><volume>135</volume><fpage>2076</fpage><lpage>2079</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/ja311518s</pub-id><?supplied-pmid 23360567?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">23360567</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR31"><label>31.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Ahn</surname><given-names>SM</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>High-performance lithium-oxygen battery electrolyte derived from optimum combination of solvent and lithium salt</article-title><source>Adv. Sci.</source><year>2017</year><volume>4</volume><fpage>1700235</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/advs.201700235</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR32"><label>32.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Raade</surname><given-names>JW</given-names></name><name><surname>Padowitz</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Development of molten salt heat transfer fluid with low melting point and high thermal stability</article-title><source>J. Sol. Energy Eng.</source><year>2011</year><volume>133</volume><fpage>031013</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1115/1.4004243</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR33"><label>33.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Uddin</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Lithium nitrate as regenerable SEI stabilizing agent for rechargeable Li/O<sub>2</sub> batteries</article-title><source>J. Phys. Chem. Lett.</source><year>2013</year><volume>4</volume><fpage>3760</fpage><lpage>3765</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/jz402025n</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR34"><label>34.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Jaumann</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Role of 1, 3-dioxolane and LiNO<sub>3</sub> addition on the long term stability of nanostructured silicon/carbon anodes for rechargeable lithium batteries</article-title><source>J. Electrochem. Soc.</source><year>2016</year><volume>163</volume><fpage>A557</fpage><lpage>A564</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1149/2.1011603jes</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR35"><label>35.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Baek</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Chemically impregnated NiO catalyst for molten electrolyte based gas-tank-free Li&#x02013;O<sub>2</sub> battery</article-title><source>J. Power Sources</source><year>2018</year><volume>402</volume><fpage>68</fpage><lpage>74</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.jpowsour.2018.09.027</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR36"><label>36.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Yao</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Carbothermal shock synthesis of high-entropy-alloy nanoparticles</article-title><source>Science</source><year>2018</year><volume>359</volume><fpage>1489</fpage><lpage>1494</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1126/science.aan5412</pub-id><?supplied-pmid 29599236?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">29599236</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR37"><label>37.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Yang</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Ultrafine silver nanoparticles for seeded lithium deposition toward stable lithium metal anode</article-title><source>Adv. Mater.</source><year>2017</year><volume>29</volume><fpage>1702714</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/adma.201702714</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR38"><label>38.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Yao</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>In situ high temperature synthesis of single-component metallic nanoparticles</article-title><source>ACS Cent. Sci.</source><year>2017</year><volume>3</volume><fpage>294</fpage><lpage>301</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/acscentsci.6b00374</pub-id><?supplied-pmid 28470046?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">28470046</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR39"><label>39.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Feng</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><name><surname>Yang</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name><name><surname>Ye</surname><given-names>F</given-names></name><name><surname>Yang</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Selective electrocatalysts toward a prototype of the membraneless direct methanol fuel cell</article-title><source>Sci. Rep.</source><year>2014</year><volume>4</volume><fpage>3813</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1038/srep03813</pub-id><?supplied-pmid 24448514?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">24448514</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR40"><label>40.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Yao</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Carbon welding by ultrafast Joule heating</article-title><source>Nano Lett.</source><year>2016</year><volume>16</volume><fpage>7282</fpage><lpage>7289</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/acs.nanolett.6b03888</pub-id><?supplied-pmid 27739680?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">27739680</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR41"><label>41.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>McCloskey</surname><given-names>BD</given-names></name><name><surname>Bethune</surname><given-names>DS</given-names></name><name><surname>Shelby</surname><given-names>RM</given-names></name><name><surname>Girishkumar</surname><given-names>G</given-names></name><name><surname>Luntz</surname><given-names>AC</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Solvents&#x02019; critical role in nonaqueous lithium&#x02013;oxygen battery electrochemistry</article-title><source>J. Phys. Chem. Lett.</source><year>2011</year><volume>2</volume><fpage>1161</fpage><lpage>1166</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/jz200352v</pub-id><?supplied-pmid 26295320?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">26295320</pub-id></element-citation></ref></ref-list></back></article>