<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD JATS (Z39.96) Journal Archiving and Interchange DTD with MathML3 v1.2 20190208//EN" "JATS-archivearticle1-mathml3.dtd"> 
<article xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" article-type="research-article" xml:lang="EN"><?properties open_access?><?DTDIdentifier.IdentifierValue -//ACS//DTD ACS Journal DTD v1.02 20061031//EN?><?DTDIdentifier.IdentifierType public?><?SourceDTD.DTDName ACSJournal-v102.dtd?><?SourceDTD.Version 1.02?><?ConverterInfo.XSLTName acs2nlmx2.xsl?><?ConverterInfo.Version 1?><front><journal-meta><journal-id journal-id-type="nlm-ta">ACS Omega</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="iso-abbrev">ACS Omega</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">ao</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="coden">acsodf</journal-id><journal-title-group><journal-title>ACS Omega</journal-title></journal-title-group><issn pub-type="epub">2470-1343</issn><publisher><publisher-name>American Chemical Society</publisher-name></publisher></journal-meta><article-meta><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid">6787888</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmid">31616808</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/acsomega.9b01541</article-id><article-categories><subj-group><subject>Article</subject></subj-group></article-categories><title-group><article-title>Ceramic Nanoparticle-Decorated Melt-Electrospun
PVDF Nanofiber Membrane with Enhanced Performance as a Lithium-Ion
Battery Separator</article-title></title-group><contrib-group><contrib contrib-type="author" id="ath1"><name><surname>Wu</surname><given-names>Shuanglin</given-names></name><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff">&#x02020;</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author" id="ath2"><name><surname>Ning</surname><given-names>Jingxia</given-names></name><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff">&#x02020;</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author" id="ath3"><name><surname>Jiang</surname><given-names>Feng</given-names></name><xref rid="aff2" ref-type="aff">&#x02021;</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author" id="ath4"><name><surname>Shi</surname><given-names>Jiayi</given-names></name><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff">&#x02020;</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author" corresp="yes" id="ath5"><name><surname>Huang</surname><given-names>Fenglin</given-names></name><xref rid="cor1" ref-type="other">*</xref><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff">&#x02020;</xref><xref rid="aff3" ref-type="aff">&#x000a7;</xref></contrib><aff id="aff1"><label>&#x02020;</label>Key Laboratory of
Eco-Textiles, Ministry of Education, <institution>Jiangnan
University</institution>, Wuxi 214122, <country>China</country></aff><aff id="aff2"><label>&#x02021;</label>Department
of Wood Science, <institution>University of British Columbia</institution>, Vancouver V6T 1Z4, <country>Canada</country></aff><aff id="aff3"><label>&#x000a7;</label><institution>Jiangsu Anreda New Materials Limited Company</institution>, Changzhou 21300, <country>China</country></aff></contrib-group><author-notes><corresp id="cor1"><label>*</label>E-mail: <email>flhuang@jiangnan.edu.cn</email>.</corresp></author-notes><pub-date pub-type="epub"><day>27</day><month>09</month><year>2019</year></pub-date><pub-date pub-type="collection"><day>08</day><month>10</month><year>2019</year></pub-date><volume>4</volume><issue>15</issue><fpage>16309</fpage><lpage>16317</lpage><history><date date-type="received"><day>27</day><month>05</month><year>2019</year></date><date date-type="accepted"><day>19</day><month>09</month><year>2019</year></date></history><permissions><copyright-statement>Copyright &#x000a9; 2019 American Chemical Society</copyright-statement><copyright-year>2019</copyright-year><copyright-holder>American Chemical Society</copyright-holder><license><license-p>This is an open access article published under an ACS AuthorChoice <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://pubs.acs.org/page/policy/authorchoice_termsofuse.html">License</ext-link>, which permits copying and redistribution of the article or any adaptations for non-commercial purposes.</license-p></license></permissions><abstract><p content-type="toc-graphic"><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="ao9b01541_0004" id="ab-tgr1"/></p><p>Designing a composite
separator that can withstand high temperature, deliver high capacity,
and offer fast charge&#x02013;discharge capability is imperative for
developing a high-performance lithium-ion battery. Here, a series
of ceramic nanoparticle-coated nanofiber membranes, including Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub>/poly(vinylidene fluoride) (PVDF), SiO<sub>2</sub>/PVDF, and Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub>/SiO<sub>2</sub>/PVDF, were
prepared by melt-electrospinning and magnetron sputtering deposition.
Among all of these composite separators, Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub>/SiO<sub>2</sub>/PVDF showed several advantages including excellent
thermal stability (no dimensional shrinkage at temperature up to 130
&#x000b0;C and an onset degradation temperature of 445 &#x000b0;C) and superb
electrolyte compatibility (340% electrolyte uptake). In addition,
the &#x003b2; phase of the fibrous PVDF membrane as well as the presence
of polar ceramic nanoparticles on the fiber surface can synergistically
improve the ion conductivity to 2.055 mS/cm at room temperature, which
is more than 8 times higher than that of the commercial polyethylene
(PE) separator. Performance of these ceramic nanoparticle-coated separators
in a lithium-ion battery demonstrated an improved discharge capacity
of 161.5 mAh/g and more than 84.3% capacity retention rate after 100
cycles. The ceramic nanoparticle-coated PVDF separators also maintained
58.4% capacity at a high current density of 8C, which is better than
the 49.8% capacity for the commercial PE separator. Therefore, the
ceramic nanoparticle-coated PVDF membrane proves to be a promising
separator for a high-power and more secure lithium-ion battery.</p></abstract><custom-meta-group><custom-meta><meta-name>document-id-old-9</meta-name><meta-value>ao9b01541</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>document-id-new-14</meta-name><meta-value>ao-2019-01541c</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>ccc-price</meta-name><meta-value/></custom-meta></custom-meta-group></article-meta></front><body><sec id="sec1"><label>1</label><title>Introduction</title><p>The lithium-ion battery has witnessed widespread applications ranging
from portable electronics to electric vehicles or even electric grids,
all benefiting from its high energy density, high power density, long
cycle life, and environmental friendliness.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref1">1</xref></sup> The design of the lithium-ion battery includes a cathode, an anode,
and a separator, where the separator is a critical component that
separates the anode from the cathode to prevent short circuit while
allowing rapid transport of lithium ions in the liquid electrolyte.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref2">2</xref></sup> To date, most commercial separators are made
from polyolefin membranes. Although these membranes are characterized
with excellent mechanical strength and chemical stability, they also
suffer from severe disadvantages such as low porosity (about 40%),
poor electrolyte wettability, low thermal stability, and unidirectional
mechanical integrity.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref2">2</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref3">3</xref></sup></p><p>Poly(vinylidene fluoride)
(PVDF) has recently been investigated for a lithium-ion separator
due to its superior film properties as compared to polyolefin ones,
including good electrolyte affinity, excellent thermal stability,
and superb electrochemical performances.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref4">4</xref></sup> Other than these excellent physical properties, the &#x003b2; phase
(TTTT) of the PVDF crystal shows the highest polarity and dielectric
constant among all five crystal phases of PVDF,<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref5">5</xref></sup> which can benefit the ionization of lithium salt in the
electrolyte, thereby increasing the lithium ion concentration in the
electrolyte and improving the ionic conductivity. It has also been
reported that both strong electric field and high temperature are
favorable for the growth of the &#x003b2; phase.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref6">6</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref7">7</xref></sup> Therefore,
it is significant to explore a film-forming strategy that can provide
both high temperature and strong
electric field.</p><p>Recently, electrospinning has been widely used
in fabricating nanofibrous membranes for lithium-ion battery separator
applications,<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref8">8</xref>&#x02212;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref10">10</xref></sup> as
electrospinning can offer membranes with favorable characteristics
such as controllable fiber diameter, large specific surface area,
and high porosity, which will necessarily lead to high electrolyte
absorption and retention rate, as well as improved lithium ion conductivity.
In general, electrospinning can be performed using either polymer
melts or polymer solutions.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref11">11</xref></sup> In comparison,
melt-electrospinning (ME) is more economical and environmentally friendly
due to the absence of organic solvents and the simplicity of the process.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref12">12</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref13">13</xref></sup> In addition, as introduced previously, the high temperature and
strong electric field during melt-electrospinning can favor the growth
of the &#x003b2; phase of PVDF, which is hypothesized to improve the
electrochemical performance of the PVDF separator.</p><p>Coating commercial
lithium-ion battery separators with ceramic layers, such as SiO<sub>2</sub>, Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub>, ZrO2, TiO<sub>2</sub>, and
CeO<sub>2</sub>,<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref14">14</xref>&#x02212;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref19">19</xref></sup> has been extensively explored as an effective and
economic way to improve the thermal stability and wettability of the
separator. However, the conventional ceramic coating can also lead
to several intrinsic disadvantages. First, the ceramic coating can
block separator pores, resulting in poor electrolyte permeability
and increased internal resistance of batteries.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref20">20</xref>&#x02212;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref22">22</xref></sup> Second, the ceramic-coated separator consumes
more than 20% binders that leads to increased production cost.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref23">23</xref></sup> In addition, the large thickness of the ceramic
layer, ranging from 3 to 20 &#x003bc;m, can increase the transfer resistance
of the composite separator.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref24">24</xref></sup> To address
these problems, we propose a simple and feasible method, magnetron
sputtering, to deposit ceramic nanoparticles onto the surface of the
separator. Magnetron sputtering deposition (MSD) has been demonstrated
as an effective surface modification method with a precise control
of the nanoparticle shape, size, and distribution by adjusting the
process parameters, such as power, pressure, and deposition time.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref25">25</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref26">26</xref></sup></p><p>Herein, we successfully fabricate a novel fibrous separator
by melt-electrospinning and magnetron sputtering. It is hypothesized
that melt-electrospinning can introduce both high temperature and
strong electric field to induce the growth of the &#x003b2; phase in
the PVDF membrane. In addition, magnetron sputtering can grow nanometer-thick
ceramic nanoparticle layers on PVDF fibers, which can further enhance
electrolyte and lithium electrode affinity. By means of melt-electrospinning
and magnetron sputtering, the as-fabricated ceramic nanoparticle-coated
membrane showed improved thermal stability, electrolyte uptake and
affinity, lowered impedance, and interfacial resistance, as well as
enhanced discharge capacity and cycling performance in the lithium-ion
battery.</p></sec><sec id="sec2"><label>2</label><title>Results and
Discussion</title><sec id="sec2.1"><label>2.1</label><title>Morphological
and Chemical Analyses of Membranes</title><p>Fourier transform infrared
(FTIR) spectra of both the PVDF pellet and melt-electrospun membrane
were acquired to investigate the effect of temperature and electric
field on the crystalline-phase transformation. Both spectra showed
the characteristic absorption peaks at 1186, 976, 876, 796, 765, and
615 cm<sup>&#x02013;1</sup>, associated with the &#x003b1; crystalline
phase of PVDF, as well as those at 1279, 1074, and 840 cm<sup>&#x02013;1</sup>, associated with the &#x003b2; phase of PVDF.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref27">27</xref></sup> Compared to the spectrum of the PVDF pellet, the peaks at 1148 and
850 cm<sup>&#x02013;1</sup> associated with the &#x003b1; phase disappeared
in ME-PVDF, whereas the intensities of other &#x003b1;-phase peaks at
976, 796, 765, and 615 cm<sup>&#x02013;1</sup> decreased significantly.
In addition, it clearly showed that the &#x003b2;-phase peaks at 1279
and 840 cm<sup>&#x02013;1</sup> increased significantly after the melt-electrospun
treatment. At operating temperature above the melting point of PVDF,
the crystal phase in PVDF pellets starts to melt and the molecular
chain mobility increases with the increase of temperature;<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref28">28</xref></sup> under the action of the electric field, the
rotation of the molecular chain and the orientation of the intrinsic
dipoles lead to the all-trans plane zigzag conformation, thereby increasing
the PVDF &#x003b2;-phase content as fibers cool down.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref29">29</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref30">30</xref></sup> The
change of these peaks indicates that both the high temperature and
strong electric field can synergistically increase the &#x003b2;-phase
content of the ME-PVDF.</p><p>The &#x003b2;-phase content of each membrane
was calculated from the FTIR spectra by applying<disp-formula id="eq1"><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="ao9b01541_m001" position="anchor"/><label>1</label></disp-formula>where <italic>F</italic>(&#x003b2;) represents the &#x003b2;-phase content; <italic>A</italic><sub>&#x003b1;</sub> and <italic>A</italic><sub>&#x003b2;</sub> are the absorbances at 765 and 840 cm<sup>&#x02013;1</sup>, respectively,
corresponding to the &#x003b1;- and &#x003b2;-phase material; and <italic>K</italic><sub>&#x003b1;</sub> and <italic>K</italic><sub>&#x003b2;</sub> are the absorption coefficients at the respective wavenumber. The
value of <italic>K</italic><sub>&#x003b1;</sub> is 6.1 &#x000d7; 10<sup>4</sup> cm<sup>2</sup>/mol and that of <italic>K</italic><sub>&#x003b2;</sub> is 7.7 &#x000d7; 10<sup>4</sup> cm<sup>2</sup>/mol.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref30">30</xref></sup> The <italic>F</italic>(&#x003b2;) values of the PVDF pellet
and ME-PVDF are 0.36 &#x000b1; 0.01 and 0.61 &#x000b1; 0.04, respectively.
Therefore, the significant increase of the <italic>F</italic>(&#x003b2;)
value in the melt-eletrospun membrane suggests that the melt-electrospinning
process can promote the crystal formation of the
&#x003b2; phase (<xref rid="fig1" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig1" ref-type="fig">1</xref></xref>).</p><fig id="fig1" position="float"><label>Figure 1</label><caption><p>FTIR spectra of ME-PVDF
and PVDF pellets.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="ao9b01541_0009" id="gr1" position="float"/></fig><p>The morphologies and porous structure of the polyethylene
(PE) membrane, ME-PVDF, and ceramic nanoparticle-coated membranes
were demonstrated by scanning electron microscopy (SEM) images (<xref rid="fig2" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig2" ref-type="fig">2</xref></xref>). The PE membrane
with a typical porous structure is shown in <xref rid="fig2" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig2" ref-type="fig">2</xref></xref>e. The as-spun PVDF membrane presents a three-dimensional
network structure with abundant open pores among the fibers (the inset
in <xref rid="fig2" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig2" ref-type="fig">2</xref></xref>a). ME-PVDF
fibers show a rather smooth surface with an average diameter of 3.18
&#x000b1; 0.63 &#x003bc;m. After sputter-coating, the PVDF fibers clearly
showed increased roughness and the surface becomes more corrugated
(<xref rid="fig2" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig2" ref-type="fig">2</xref></xref>b&#x02013;d).
The increased surface roughness is hypothesized to be beneficial to
the liquid electrolyte absorption, which will be further discussed
in the latter part. As expected, the average fiber diameters increased
to 3.28 &#x000b1; 0.04, 3.25 &#x000b1; 0.08, and 3.26 &#x000b1; 0.02 &#x003bc;m
for the Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub>/SiO<sub>2</sub>/PVDF, Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub>/PVDF, and SiO<sub>2</sub>/PVDF membranes, respectively,
corresponding to respective ca. 50, 35, and 40 nm ceramic nanoparticle
coating layers. Although the fiber diameters increased after sputter-coating,
all of the ceramic nanoparticle-coated membranes remain porous, suggesting
that the open pores were unaffected by the deposition of nanoparticles
(the inset in <xref rid="fig2" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig2" ref-type="fig">2</xref></xref>b&#x02013;d). The presence of ceramic nanoparticles on the surface
of ME-PVDF fibers was verified from the energy-dispersive spectrum
(EDS) (<xref rid="fig3" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig3" ref-type="fig">3</xref></xref>). The
uncoated PVDF membrane showed only signals for C and F, whereas Al
and Si atoms can be observed from the Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub>-
and SiO<sub>2</sub>-coated membrane with respective 0.12 and 0.32
wt % content (inset table in <xref rid="fig3" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig3" ref-type="fig">3</xref></xref>). The less Al content on the membrane could be due
to the low-power setup during coating. As expected, both Al and Si
atoms could be observed from the Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub>/SiO<sub>2</sub>/PVDF composite membrane, with respective 0.04 and 0.12 wt
% content. Overall, the Al and Si contents on the Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub>/SiO<sub>2</sub>/PVDF composite membrane are less than those
on the respective Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub>/PVDF and SiO<sub>2</sub>/PVDF membrane, as the coating time was halved for the Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub>/SiO<sub>2</sub>/PVDF membrane.</p><fig id="fig2" position="float"><label>Figure 2</label><caption><p>SEM images of (a) ME-PVDF, (b) Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub>/SiO<sub>2</sub>/PVDF, (c) Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub>/PVDF, (d)
SiO<sub>2</sub>/PVDF composite membrane, and (e) PE membrane. Insets
are low-magnification
SEM images.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="ao9b01541_0001" id="gr2" position="float"/></fig><fig id="fig3" position="float"><label>Figure 3</label><caption><p>EDS elemental
analysis of ME-PVDF, Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub>/SiO<sub>2</sub>/PVDF,
Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub>/PVDF, and SiO<sub>2</sub>/PVDF composite
nanofiber membranes.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="ao9b01541_0006" id="gr3" position="float"/></fig></sec><sec id="sec2.2"><label>2.2</label><title>Thermal Stability of the Membranes</title><p>The thermal stability of the separator membrane is a critical safety
factor for lithium-ion batteries, as heat can be generated from continuous
electrochemical reactions during charging and discharging within the
battery. In addition, LIB has also been used at elevated temperature
and/or at excessive discharge current, which requires high thermal
stability that can withstand the temperature rise during service.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref31">31</xref></sup> Separators without satisfying thermal stability
tend to shrink or melt as the temperature increases, which can lead
to short circuit or even explosion. The dimensional changes of polyethylene
(PE) and ME-PVDF membranes after heating at 130 &#x000b0;C for 0.5 h
are presented in <xref rid="fig4" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig4" ref-type="fig">4</xref></xref>a. At a starting diameter of 18 mm, the PE membrane shrank drastically
with more than 47% areal shrinkage, whereas the ME-PVDF membrane only
showed approximately 11% areal shrinkage. The higher thermal stability
of the ME-PVDF membrane is expected considering its higher melting
point of 170 &#x000b0;C as compared to the 130 &#x000b0;C for PE. After
coating with ceramic nanoparticles, no obvious shrinkage could be
observed, which demonstrates that the deposited ceramic nanoparticles
can significantly improve the thermal stability of the ME-PVDF membranes.
The uniformly deposited ceramic nanoparticles can serve as a thermostable
framework to resist the dimensional variation of PVDF separators at
high temperatures.</p><fig id="fig4" position="float"><label>Figure 4</label><caption><p>(a) Photographs of PE and ME-PVDF, Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub>/SiO<sub>2</sub>/PVDF, Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub>/PVDF, and
SiO<sub>2</sub>/PVDF separator membranes before and after thermal
treatment at 130
&#x000b0;C for 2 h. (b) Thermogravimetric (TG) and (c) differential scanning
calorimetry (DSC) curves of ME-PVDF, Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub>/SiO<sub>2</sub>/PVDF, Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub>/PVDF, and SiO<sub>2</sub>/PVDF membranes.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="ao9b01541_0002" id="gr4" position="float"/></fig><p>The thermal stabilities of the ME-PVDF, Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub>/SiO<sub>2</sub>/PVDF, Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub>/PVDF, and SiO<sub>2</sub>/PVDF composite membranes were further
characterized by thermogravimetric (TG) curves under a nitrogen atmosphere
from 200 to 700 &#x000b0;C (<xref rid="fig4" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig4" ref-type="fig">4</xref></xref>b). The TG curves of all four membranes showed almost
no mass loss at temperatures below 400 &#x000b0;C, indicating high thermal
stability of the PVDF fibrous membrane. The onset degradation temperature
was used to identify the temperature at which the membranes start
to degrade, which showed increased values from 415 &#x000b0;C for the
uncoated membrane to 421 &#x000b0;C for both Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub>/PVDF and SiO<sub>2</sub>/PVDF membranes and 445 &#x000b0;C for the
Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub>/SiO<sub>2</sub>/PVDF membrane. The increased
onset temperature after ceramic nanoparticle coating indicates improved
thermal stability, which is caused by the more thermally stable outer
inorganic layer. However, the char residues at 700 &#x000b0;C decreased
with ceramic nanoparticle coating, showing respective values of 33.18,
29.41, 27.97, and 24.63% for ME-PVDF, Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub>/PVDF,
SiO<sub>2</sub>/PVDF, and Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub>/SiO<sub>2</sub>/PVDF membranes. The decreased char residues might be due to the
generation of hydrogen fluoride during the decomposition of PVDF,<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref32">32</xref></sup> which can easily react with Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub> and SiO<sub>2</sub> to lead to greater weight loss on the
residual portion of the membranes. The melting temperature of all
four PVDF membrane was investigated from DSC curves (<xref rid="fig4" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig4" ref-type="fig">4</xref></xref>c), showing slightly increased
values from 168.6 &#x000b0;C for the pure ME-PVDF separator to 169.8,
169.7, and 169.7 &#x000b0;C for Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub>/SiO<sub>2</sub>/PVDF, Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub>/PVDF, and SiO<sub>2</sub>/PVDF,
respectively. The slightly increased melting temperature by the ceramic
nanoparticle coating can be attributed to its interaction with PVDF
fibers, which could restrict the polymer chain mobility.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref33">33</xref></sup></p><p>In essence, ceramic nanoparticle coating
can significantly improve the thermal stability of the ME-PVDF membranes,
as indicated by less thermal shrinkage at 130 &#x000b0;C, increased melting
temperature, and increased onset degradation temperature. Therefore,
the ceramic nanoparticle-coated PVDF membrane can be better suited
for lithium-ion battery applications.</p></sec><sec id="sec2.3"><label>2.3</label><title>Porosity and Electrolyte Uptake of Membranes</title><p>Ionic conductivity represents the rate of lithium-ion transportation
between the cathode and anode and is essential to the LIB performance.
It is highly dependent on the porosity and affinity toward electrolyte.
Compared to the commercial PE separator, the ME-PVDF separator showed
much higher porosity (74.8 vs 46.2%) (<xref rid="tbl1" ref-type="other">Table <xref rid="tbl1" ref-type="other">1</xref></xref>). The high porosity of the melt-electrospun
membrane is expected due to the large interfiber spacings as previously
observed from SEM imaging. In contrast, pores on the commercial PE
separator were generated by hot stretching of the PE film, which can
only create a limited number of open pores within the film structure.
It is therefore concluded that melt-electrospinning can effectively
fabricate highly porous membranes for LIB separators. Ceramic nanoparticle
coating can slightly lower the porosity to around 62&#x02013;69% due
to the increased fiber diameters, but it is still significantly higher
than the porosity of the PE membrane.</p><table-wrap id="tbl1" position="float"><label>Table 1</label><caption><title>Performance
of ME-PVDF,
Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub>/SiO<sub>2</sub>/PVDF, Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub>/PVDF, SiO<sub>2</sub>/PVDF, and PE Membranes</title></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups" border="0"><colgroup><col align="left"/><col align="left"/><col align="char" char="."/><col align="char" char="."/><col align="char" char="."/><col align="char" char="."/></colgroup><thead><tr><th style="border:none;" align="center">sample</th><th style="border:none;" align="center">thickness (&#x003bc;m)</th><th style="border:none;" align="center" char=".">bulk
resistance (&#x003a9;)</th><th style="border:none;" align="center" char=".">ion conductivity (mS/cm,&#x000a0;25&#x000a0;&#x000b0;C)</th><th style="border:none;" align="center" char=".">electrolyte uptake (%)</th><th style="border:none;" align="center" char=".">porosity (%)</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="border:none;" align="left">ME-PVDF</td><td style="border:none;" align="left">50</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">3.30</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">0.754</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">339.9</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">74.8</td></tr><tr><td style="border:none;" align="left">Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub>/SiO<sub>2</sub>/PVDF</td><td style="border:none;" align="left">50.1</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">1.21</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">2.055</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">366.2</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">61.8</td></tr><tr><td style="border:none;" align="left">Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub>/PVDF</td><td style="border:none;" align="left">50.1</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">1.90</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">1.309</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">346.6</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">69.2</td></tr><tr><td style="border:none;" align="left">SiO<sub>2</sub>/PVDF</td><td style="border:none;" align="left">50.1</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">2.63</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">0.946</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">369.6</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">62.4</td></tr><tr><td style="border:none;" align="left">PE</td><td style="border:none;" align="left">25</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">5.14</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">0.242</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">155.6</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">46.2</td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap><p>Apart from high porosity,
good affinity between the separator and electrolyte is also critical
for its electrochemical performance, as good wetting performance can
facilitate the fast lithium-ion transport through a membrane. The
wetting properties of the four membranes were evaluated by the liquid
electrolyte spreading test (with 10 &#x003bc;L of electrolyte) and contact
angle measurement (with 5 &#x003bc;L of electrolyte). The spreading
of a drop of liquid electrolyte on the surface of ME-PVDF, Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub>/SiO<sub>2</sub>/PVDF, Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub>/PVDF, SiO<sub>2</sub>/PVDF, and PE membranes was recorded in <xref rid="fig6" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig6" ref-type="fig">6</xref></xref>a, showing limited
wetting on the PE membrane and fast spreading through the whole ME-PVDF,
Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub>/SiO<sub>2</sub>/PVDF, Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub>/PVDF, and SiO<sub>2</sub>/PVDF membranes within 2 s. In addition,
the liquid electrolyte contact angles (<xref rid="fig5" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig5" ref-type="fig">5</xref></xref>b) on ME-PVDF, Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub>/SiO<sub>2</sub>/PVDF, Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub>/PVDF, SiO<sub>2</sub>/PVDF, and PE membranes were quantified as 25.1, 18.3, 20.7,
16.0, and 46.3&#x000b0;, respectively. It is clear that the PVDF membrane
showed much better wetting behavior than that of the PE membrane.
This could be due to the existence of the polar bonds (C&#x02013;F)
in the PVDF separator, therefore generating strong interaction with
the polar electrolyte. In contrast, the PE membrane was made from
hydrophobic polyolefin, which resulted in poor wettability with the
polar liquid electrolyte.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref21">21</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref34">34</xref></sup> As expected, coating
of the PVDF membrane with ceramic nanoparticles can further lower
the contact angle due to the more polar Si&#x02013;O and Al&#x02013;O
bonds. An electrolyte update test was conducted to further confirm
the porosity and wettability of the membranes. Due to its low porosity
and poor wettability with the liquid electrolyte, the PE membrane
only showed 155.6% electrolyte uptake, which is less than half of
the electrolyte uptake for the uncoated and coated PVDF membranes
(346.6&#x02013;369.6%) (<xref rid="tbl1" ref-type="other">Table <xref rid="tbl1" ref-type="other">1</xref></xref>). Combining with high porosity, high electrolyte uptake,
and better wettability, the ceramic nanoparticle-coated membranes
were expected to demonstrate improved electrochemical performance
as compared to that of the commercial PE membrane or uncoated PVDF
membrane.</p><fig id="fig5" position="float"><label>Figure 5</label><caption><p>(a) Photographs of the wetting behavior. (b) Initial contact
angles
of the ME-PVDF, Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub>/SiO<sub>2</sub>/PVDF,
Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub>/PVDF, SiO<sub>2</sub>/PVDF, and PE membranes
with the liquid electrolyte.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="ao9b01541_0007" id="gr5" position="float"/></fig></sec><sec id="sec2.4"><label>2.4</label><title>Electrochemical
Performance of Membranes</title><p>To determine the electrochemical
performance of ME-PVDF and ceramic nanoparticle-coated membranes,
electrochemical impedance spectra (EIS) were used to measure their
ionic conductivity (<xref rid="fig6" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig6" ref-type="fig">6</xref></xref>a,b). Based on <xref rid="eq4" ref-type="disp-formula">eq <xref rid="eq4" ref-type="disp-formula">4</xref></xref>, the ionic conductivities of the PE, ME-PVDF,
Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub>/SiO<sub>2</sub>/PVDF, Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub>/PVDF, and SiO<sub>2</sub>/PVDF separators were calculated
to be 0.242, 0.754, 2.055, 1.309, and 0.946 at room temperature, respectively.
The ionic conductivity of the PVDF membrane is more than 3 times of
that of the PE membrane, which can be explained by its higher porosity
and better electrolyte affinity. The ceramic nanoparticle coating
can further enhance the ionic conductivity due to the improved liquid
electrolyte affinity by the more polar inorganic oxide nanoparticles.
The compatibility of the lithium electrode with these membranes was
also evaluated by EIS using a Li/membrane/Li symmetric cell. <xref rid="fig6" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig6" ref-type="fig">6</xref></xref>c shows the Nyquist
plots of the Li/separator/Li cell at the open-circuit potential. The
interfacial impedance between the lithium electrode and PE membrane
was 83 &#x003a9;, which can be significantly reduced to 33, 29, 30,
and 26 &#x003a9; for ME-PVDF, Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub>/SiO<sub>2</sub>/PVDF, Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub>/PVDF, and SiO<sub>2</sub>/PVDF
membranes, respectively. The cell using ceramic nanoparticle-modified
separators showed a reduced electrochemical resistance than that of
the ME-PVDF separator, indicating smooth ion transport between the
ceramic nanoparticle-coated separators and electrodes. Moreover, the
SiO<sub>2</sub>/PVDF membrane exhibited the smallest interfacial impedance
and therefore had the best separator&#x02013;electrode compatibility.
This is consistent with a previous research that a very thin inorganic
oxide layer can negate the interfacial impedance between the solid-state
electrolyte and lithium metal, owing to the high binding energy between
lithium and the alumina layer.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref35">35</xref></sup></p><fig id="fig6" position="float"><label>Figure 6</label><caption><p>(a) Electrochemical impedance
spectroscopy (EIS) profiles
of ME- PVDF, Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub>/SiO<sub>2</sub>/PVDF, Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub>/PVDF, SiO<sub>2</sub>/PVDF, and PE membranes
at 25 &#x000b0;C; (b) magnified image of the EIS profile; (c) AC impedance
spectra, and (d) linear sweep voltammograms (LSV) of the different
separators.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="ao9b01541_0008" id="gr6" position="float"/></fig><p>The electrochemical stability of the composite membranes was investigated
by the linear sweep voltammetry (LSV) method. The electrochemical
operating window of membranes is described in <xref rid="fig6" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig6" ref-type="fig">6</xref></xref>d. The obtained result for the PE separator
saturated with the liquid electrolyte indicated that oxidative decomposition
happens at the potential of about 4.5 V (vs Li/Li<sup>+</sup>), which
was ascribed to the low oxidative stability of the solvent components
in the organic liquid electrolyte. Much higher oxidative potentials
can be observed for the ceramic-modified separators. The Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub>/SiO<sub>2</sub>/PVDF separator was stable up to about
5.7 V electrochemically.</p></sec><sec id="sec2.5"><label>2.5</label><title>Battery Performance Analysis</title><p>The charge&#x02013;discharge
measurement can directly assess the effect of the ceramic nanoparticle-coated
separators on the electrochemical performance of batteries. <xref rid="fig7" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig7" ref-type="fig">7</xref></xref>a displays the initial
charge&#x02013;discharge profiles of Li/separator/LiNiCoMn cells cycled
at 0.5C. The initial discharge capacities for the battery using PE
and ME-PVDF membranes as separators were 153.0 and 156.1 mAh/g, respectively,
which slightly increased to 161.5, 159.8, and 158.8 mAh/g for Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub>/SiO<sub>2</sub>/PVDF, Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub>/PVDF, and SiO<sub>2</sub>/PVDF separators, respectively. It can
be observed that the LiNiCoMn electrode using the ceramic nanoparticle-coated
separators exhibited a slightly higher initial reversible capacity
and lower charge&#x02013;discharge potential gap compared with those
of the one using the PE separator, possibly due to the higher ionic
conductivity of the ceramic nanoparticle-coated membranes (<xref rid="fig7" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig7" ref-type="fig">7</xref></xref>a).</p><fig id="fig7" position="float"><label>Figure 7</label><caption><p>(a) Initial
discharge capacity of the cells. (b) Battery cycle performance under
100 cycles of the 0.5C charge/discharge rate. (c) Rate capacity tests
using the ME-PVDF, Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub>/SiO<sub>2</sub>/PVDF,
Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub>/PVDF, SiO<sub>2</sub>/PVDF, and PE separators.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="ao9b01541_0003" id="gr7" position="float"/></fig><p><xref rid="fig7" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig7" ref-type="fig">7</xref></xref>b presents the cyclic
stability of the LiNiCoMn cathode using various separators in the
voltage range of 2.8&#x02013;4.2 V under 0.5C rate at room temperature.
Other than the slightly different initial capacity of the LiNiCoMn
cathode for all five separators, as in <xref rid="fig7" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig7" ref-type="fig">7</xref></xref>a, the fading rate also varies for these
separators upon cycling. After 100 cycles, the discharge capacities
of PE, ME-PVDF, Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub>/SiO<sub>2</sub>/PVDF,
Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub>/PVDF, and SiO<sub>2</sub>/PVDF separators
decreased to 120.5, 126.9, 135.6, 133.8, and 130.2 mAh/g, with specific
capacity retention rates of 78.4, 81.3, 84.3, 83.7, and 82.0%, respectively.
These results indicated that the Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub>/SiO<sub>2</sub>/PVDF separator had the best performance in the lithium-ion
battery, which indicated that the affinity of the ceramic nanoparticles
to the electrolyte and the increased &#x003b2; phase of PVDF can improve
the electrochemical performance of separators.</p><p><xref rid="fig7" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig7" ref-type="fig">7</xref></xref>c depicts the rate capability
of LiNiCoMn/separator/Li cells with PE, ME-PVDF, Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub>/SiO<sub>2</sub>/PVDF, Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub>/PVDF, and
SiO<sub>2</sub>/PVDF separators at discharge currents from 0.2C to
8C. With the increase of the current rate, the ceramic nanoparticle-coated
separators exhibited improved capacity retention compared with that
of the PE separator. For instance, at the current density of 8C, the
cell assembled with the PE separator maintained 49.8% capacity relative
to the capacity at 0.2C, whereas the cell containing the Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub>/SiO<sub>2</sub>/PVDF separator maintained 58.4%. The
superior rate performance of the Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub>/SiO<sub>2</sub>/PVDF separator can be attributed to better wetting ability
and higher ion conductivity. In addition, the binder-free, thin-layer
ceramic nanoparticles facilitated efficient ion transport without
affecting the pore structure.</p></sec></sec><sec id="sec3"><label>3</label><title>Conclusions</title><p>In summary, we prepared a ceramic
nanoparticle-coated PVDF fiber membrane for lithium-ion batteries
through melt-electrospinning (ME) and magnetron sputtering deposition
(MSD). Under the synergistic effect of electric field and temperature
of melt-electrospinning, the &#x003b2; phase of PVDF could improve effectively,
thereby improving the ion conductivity. Compared to a commercial PE
separator, the ceramic nanoparticle-coated separator exhibited good
wettability, high ionic conductivity, and excellent thermal stability
at high temperatures. The resulting lithium-ion battery containing
the Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub>/SiO<sub>2</sub>/PVDF composite separator
exhibited high discharge capacity of 161.5 mAh/g and excellent cycling
stability that retained a capacity of 135.6 mAh/g after 100 cycles,
corresponding to 84.3% specific capacity retention rate. It is therefore
concluded that the ceramic nanoparticle-coated ME-PVDF composite membranes
are superior to PE membranes to be used as separators in lithium-ion
batteries.</p></sec><sec id="sec4"><label>4</label><title>Experimental
Section</title><sec id="sec4.1"><label>4.1</label><title>Melt-Electrospinning
and Ceramic Nanoparticle Coating of the PVDF Membrane</title><p>PVDF
with a number-average molecular weight (<italic>M</italic><sub>n</sub>) of 5.5 &#x000d7; 10<sup>4</sup> g/mol and low viscosity (melt flow
index (MFI) of 100 g/10 min at 230 &#x000b0;C) was purchased from Yijia
Plastic Materials Co., Ltd. A homemade melt-electrospinning instrument
(<xref rid="fig8" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig8" ref-type="fig">8</xref></xref>a) was used
to fabricate the PVDF nanofiber membrane. For a typical spinning experiment,
a portion of 2.16 kg of PVDF pellets was loaded into a copper syringe
(&#x003a6; = 24 mm) with a blunt 0.8 mm spinneret. Melt-electrospinning
was conducted at 220 &#x000b0;C to melt the PVDF in the syringe. A voltage
of 20 kV was applied to the spinneret, and the spinning speed was
set to 5 mL/h. A collecting plate covered by a piece of aluminum foil
was used as a collector for fiber deposition.</p><fig id="fig8" position="float"><label>Figure 8</label><caption><p>Schematics
of (a) melt-electrospinning
device and (b) magnetron sputtering deposition setup.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="ao9b01541_0005" id="gr8" position="float"/></fig><p>After electrospinning,
the melt-electrospun PVDF (ME-PVDF) separator was dried at 60 &#x000b0;C
and then sputter-coated with ceramic nanoparticles using a magnetron
sputtering setup (JZCK-420B, Shenyang Jingyi Research Technology Co.
Ltd., China) (<xref rid="fig8" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig8" ref-type="fig">8</xref></xref>b) from both silicon and aluminum targets (99.9% purity, Hefei Crystal
Materials Technology Co., Ltd.). Direct current and radio-frequency
magnetron sputtering deposition techniques were used to deposit Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub> and SiO<sub>2</sub> layers, respectively. The
sputter chamber was first vacuumed to 8.9 &#x000d7; 10<sup>&#x02013;5</sup> Pa before purging with working (Ar) and reactive (O<sub>2</sub>)
gases of 99.99% purity at different proportions (<xref rid="tbl2" ref-type="other">Table <xref rid="tbl2" ref-type="other">2</xref></xref>). Sputter-coating was carried
out under a gas pressure of 0.8 Pa with respective power listed in <xref rid="tbl2" ref-type="other">Table <xref rid="tbl2" ref-type="other">2</xref></xref>, and the coated ME-PVDF
was named as SiO<sub>2</sub>/PVDF and Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub>/PVDF.
For the composite ceramic nanoparticle-coated PVDF membrane (SiO<sub>2</sub>/Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub>/PVDF), the magnetron cosputtering
method with two individual sputtering guns for SiO<sub>2</sub> and
Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub> was employed. The specific sputtering
parameters in <xref rid="tbl2" ref-type="other">Table <xref rid="tbl2" ref-type="other">2</xref></xref> were selected based on the different oxidation properties of the
silicon and aluminum targets. The thickness of the sputter-coated
layer was determined using a quartz crystal microbalance (FTM107-A,
Shanghai Taiyao Co. Ltd., China) as a catcher, and the thickness of
the coated ceramic nanoparticle layers of all three membranes is around
200 nm. Immediately after sputter-coating, the ceramic nanoparticle-coated
ME-PVDF membrane was further pressed using a hot press (Carver 4128,
Carver Company, USA) at 75 &#x000b0;C and 10&#x0202f;000 psi for 10 min
to ensure a flat surface for the lithium-ion battery separator application.</p><table-wrap id="tbl2" position="float"><label>Table 2</label><caption><title>Specific Sputtering Parameters Used
for the Three ME-PVDF Membranes</title></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups" border="0"><colgroup><col align="left"/><col align="char" char=":"/><col align="left"/></colgroup><thead><tr><th style="border:none;" align="center">sample</th><th style="border:none;" align="center" char=":">Ar/O<sub>2</sub></th><th style="border:none;" align="center">power
(W)</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="border:none;" align="left">SiO<sub>2</sub>/PVDF</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=":">4:1</td><td style="border:none;" align="left">45</td></tr><tr><td style="border:none;" align="left">Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub>/PVDF</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=":">10:1</td><td style="border:none;" align="left">24</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="2" style="border:none;" align="left">SiO<sub>2</sub>/Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub>/PVDF</td><td rowspan="2" style="border:none;" align="char" char=":">7:1</td><td style="border:none;" align="left">SiO<sub>2</sub>: 45</td></tr><tr><td style="border:none;" align="left">Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub>: 24</td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap></sec><sec id="sec4.2"><label>4.2</label><title>Characterization of
the Ceramic Nanoparticle-Coated Membrane</title><p>Both melt-electrospun
membranes and pellets were analyzed by Fourier transform infrared
(FTIR) spectroscopy (Nicoletis10, Thermo Fisher Scientific Technology
Co., Ltd., China) in the range of 600&#x02013;4000 cm<sup>&#x02013;1</sup> to verify the PVDF crystalline-phase transformation. The membrane
was sputter-coated with gold and examined by scanning electron microscopy
(SU1510, Hitachi, Japan) at an accelerating voltage of 10 kV for the
microscopic structure and morphology. The presence of inorganic elements
of coated ceramic nanoparticles on the ME-PVDF membrane was investigated
using energy-dispersive spectroscopy (EDS) (Quantax400, Bruker, German).</p><p>All membranes were thermally treated at 130 &#x000b0;C for 0.5 h to
determine their respective areal thermal shrinkage (<italic>A</italic>), which was calculated using the following equation<disp-formula id="eq2"><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="ao9b01541_m002" position="anchor"/><label>2</label></disp-formula>where <italic>S</italic><sub>0</sub> and <italic>S</italic><sub>T</sub> refer to the area of the membrane before and after thermal treatment,
respectively.</p><p>Differential scanning calorimetry (DSC) (TA-Q200,
Waters, China) was used to measure the thermal stability of membranes
from 20 to 200 &#x000b0;C with a heating rate of 10 &#x000b0;C/min under
a nitrogen atmosphere at a flow rate of 20 mL/min. Thermal gravimetric
analysis (TGA Q500, USA Waters Industry) of the membranes was conducted
from 20 to 700 &#x000b0;C under a N<sub>2</sub> atmosphere at a heating
rate of 10 &#x000b0;C/min.</p><p>The porosity of the membrane was calculated
according to the following equation<disp-formula id="eq3"><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="ao9b01541_m003" position="anchor"/><label>3</label></disp-formula>where <italic>M</italic><sub>m</sub> and <italic>M</italic><sub>BuOH</sub> represent the masses of the membrane before
and after absorbing <italic>n</italic>-butanol, respectively, while
&#x003c1;<sub>BuOH</sub> and &#x003c1;<sub>P</sub> represent the densities
of <italic>n</italic>-butanol and PVDF, respectively.</p><p>The electrolyte
wettability of the membranes was examined by the electrolyte spreading
test. About 10 &#x003bc;L of electrolyte (1 M LiPF<sub>6</sub> in ethylene
carbonate, dimethyl carbonate, methyl ethyl carbonate EC/DMC/EMC,
1:1:1, by volume) was dropped onto the membrane in an argon-filled
glovebox, and the electrolyte spreading was captured after 15 s. An
optical contact angle meter (DCAT-21, GER Dataphysica Industry) was
used to quantify the spreadability by taking the droplet contact angle
of liquid electrolyte (with 5 &#x003bc;L of electrolyte) just dripped
onto the membranes at room temperature. The electrolyte uptake was
determined according to the following equation<disp-formula id="eq4"><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="ao9b01541_m004" position="anchor"/><label>4</label></disp-formula>where <italic>W</italic><sub>0</sub> and <italic>W</italic> are the wet weights of the membrane before and after completely
absorbing liquid electrolyte.</p></sec><sec id="sec4.3"><label>4.3</label><title>Electrochemical Performance of the Ceramic Nanoparticle-Coated
Membrane</title><p>The ionic conductivity of membranes was determined
by electrochemical impedance spectroscopy (EIS) using a CHI 660E electrochemical
workstation (CH Instruments, Shanghai, China). The membranes were
saturated with about 30 &#x003bc;L of liquid electrolyte, sandwiched
between two stainless steel plates, and assembled as a coin cell (CR2032).
EIS analysis was performed at a frequency range of 0.1&#x02013;10<sup>6</sup> Hz. The ionic conductivities were calculated by the following
equation<disp-formula id="ueq1"><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="ao9b01541_m005" position="anchor"/><label>5</label></disp-formula>where <italic>L</italic> and <italic>R</italic><sub>b</sub> represent the thickness and bulk resistance
of the membrane, respectively, and <italic>S</italic> is the area
of the stainless steel electrode.</p><p>A lithium symmetric cell was
assembled by sandwiching the electrolyte-saturated membrane between
two lithium electrodes in a coin cell and was used to characterize
the LIB interfacial charge-transfer resistance by EIS at a frequency
range of 0.01&#x02013;10<sup>6</sup> Hz. The electrochemical stability
window of the membranes was measured by linear sweep voltammetry (LSV).
The membrane was sandwiched between a stainless steel working electrode
and a lithium metal counterelectrode. The LSV test was carried out
at a scan rate of 10 mV/s over a voltage range 2.5&#x02013;6.0 V vs
Li<sup>+</sup>/Li.</p><p>The performance of the PVDF membrane as a
lithium-ion battery separator was tested in a coin cell assembly using
metallic Li (Shenzhen Kejing Zhida Technology Co. Ltd., China) as
an anode, an active material composition of 94.2 wt % LiNiCoMnO<sub>2</sub> (Shenzhen kejing Zhida Technology Co. Ltd, China) as a cathode,
and approximately 30 &#x003bc;L of electrolyte solution (1 M LiPF<sub>6</sub> in EC/DMC/EMC, 1:1:1, by volume). Five different membranes
were tested for comparison: separator PE as a control (20 &#x003bc;m
thick) and ME-PVDF, Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub>/SiO<sub>2</sub>/PVDF,
Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub>/PVDF, and SiO<sub>2</sub>/PVDF (the
thickness for all PDVF membranes is 25 &#x003bc;m). The coin cells were
assembled in a glovebox (Mbraun, Germany) filled with argon gas. The
charge and discharge cycling tests on cells were performed at 0.5C
with a battery test equipment (CT-3008W-5V1nA-S4, Shenzhen Neware
Technology Limited, China). Cells were charged to 4.2 V and discharged
to 2.8 V at current rates of 0.5C, 1.0C, 2.0C, 5.0C, 8.0C, and 10.0C
for the measurement of rate capacity.</p></sec></sec></body><back><notes notes-type="COI-statement" id="NOTES-d7e1793-autogenerated"><p>The authors declare no competing financial interest.</p></notes><ack><title>Acknowledgments</title><p>We are grateful to the Jiangsu Key R&#x00026;D Program (BE2017060,
BE2016707), the China Postdoctoral Science Foundation (169483), and
the 111 Project (B17021).</p></ack><ref-list><title>References</title><ref id="ref1"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit1"><name><surname>Tarascon</surname><given-names>J.-M.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Armand</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Issues and challenges
facing rechargeable lithium batteries</article-title>. <source>Mater.
Sustainable Energy</source>
<year>2010</year>, <fpage>171</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>179</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1142/9789814317665_0024</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref2"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit2"><name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>S. S.</given-names></name>
<article-title>A review
on the separators of liquid electrolyte Li-ion batteries</article-title>. <source>J. Power Sources</source>
<year>2007</year>, <volume>164</volume>, <fpage>351</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>364</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.jpowsour.2006.10.065;</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref3"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit3"><name><surname>Fu</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Cheng</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Hu</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Flexible Batteries: From Mechanics to Devices</article-title>. <source>ACS Energy Lett.</source>
<year>2016</year>, <volume>1</volume>, <fpage>1065</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>1079</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/acsenergylett.6b00401</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref4"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit4"><name><surname>Hwang</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Kwon</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Byun</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Preparation
of PVdF nanofiber membranes by electrospinning and their use as secondary
battery separators</article-title>. <source>J. Membr. Sci.</source>
<year>2011</year>, <volume>378</volume>, <fpage>111</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>116</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.memsci.2011.06.005</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref5"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit5"><name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Tang</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Pan</surname><given-names>M.-W.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Zhu</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Zhong</surname><given-names>G.-J.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>Z.-M.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Polymorphic extended-chain and folded-chain crystals in poly (vinylidene
fluoride) achieved by combination of high pressure and ion&#x02013;dipole
interaction</article-title>. <source>Macromolecules</source>
<year>2015</year>, <volume>48</volume>, <fpage>8565</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>8573</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/acs.macromol.5b01895</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref6"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit6"><name><surname>Satyanarayana</surname><given-names>K. C.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Bolton</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Molecular dynamics simulations of &#x003b1;-to &#x003b2;-poly
(vinylidene fluoride) phase change by stretching and poling</article-title>. <source>Polymer</source>
<year>2012</year>, <volume>53</volume>, <fpage>2927</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>2934</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.polymer.2012.04.008</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref7"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit7"><name><surname>Lu</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Hsu</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Study of the crystallization
behavior of poly (vinylidene fluoride) from melt under the effect
of an electric field</article-title>. <source>Macromolecules</source>
<year>1986</year>, <volume>19</volume>, <fpage>326</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>329</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/ma00156a013</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref8"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit8"><name><surname>Pan</surname><given-names>J.-L.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Zhu</surname><given-names>P.-P.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Wei</surname><given-names>J.-C.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Cai</surname><given-names>J.-X.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Yu</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Koratkar</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Yang</surname><given-names>Z.-Y.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Ultrathin
and Strong Electrospun Porous Fiber Separator</article-title>. <source>ACS Appl. Energy Mater.</source>
<year>2018</year>, <volume>1</volume>, <fpage>4794</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>4803</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/acsaem.8b00855</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref9"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit9"><name><surname>Miao</surname><given-names>Y.-E.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Zhu</surname><given-names>G.-N.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Hou</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Xia</surname><given-names>Y.-Y.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Electrospun polyimide nanofiber-based
nonwoven separators for lithium-ion batteries</article-title>. <source>J. Power Sources</source>
<year>2013</year>, <volume>226</volume>, <fpage>82</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>86</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.jpowsour.2012.10.027</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref10"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit10"><name><surname>Kang</surname><given-names>D.-W.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>J.-K.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Characterization
of fibrous gel polymer electrolyte for lithium polymer batteries with
enhanced electrochemical properties</article-title>. <source>J. Electroanal.
Chem.</source>
<year>2016</year>, <volume>775</volume>, <fpage>37</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>42</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.jelechem.2016.05.029</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref11"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit11"><name><surname>Subbiah</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Bhat</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Tock</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Parameswaran</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Ramkumar</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Electrospinning of nanofibers</article-title>. <source>J. Appl. Polym. Sci.</source>
<year>2005</year>, <volume>96</volume>, <fpage>557</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>569</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/app.21481</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref12"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit12"><name><surname>Lyons</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Ko</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Melt-electrospinning
part I: processing parameters and geometric properties</article-title>. <source>Polymer</source>
<year>2004</year>, <volume>45</volume>, <fpage>7597</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>7603</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.polymer.2004.08.071</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref13"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit13"><name><surname>Hutmacher</surname><given-names>D. W.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Dalton</surname><given-names>P. D.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Melt electrospinning</article-title>. <source>Chem. - Asian J.</source>
<year>2011</year>, <volume>6</volume>, <fpage>44</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>56</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/asia.201000436</pub-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21080400</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref14"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit14"><name><surname>Fu</surname><given-names>Q.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Lin</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Yu</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Yang</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Zeng</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Mechanically
Reinforced PVdF/PMMA/SiO2 Composite Membrane and Its Electrochemical
Properties as a Separator in Lithium-Ion Batteries</article-title>. <source>Energy Technol.</source>
<year>2018</year>, <volume>6</volume>, <fpage>144</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>152</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/ente.201700347</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref15"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit15"><name><surname>Nho</surname><given-names>Y.-C.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Sohn</surname><given-names>J.-Y.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Shin</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Park</surname><given-names>J.-S.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Lim</surname><given-names>Y.-M.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Kang</surname><given-names>P.-H.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Preparation of nanocomposite
&#x003b3;-Al2O3/polyethylene separator crosslinked by electron beam
irradiation for lithium secondary battery</article-title>. <source>Radiat.
Phys. Chem.</source>
<year>2017</year>, <volume>132</volume>, <fpage>65</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>70</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.radphyschem.2016.12.002</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref16"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit16"><name><surname>Xue</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Fu</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Shi</surname><given-names>Q.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Carbon-Coated Si Nanoparticles
Dispersed in Carbon Nanotube Networks As Anode Material for Lithium-Ion
Batteries</article-title>. <source>ACS Appl. Mater. Interfaces</source>
<year>2013</year>, <volume>5</volume>, <fpage>21</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>25</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/am3027597</pub-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">23206443</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref17"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit17"><name><surname>Yang</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Tong</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Luo</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Yuan</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Yang</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Boehmite particle coating modified microporous polyethylene membrane:
a promising separator for lithium ion batteries</article-title>. <source>J. Power Sources</source>
<year>2017</year>, <volume>348</volume>, <fpage>80</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>86</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.jpowsour.2017.02.078</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref18"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit18"><name><surname>Zhu</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Jiang</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Ai</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Yang</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Cao</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name>
<article-title>TiO2 ceramic-grafted polyethylene
separators for enhanced thermostability and electrochemical performance
of lithium-ion batteries</article-title>. <source>J. Membr. Sci.</source>
<year>2016</year>, <volume>504</volume>, <fpage>97</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>103</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.memsci.2015.12.059</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref19"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit19"><name><surname>Luo</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Liao</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Zhu</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Huang</surname><given-names>Q.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Investigation of nano-CeO2 contents
on the properties of polymer ceramic separator for high voltage lithium
ion batteries</article-title>. <source>J. Power Sources</source>
<year>2017</year>, <volume>348</volume>, <fpage>229</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>238</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.jpowsour.2017.02.085</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref20"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit20"><name><surname>Song</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Ryou</surname><given-names>M.-H.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Son</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>J.-N.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>D. J.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>Y. M.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Choi</surname><given-names>J. W.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Park</surname><given-names>J.-K.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Co-polyimide-coated
polyethylene separators for enhanced thermal stability of lithium
ion batteries</article-title>. <source>Electrochim. Acta</source>
<year>2012</year>, <volume>85</volume>, <fpage>524</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>530</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.electacta.2012.06.078</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref21"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit21"><name><surname>Liang</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Yang</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Jin</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Cheng</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Polyethylene oxide-coated
electrospun polyimide fibrous seperator for high-performance lithium-ion
battery</article-title>. <source>J. Mater. Sci. Technol.</source>
<year>2016</year>, <volume>32</volume>, <fpage>200</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>206</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.jmst.2015.11.006</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref22"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit22"><name><surname>Bicy</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Suriyakumar</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Anu</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Kalarikkal</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Stephen</surname><given-names>A. M.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Geethamma</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Rouxel</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Thomas</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name>; et al. <article-title>Highly lithium ion conductive, Al2O3 decorated electrospun P (VDF-TrFE)
membranes for lithium ion battery separators</article-title>. <source>New J. Chem.</source>
<year>2018</year>, <volume>42</volume>, <fpage>19505</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>19520</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1039/C8NJ01907J</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref23"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit23"><name><surname>Jeong</surname><given-names>H.-S.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Hong</surname><given-names>S. C.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>S.-Y.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Effect
of microporous structure on thermal shrinkage and electrochemical
performance of Al2O3/poly (vinylidene fluoride-hexafluoropropylene)
composite separators for lithium-ion batteries</article-title>. <source>J. Membr. Sci.</source>
<year>2010</year>, <volume>364</volume>, <fpage>177</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>182</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.memsci.2010.08.012</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref24"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit24"><name><surname>Shin</surname><given-names>W.-K.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>D.-W.</given-names></name>
<article-title>High performance
ceramic-coated separators prepared with lithium ion-containing SiO2
particles for lithium-ion batteries</article-title>. <source>J. Power
Sources</source>
<year>2013</year>, <volume>226</volume>, <fpage>54</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>60</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.jpowsour.2012.10.082</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref25"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit25"><name><surname>Zuo</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Keil</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Grundmeier</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Synthesis and characterization of
photochromic Ag-embedded TiO2 nanocomposite thin films by non-reactive
RF-magnetron sputter deposition</article-title>. <source>Appl. Surf.
Sci.</source>
<year>2012</year>, <volume>258</volume>, <fpage>7231</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>7237</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.apsusc.2012.04.054</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref26"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit26"><name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Qiu</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Tan</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Lin</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Zeng</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Moore</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Jiang</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Effect of
Al content on structure and properties of TiAlCN coatings prepared
by magnetron sputtering</article-title>. <source>J. Alloys Compd.</source>
<year>2014</year>, <volume>617</volume>, <fpage>81</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>85</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.jallcom.2014.08.009</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref27"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit27"><name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Feng</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Shi</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Lu</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Xiao</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Wu</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Huang</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Qu</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Han</surname><given-names>Z. H.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Surface morphology evolution of CeO2/YSZ (001) buffer
layers fabricated via magnetron sputtering</article-title>. <source>Appl. Surf. Sci.</source>
<year>2013</year>, <volume>284</volume>, <fpage>150</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>154</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.apsusc.2013.07.072</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref28"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit28"><name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Meng</surname><given-names>Q.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Influence of crystalline properties on the dielectric and energy
storage properties of poly (vinylidene fluoride)</article-title>. <source>J. Appl. Polym. Sci.</source>
<year>2011</year>, <volume>122</volume>, <fpage>1659</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>1668</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/app.34020</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref29"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit29"><name><surname>Janakiraman</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Surendran</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Ghosh</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Anandhan</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Venimadhav</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name>
<article-title>A new strategy
of PVDF based Li-salt polymer electrolyte through electrospinning
for lithium battery application</article-title>. <source>Mater. Res.
Express</source>
<year>2019</year>, <volume>6</volume>, <elocation-id>035303</elocation-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1088/2053-1591/aaf369</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref30"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit30"><name><surname>Sajkiewicz</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Wasiak</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Goc&#x00142;owski</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Phase transitions
during stretching of poly (vinylidene fluoride)</article-title>. <source>Eur. Polym. J.</source>
<year>1999</year>, <volume>35</volume>, <fpage>423</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>429</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/S0014-3057(98)00136-0</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref31"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit31"><name><surname>Kundu</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Costa</surname><given-names>C. M.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Dias</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Maceiras</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Vilas</surname><given-names>J. L.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Lanceros-Me&#x02032;ndez</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name>
<article-title>On the relevance
of the polar &#x003b2;-phase of poly (vinylidene fluoride) for high
performance lithium-ion battery separators</article-title>. <source>J. Phys. Chem. C</source>
<year>2017</year>, <volume>121</volume>, <fpage>26216</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>26225</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/acs.jpcc.7b09227</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref32"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit32"><name><surname>Baginska</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Blaiszik</surname><given-names>B. J.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Merriman</surname><given-names>R. J.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Sottos</surname><given-names>N. R.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Moore</surname><given-names>J. S.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>White</surname><given-names>S. R.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Autonomic shutdown
of lithium-ion batteries using thermoresponsive microspheres</article-title>. <source>Adv. Energy Mater.</source>
<year>2012</year>, <volume>2</volume>, <fpage>583</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>590</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/aenm.201100683</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref33"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit33"><name><surname>Campos</surname><given-names>J. S. C.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Ribeiro</surname><given-names>A. A.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Cardoso</surname><given-names>C. X.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Preparation
and characterization of PVDF/CaCO3 composites</article-title>. <source>Mater. Sci. Eng., B</source>
<year>2007</year>, <volume>136</volume>, <fpage>123</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>128</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.mseb.2006.09.017</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref34"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit34"><name><surname>Bhute</surname><given-names>M. V.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Kondawar</surname><given-names>S. B.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Electrospun poly (vinylidene fluoride)/cellulose acetate/AgTiO2
nanofibers polymer electrolyte membrane for lithium ion battery</article-title>. <source>Solid State Ionics</source>
<year>2019</year>, <volume>333</volume>, <fpage>38</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>44</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.ssi.2019.01.019</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref35"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit35"><name><surname>Han</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Gong</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Fu</surname><given-names>K. K.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>He</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Hitz</surname><given-names>G. T.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Dai</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Pearse</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Rubloff</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></name>; et al. <article-title>Negating interfacial
impedance in garnet-based solid-state Li metal batteries</article-title>. <source>Nat. Mater.</source>
<year>2017</year>, <volume>16</volume>, <fpage>572</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>579</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1038/nmat4821</pub-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">27992420</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref></ref-list></back></article>