<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD JATS (Z39.96) Journal Archiving and Interchange DTD with MathML3 v1.2 20190208//EN" "JATS-archivearticle1-mathml3.dtd"> 
<article xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" article-type="data-paper"><?DTDIdentifier.IdentifierValue -//ES//DTD journal article DTD version 5.6.0//EN//XML?><?DTDIdentifier.IdentifierType public?><?SourceDTD.DTDName art560.dtd?><?SourceDTD.Version 5.6.0?><?ConverterInfo.XSLTName elsevier2nlmx2.xsl?><?ConverterInfo.Version 1?><?origin publisher?><?FILEmeta_DIB104379 xml ?><?FILEmain xml ?><?FILEmain pdf ?><?FILEgr1 jpg ?><?FILEgr2 jpg ?><?FILEgr3 jpg ?><?FILEgr4 jpg ?><?FILEgr5 jpg ?><?FILEgr6 jpg ?><?FILEgr7 jpg ?><?FILEmmc1 jpg ?><?FILEmmc1 mp4 ?><?properties open_access?><front><journal-meta><journal-id journal-id-type="nlm-ta">Data Brief</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="iso-abbrev">Data Brief</journal-id><journal-title-group><journal-title>Data in Brief</journal-title></journal-title-group><issn pub-type="epub">2352-3409</issn><publisher><publisher-name>Elsevier</publisher-name></publisher></journal-meta><article-meta><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid">6742859</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">S2352-3409(19)30733-4</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.dib.2019.104379</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">104379</article-id><article-categories><subj-group subj-group-type="heading"><subject>Engineering</subject></subj-group></article-categories><title-group><article-title>Data and video for the thermal and fire propagation of multiple lithium-ion batteries</article-title></title-group><contrib-group><contrib contrib-type="author" id="au1"><name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>Mingyi</given-names></name><email>chenmy@ujs.edu.cn</email><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff">a</xref><xref rid="aff2" ref-type="aff">b</xref><xref rid="cor1" ref-type="corresp">&#x02217;</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author" id="au2"><name><surname>Ouyang</surname><given-names>Dongxu</given-names></name><xref rid="aff3" ref-type="aff">c</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author" id="au3"><name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>Jiahao</given-names></name><xref rid="aff4" ref-type="aff">d</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author" id="au4"><name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>Jian</given-names></name><xref rid="aff3" ref-type="aff">c</xref></contrib></contrib-group><aff id="aff1"><label>a</label>School of the Environment and Safety Engineering, Jiangsu University, Zhenjiang, 212013, Jiangsu, China</aff><aff id="aff2"><label>b</label>Firefighting and Rescue Technology Key Laboratory of the Ministry of Public Security, China People's Police University, Langfang, 065000, Hebei, China</aff><aff id="aff3"><label>c</label>State Key Laboratory of Fire Science, University of Science and Technology of China, Hefei, 230026, Anhui, China</aff><aff id="aff4"><label>d</label>College of Ocean Science and Engineering, Shanghai Maritime University, Shanghai, 201306, China</aff><author-notes><corresp id="cor1"><label>&#x02217;</label>Corresponding author. School of the Environment and Safety Engineering, Jiangsu University, Zhenjiang, 212013, Jiangsu, China. <email>chenmy@ujs.edu.cn</email></corresp></author-notes><pub-date pub-type="pmc-release"><day>28</day><month>8</month><year>2019</year></pub-date><!-- PMC Release delay is 0 months and 0 days and was based on <pub-date
						pub-type="epub">.--><pub-date pub-type="collection"><month>10</month><year>2019</year></pub-date><pub-date pub-type="epub"><day>28</day><month>8</month><year>2019</year></pub-date><volume>26</volume><elocation-id>104379</elocation-id><history><date date-type="received"><day>20</day><month>5</month><year>2019</year></date><date date-type="rev-recd"><day>2</day><month>8</month><year>2019</year></date><date date-type="accepted"><day>2</day><month>8</month><year>2019</year></date></history><permissions><copyright-statement>&#x000a9; 2019 The Author(s)</copyright-statement><copyright-year>2019</copyright-year><license license-type="CC BY" xlink:href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/"><license-p>This is an open access article under the CC BY license (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/).</license-p></license></permissions><related-article related-article-type="article-reference" id="d31e14" ext-link-type="doi" xlink:href="10.1016/j.applthermaleng.2019.113750"/><abstract id="abs0010"><p>The data presented in this article are related to research article &#x0201c;Investigation on thermal and fire propagation behaviors of multiple lithium-ion batteries within the package&#x0201d; (Chen et&#x000a0;al., 2019). This data article provides the data information including the experiment pictures, flame temperatures, pressure and heat flux sensors temperatures, and gas concentrations of 6&#x000a0;&#x000d7;&#x000a0;6 batteries and 10&#x000a0;&#x000d7;&#x000a0;10 batteries. The video of the whole thermal and fire propagation behaviors of 6&#x000a0;&#x000d7;&#x000a0;6 batteries is also provided.</p></abstract><kwd-group id="kwrds0010"><title>Keywords</title><kwd>Lithium-ion battery</kwd><kwd>Pack</kwd><kwd>Thermal behavior</kwd><kwd>Fire propagation</kwd></kwd-group></article-meta></front><body><p id="p0010"><table-wrap position="float" id="undtbl1"><caption><p>Specifications Table</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><tbody><tr><td>Subject</td><td>Engineering</td></tr><tr><td>Specific subject area</td><td>Safety engineering</td></tr><tr><td>Type of data</td><td>Image<break/>Graph<break/>Figure<break/>Video</td></tr><tr><td>How data were acquired</td><td>Camera, Thermocouples,<break/>Servomex 4100 gas analyser,</td></tr><tr><td>Data format</td><td>Raw</td></tr><tr><td>Parameters for data collection</td><td>The collection of temperature and gas concentration data is mainly in the case of thermal runaway and fire in the battery pack.</td></tr><tr><td>Description of data collection</td><td>Temperature data is collected by thermocouples. Gas concentration data was collected by Servomex 4100 gas analyser. Video and image data is recorded by the camera.</td></tr><tr><td>Data source location</td><td>University of Science and Technology of China, Hefei, China</td></tr><tr><td>Data accessibility</td><td>With the article</td></tr><tr><td>Related research article</td><td>Mingyi Chen, Ouyang Dongxu, Jiahao Liu, Jian Wang, Investigation on thermal and fire propagation behaviors of multiple lithium-ion batteries within the package, Applied Thermal Engineering<break/>DOI<break/>10.1016/j.applthermaleng.2019.113750</td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap><table-wrap position="float" id="undtbl2"><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><tbody><tr><td><bold>Value of the data</bold><list list-type="simple" id="olist0010"><list-item id="u0010"><label>&#x02022;</label><p id="p0015">The experiment pictures can be a reference for the further lithium-ion battery fire studies.</p></list-item><list-item id="u0015"><label>&#x02022;</label><p id="p0020">The video presented clearly demonstrate the fire propagation behaviors of multiple lithium-ion batteries.</p></list-item><list-item id="u0020"><label>&#x02022;</label><p id="p0025">Lithium-ion battery fire can be more intuitively understanding form the flame temperatures.</p></list-item></list></td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap></p><sec id="sec1"><label>1</label><title>Data</title><p id="p0030">The dataset in this article describes the thermal and fire propagation process of multiple lithium-ion batteries with varying pack scale. <xref rid="fig1" ref-type="fig">Fig.&#x000a0;1</xref> presents the constructions of the battery pack for 6&#x000a0;&#x000d7;&#x000a0;6 batteries and 10&#x000a0;&#x000d7;&#x000a0;10 batteries. <xref rid="fig2" ref-type="fig">Fig.&#x000a0;2</xref> shows the position of the heater in the pack. <xref rid="fig3" ref-type="fig">Fig.&#x000a0;3</xref> presents the batteries which are completely burned. Video 1 shows the whole thermal and fire propagation process for 6&#x000a0;&#x000d7;&#x000a0;6 batteries. <xref rid="fig4" ref-type="fig">Fig.&#x000a0;4</xref> shows the flame temperatures changes. <xref rid="fig5" ref-type="fig">Fig.&#x000a0;5</xref> shows the pressure and heat flux sensors temperatures. <xref rid="fig6" ref-type="fig">Fig.&#x000a0;6</xref> shows oxygen, carbon dioxide, and carbon monoxide concentration changes.<fig id="fig1"><label>Fig.&#x000a0;1</label><caption><p><bold>Structure of the batteries inside the cardboard box</bold>. The batteries are SAMSUNG 18650 type LiCoO<sub>2</sub> cells which are charged to 80% SOC (commonly used state for storage and transportation). The batteries were packed in a cardboard box supplied by the manufacturer, and each cell was separated by crossed hard papers.</p></caption><alt-text id="alttext0015">Fig.&#x000a0;1</alt-text><graphic xlink:href="gr1"/></fig><fig id="fig2"><label>Fig.&#x000a0;2</label><caption><p><bold>Position of the heater in the pack</bold>. The red circle here simply represents the heating rod. The middle of the cardboard box was hollowed out, and a 500 W heating rod with similar dimensions of the battery was used to achieve the purpose of thermal propagation.</p></caption><alt-text id="alttext0020">Fig.&#x000a0;2</alt-text><graphic xlink:href="gr2"/></fig><fig id="fig3"><label>Fig.&#x000a0;3</label><caption><p><bold>Burned batteries after the fire tests</bold>. At the end of the combustion experiment, the shape of the burning residue of the battery pack was photographed with a camera. The shooting angle is directly above the battery pack. The state of each battery in the battery pack is original after the end of the experiment, and there is no manual disturbance.</p></caption><alt-text id="alttext0025">Fig.&#x000a0;3</alt-text><graphic xlink:href="gr3"/></fig><fig id="fig4"><label>Fig.&#x000a0;4</label><caption><p><bold>Flame temperatures</bold>. Flame temperatures of (a) 6&#x000a0;&#x000d7;&#x000a0;6 batteries and (b) 10&#x000a0;&#x000d7;&#x000a0;10 batteries during the thermal and fire propagation. The abscissa is time and the ordinate is temperature change. Since the combustion development period is relatively concentrated, the abscissa has only taken 600&#x02013;1300 seconds.</p></caption><alt-text id="alttext0030">Fig.&#x000a0;4</alt-text><graphic xlink:href="gr4"/></fig><fig id="fig5"><label>Fig.&#x000a0;5</label><caption><p><bold>Pressure and heat flux sensors temperatures</bold>. Pressure and heat flux sensors temperatures of (a) 6&#x000a0;&#x000d7;&#x000a0;6 batteries and (b) 10&#x000a0;&#x000d7;&#x000a0;10 batteries during the thermal and fire propagation. B stands for the rear side position and R stands for the right side position. 30 and 40 represent the distance of the sensor from the center of the battery pack.</p></caption><alt-text id="alttext0035">Fig.&#x000a0;5</alt-text><graphic xlink:href="gr5"/></fig><fig id="fig6"><label>Fig.&#x000a0;6</label><caption><p><bold>O</bold><sub><bold>2</bold></sub><bold>, CO</bold><sub><bold>2</bold></sub><bold>, and CO concentration changes</bold>. Oxygen, carbon dioxide, and carbon monoxide concentration changes of (a) 6&#x000a0;&#x000d7;&#x000a0;6 batteries and (b) 10&#x000a0;&#x000d7;&#x000a0;10 batteries during the thermal and fire propagation. The black ordinate is the axis of oxygen concentration change. The red ordinate is the axis of carbon dioxide concentration change. The blue ordinate is the axis of carbon monoxide concentration change. The gas concentration unit is the volume fraction in air and expressed as percentage.</p></caption><alt-text id="alttext0040">Fig.&#x000a0;6</alt-text><graphic xlink:href="gr6"/></fig></p><p>Supplementary video related to this article can be found at <ext-link ext-link-type="doi" xlink:href="10.1016/j.dib.2019.104379" id="intref0010">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.dib.2019.104379</ext-link></p><p id="p0040">The following is the supplementary data related to this article:<supplementary-material content-type="local-data" id="mmc1"><caption><title>Video 1</title><p>1</p></caption><media xlink:href="mmc1.mp4"><alt-text>Video 1</alt-text></media></supplementary-material></p></sec><sec id="sec2"><label>2</label><title>Experimental design, materials, and methods</title><p id="p0045">Experiments were carried out to study the thermal changes and fire behaviors during the thermal and fire propagation process of multiple lithium-ion batteries as detailed in Ref <xref rid="bib1" ref-type="bibr">[1]</xref>. This article provides the data for a better understanding of the fire behaviors and the pictures and video are mainly obtained by means of camera recording.</p><p id="p0050">Flame temperature is an important parameter for analyzing fire hazards. A plurality of thermocouples are placed above the battery pack to measure the flame temperatures of multiple lithium-ion batteries fire. The thermocouples are arranged as shown in <xref rid="fig7" ref-type="fig">Fig.&#x000a0;7</xref>. The thermocouples were placed every 10 cm above the center of the battery pack, and a total of six thermocouples were set. To measure the flame temperatures of the lithium-ion battery fire, the same thermocouples as in Ref <xref rid="bib1" ref-type="bibr">[1]</xref> were used. The thermocouples are K-type with 1 mm diameter, 1400 K measurement range, and 0.5 K precision. National Instruments (NI) data acquisition instruments are used to record temperature data transmitted by thermocouples.<fig id="fig7"><label>Fig.&#x000a0;7</label><caption><p>Experiment setup for flame temperatures measurement.</p></caption><alt-text id="alttext0045">Fig.&#x000a0;7</alt-text><graphic xlink:href="gr7"/></fig></p><p id="p0055">The ambient temperature at which the pressure and heat flux sensors probes are located is an important parameter for examining their operating conditions. The positions of the pressure and heat flux sensors probes are specifically described in Ref <xref rid="bib1" ref-type="bibr">[1]</xref>.</p><p id="p0060">Three simultaneous gas stream measurements of oxygen, carbon dioxide, and carbon monoxide are analyzed in the Servomex 4100 gas analyzer.</p></sec></body><back><ref-list id="cebib0010"><title>References</title><ref id="bib1"><label>1</label><element-citation publication-type="journal" id="sref1"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Chen</surname></name></person-group><article-title>Investigation on thermal and fire propagation behaviors of multiple lithium-ion batteries within the package</article-title><source>Appl. Therm. Eng.</source><volume>159</volume><year>2019</year><comment>113750</comment><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.applthermaleng.2019.113750</pub-id></element-citation></ref></ref-list><sec id="appsec1"><title>Conflict of interest</title><p id="p0095w">The authors declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper.</p></sec><ack id="ack0010"><title>Acknowledgments</title><p>This research was supported by the <funding-source id="gs1">National Key Research and Development Program of China</funding-source> (2018YFC0808600), the opening fund of Key Laboratory of Firefighting and Rescue Technology, <funding-source id="gs2">Ministry of Public Security</funding-source> (KF201801), Programs of <funding-source id="gs3">Senior Talent Foundation of Jiangsu University</funding-source> (17JDG036), and the <funding-source id="gs4">Shanghai Sailing Program</funding-source> (18YF1409600).</p></ack></back></article>