<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD JATS (Z39.96) Journal Archiving and Interchange DTD v1.2 20190208//EN" "JATS-archivearticle1.dtd"> 
<article xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" article-type="research-article"><?properties open_access?><?DTDIdentifier.IdentifierValue -//Springer-Verlag//DTD A++ V2.4//EN?><?DTDIdentifier.IdentifierType public?><?SourceDTD.DTDName A++V2.4.dtd?><?SourceDTD.Version 2.4?><?ConverterInfo.XSLTName springer2nlmx2.xsl?><?ConverterInfo.Version 1?><front><journal-meta><journal-id journal-id-type="nlm-ta">Sci Rep</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="iso-abbrev">Sci Rep</journal-id><journal-title-group><journal-title>Scientific Reports</journal-title></journal-title-group><issn pub-type="epub">2045-2322</issn><publisher><publisher-name>Nature Publishing Group UK</publisher-name><publisher-loc>London</publisher-loc></publisher></journal-meta><article-meta><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid">6746694</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">50011</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1038/s41598-019-50011-8</article-id><article-categories><subj-group subj-group-type="heading"><subject>Article</subject></subj-group></article-categories><title-group><article-title>Possibility of Recycling SiO<sub>x</sub> Particles Collected at Silicon Ingot Production Process as an Anode Material for Lithium Ion Batteries</article-title></title-group><contrib-group><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>Junghyun</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff1">1</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>So Yeun</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff2">2</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Yang</surname><given-names>Cheol-Min</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff2">2</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author" corresp="yes"><name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>Gyo Woo</given-names></name><address><email>gwlee@jbnu.ac.kr</email></address><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff1">1</xref></contrib><aff id="Aff1"><label>1</label><institution-wrap><institution-id institution-id-type="ISNI">0000 0004 0470 4320</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="GRID">grid.411545.0</institution-id><institution>Division of Mechanical Design Engineering, </institution><institution>Chonbuk National University, </institution></institution-wrap>Jeonju, 54896 Republic of Korea </aff><aff id="Aff2"><label>2</label><institution-wrap><institution-id institution-id-type="ISNI">0000000121053345</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="GRID">grid.35541.36</institution-id><institution>Institute of Advanced Composite Materials, </institution><institution>Korea Institute of Science and Technology (KIST), </institution></institution-wrap>Wanju, Jeollabuk-do 55324 Republic of Korea </aff></contrib-group><pub-date pub-type="epub"><day>16</day><month>9</month><year>2019</year></pub-date><pub-date pub-type="pmc-release"><day>16</day><month>9</month><year>2019</year></pub-date><pub-date pub-type="collection"><year>2019</year></pub-date><volume>9</volume><elocation-id>13313</elocation-id><history><date date-type="received"><day>28</day><month>5</month><year>2019</year></date><date date-type="accepted"><day>4</day><month>9</month><year>2019</year></date></history><permissions><copyright-statement>&#x000a9; The Author(s) 2019</copyright-statement><license license-type="OpenAccess"><license-p><bold>Open Access</bold> This article is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International License, which permits use, sharing, adaptation, distribution and reproduction in any medium or format, as long as you give appropriate credit to the original author(s) and the source, provide a link to the Creative Commons license, and indicate if changes were made. The images or other third party material in this article are included in the article&#x02019;s Creative Commons license, unless indicated otherwise in a credit line to the material. If material is not included in the article&#x02019;s Creative Commons license and your intended use is not permitted by statutory regulation or exceeds the permitted use, you will need to obtain permission directly from the copyright holder. To view a copy of this license, visit <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</ext-link>.</license-p></license></permissions><abstract id="Abs1"><p id="Par1">Recently, some studies have utilized silicon (Si) as an anode material of lithium ion battery by recycling Si from the slurry of wafer slicing dust. The filtration of Si particles condensed from Si vapors that were exhausted from the ingot growing furnace could propose another method of Si recycling. In this study, we investigated the possibility of using such collected silicon oxides (SiO<sub>x</sub>) particles as an anode material. After collecting SiO<sub>x</sub> particles, FE-SEM, TEM, EDS, XRD, XPS analysis, and charge/discharge test were carried out to investigate characteristics and usability of these particles. FE-SEM and FE-TEM images showed that these particles mainly consisted of spherical primary particles with a diameter of 10&#x02009;nm or less. Agglomerates of these primary particles were larger than 300&#x02009;nm in diameter. In TEM image and EDS analysis, crystalline particles were observed along with amorphous particles. As a result of XRD analysis, amorphous silica (SiO<sub>2</sub>) and crystalline Si were observed. Charge/discharge tests were carried out to determine the feasibility of using these particles as an anode material for lithium ion batteries. A cycle efficiency of 40.6% was obtained in the test in which the total number of charge/discharge cycle was 100 under the condition of C-rate 0.2 for the first three times and C-rate 1.0 for the remaining 97 times. Results showed that these collected particles could be used as an anode material for lithium ion batteries.</p></abstract><kwd-group kwd-group-type="npg-subject"><title>Subject terms</title><kwd>Electronic devices</kwd><kwd>Batteries</kwd></kwd-group><funding-group><award-group><funding-source><institution>Korea Small and Medium Business Administration (Grant No. 0504805)</institution></funding-source></award-group></funding-group><custom-meta-group><custom-meta><meta-name>issue-copyright-statement</meta-name><meta-value>&#x000a9; The Author(s) 2019</meta-value></custom-meta></custom-meta-group></article-meta></front><body><sec id="Sec1" sec-type="introduction"><title>Introduction</title><p id="Par2">Silicon (Si) has been widely used to fabricate semiconductors for electronic devices. It is utilized in the shape of a wafer made by melting raw polysilicon, growing in the form of a single crystal ingot, and then cutting the ingot thinly according to the purpose of use. The importance of renewable energy has been emphasized to reduce the consumption of fossil fuel. Si has also been used as a raw material for photovoltaic solar cells to utilize solar energy. With increasing need for solar cells due to the growth of photovoltaic cell market, demand for Si to produce wafer is steadily increasing<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR1">1</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR2">2</xref></sup>.</p><p id="Par3">However, a large amount of Si loss occurs in the slicing process using wire saws when a thin wafer is cut out from the cylindrical Si ingot. This kerf loss might increase the production cost of Si wafers. The resulting Si sludge adversely affects the environment, resulting in additional costs for the sludge treatment. In general, Si sludge from single-crystal ingot is consisted of kerf-loss crystalline Si and some impurities like lubricant oil and metal debris from the wire saw. When the sludge is recycled the impurities need to be removed through complex and expensive procedures<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR3">3</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR4">4</xref></sup>. To reduce such loss of Si, several studies have tried to recycle Si from the sludge<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR3">3</xref>&#x02013;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR9">9</xref></sup>. Wang <italic>et al</italic>.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR5">5</xref></sup> have recycled Si sludge to fabricate solar cells, and analyzed the performance of these cells. They reported that solar cells made from recycled Si could achieve a performance less than 2% compared to commercial solar cells, making it possible to use the recycled Si. Tsai<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR6">6</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR7">7</xref></sup> has separated Si from impurities using electric force and particle weight. Tomono <italic>et al</italic>.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR8">8</xref></sup> have also studied the recycling of the produced sludge from a slicing process using diamond wires. Removal efficiencies of lubricant and metal impurities using acetone and acid solutions, respectively, were examined by thermal and elemental analyses. Sergiienko <italic>et al</italic>.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR9">9</xref></sup> have reported that Si sludge can be separated into Si and silicon carbide (SiC) by centrifugation and cyclone.</p><p id="Par4">Various methods of secondary batteries have been explored in many researches throughout the years. Xie <italic>et al</italic>.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR10">10</xref></sup> reviewed the recent progress of Li-ion storage performances of various rhenium disulfide (ReS<sub>2</sub>) electrodes, mainly focusing on the synthesis method, structures, the reaction mechanism, and the corresponding electrochemical performance. In 2018, Liao <italic>et al</italic>.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR11">11</xref></sup> reported that the morphology, size and phase of the material (nano-sized niobium pentoxide) play a crucial role in its electrochemical performance, and discussed that the material has the great potential as a practical high-rate anode material for lithium-ion batteries. In the recent review paper, Wang <italic>et al</italic>.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR12">12</xref></sup> summarized the synthesis strategies, common characterization techniques, and their important role in electrochemical lithium/sodium ions storage and capacitance properties of oxygen-defective metal oxides.</p><p id="Par5">In this study, we investigated the possibility of recycling the silicon oxides (SiO<sub>x</sub>) particles mixed with crystalline Si collected from Si vapors in the ingot growing process. It is expected that the coexistence of Si crystal and amorphous silica (SiO<sub>2</sub>) particles could be helpful to achieve good electrochemical performances as an anode material for lithium ion batteries. Additionally, the proposed approach is based on a facile, green, and cost-effective process.</p></sec><sec id="Sec2" sec-type="results"><title>Results and Discussion</title><sec id="Sec3"><title>Particle characteristics</title><p id="Par6">FE-SEM and EDS mapping images of the particles are shown in Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig1" ref-type="fig">1</xref>, including FE-SEM image of particles (Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig1" ref-type="fig">1a</xref>), Si element mapping (Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig1" ref-type="fig">1b</xref>), and O element mapping picture (Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig1" ref-type="fig">1c</xref>). Figure&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig1" ref-type="fig">1a</xref> has a scale bar of 20 &#x003bc;m and a particle size at the center is larger than 30 &#x003bc;m. Also, lots of nanometer scaled particles are seen around the large particles. FE-SEM image shows that these particles are a mixture of &#x003bc;m size particles and agglomerates of nm particles. EDS mapping photos in Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig1" ref-type="fig">1b</xref> and Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig1" ref-type="fig">1c</xref> show that regions of Si and O can be clearly distinguished. These mapping photos suggest that the particle larger than 30 &#x003bc;m in size in Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig1" ref-type="fig">1a</xref> might be Si crystal rather than SiO<sub>x</sub>.<fig id="Fig1"><label>Figure 1</label><caption><p>(<bold>a</bold>) FE-SEM image of the collected SiO<sub>x</sub> particles, (<bold>b</bold>,<bold>c</bold>) EDS mappings of the collected SiO<sub>x</sub> particles.</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="41598_2019_50011_Fig1_HTML" id="d29e381"/></fig></p><p id="Par7">The averages and standard deviations of weight and atomic fractions for Si and O elements of the samples from the EDS analyses are as follows: 53.8&#x02009;wt% (std. dev.&#x02009;=&#x02009;8.5&#x02009;wt%) and 40.3 at% (std. dev.&#x02009;=&#x02009;8.7 at%) for Si and 46.2&#x02009;wt% (std. dev.&#x02009;=&#x02009;8.5&#x02009;wt%) and 59.7 at% (std. dev.&#x02009;=&#x02009;8.7 at%) for O element, respectively.</p><p id="Par8">To investigate the composition of particles, XPS spectrum was obtained as shown in Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig2" ref-type="fig">2</xref>. In the XPS spectrum, Si and O elements were identified as in EDS analysis. In addition to these two elements, a small amount of C element was detected. It was originated from the graphitic heater in the ingot grower. Based on the results of EDS and XPS analyses we believed that the collected particles are mainly consisted of silicon oxides (SiO<sub>x</sub>) and crystalline silicon (Si).<fig id="Fig2"><label>Figure 2</label><caption><p>XPS spectra of SiO<sub>x</sub> particles showing O, Si, and C elements.</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="41598_2019_50011_Fig2_HTML" id="d29e403"/></fig></p><p id="Par9">Figure&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig3" ref-type="fig">3</xref> is TEM images of collected Si particles with crystalline structures. The scale bar is 100&#x02009;nm in Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig3" ref-type="fig">3a</xref> and 5 nm in Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig3" ref-type="fig">3b</xref>. Agglomerates or aggregates of nanometer particles were approximately 300 nm in diameter. Figure&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig3" ref-type="fig">3b</xref> is an enlarged view of a rectangular portion seen at the central position of Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig3" ref-type="fig">3a</xref>. In the figure, the size of primary particles was less than 10 nm, and the lattice spacing was 0.31&#x02009;nm. Crystalline particles could be found along with amorphous SiO<sub>x</sub> particles.<fig id="Fig3"><label>Figure 3</label><caption><p>TEM images showing aggregated nanometer sized particles (<bold>a</bold>) and crystalline structures of particles with high magnification (<bold>b</bold>).</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="41598_2019_50011_Fig3_HTML" id="d29e439"/></fig></p><p id="Par10">Figure&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig4" ref-type="fig">4</xref> is the XRD spectrum showing peaks of Si crystals, amorphous SiO<sub>2</sub> particles, and SiC. The broad peak at 2&#x003b8; equals 20&#x000b0; ~ 30&#x000b0; on the left side of Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig4" ref-type="fig">4</xref>, showing the presence of amorphous SiO<sub>2</sub>. In case of larger than 30&#x000b0; for 2&#x003b8; value several peaks confirm the presence of crystalline Si and SiC<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR13">13</xref>&#x02013;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR16">16</xref></sup>. When the SiO<sub>x</sub> particles were used as an anode material, it was known through the result of the previous study that the higher the Si crystal content, the higher the charge/discharge capacity<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR17">17</xref></sup>. In their article, Takezawa <italic>et al</italic>.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR17">17</xref></sup> showed that the values of charge and discharge capacities were decreased with increasing values of <italic>x</italic> in SiO<sub>x</sub>. On the basis of this literature and the XRD analysis we believe that it is quite possible to use the collected SiO<sub>x</sub> powder as an anode materials of the lithium ion battery<fig id="Fig4"><label>Figure 4</label><caption><p>XRD peaks showing Si and SiC crystalline and amorphous SiO<sub>2</sub>.</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="41598_2019_50011_Fig4_HTML" id="d29e497"/></fig></p><p id="Par11">Figure&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig5" ref-type="fig">5</xref> shows particle size distribution of collected particles. The distribution is bimodal with a group of nm sized particles and a group of &#x003bc;m sized particles. This could explain the &#x003bc;m sized particles shown in FE-SEM photographs and lots of agglomerated nm sized particles found around the &#x003bc;m sized particles. The mean sizes of the nm size group on the left and the &#x003bc;m size one on the right were 322.9 nm and 17.9 &#x003bc;m, with standard deviations of 40.7 nm and 3.5 &#x003bc;m, respectively. The specific surface area and average pore size of the particles measured by BET and BJH analyses were 184.4 m<sup>2</sup>/g and 7.4 nm, respectively. FE-SEM image, the specific surface area, and the pore size suggested that tens of nanometer particles aggregated to form larger particles with diameter of approximately 300&#x02009;nm and agglomerates of larger particles formed tens of micrometer sized particles.<fig id="Fig5"><label>Figure 5</label><caption><p>Particle size distribution showing a bimodal shape with mode values of 322.9&#x02009;nm and 17.9 &#x003bc;m.</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="41598_2019_50011_Fig5_HTML" id="d29e514"/></fig></p><p id="Par12">These collected particles were identified as SiO<sub>x</sub> particles mixed with crystalline Si through several analyses. When Si is used as an anode material for a lithium ion battery, crystalline Si is advantageous in terms of the capacity of the battery. There have been some attempts to utilize amorphous SiO<sub>x</sub> particles because of disadvantages caused by the expansion and contraction of crystalline Si particles occurred during charging and discharging process<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR18">18</xref></sup>. In this view, proper mixing of these two types of particles (Si crystal and amorphous SiO<sub>2</sub>) could be helpful to achieve good electrochemical performance when they are used as an anode material for lithium ion batteries.</p></sec><sec id="Sec4"><title>Electrochemical property</title><p id="Par13">Figure&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig6" ref-type="fig">6a</xref> shows the galvanostatic charge (Li<sup>+</sup> insertion) and discharge (Li<sup>+</sup> extraction) profiles of SiO<sub>x</sub> anodes in the voltage range of 0.05 to 2.0&#x02009;V (vs. Li/Li<sup>+</sup>) at room temperature. As a result of the charge/discharge test, the initial charging capacity was 1572.8 mAh/g and the initial discharging capacity was 456.3 mAh/g.<fig id="Fig6"><label>Figure 6</label><caption><p>Electrochemical performance of SiO<sub>x</sub> anode. (<bold>a</bold>) Galvanostatic charge and discharge profiles in the 1st, 2nd, 3rd, and 100th cycles. (<bold>b</bold>) Differential capacity vs. cell potential curves. (<bold>c</bold>) Cycle performance and coulombic efficiency of the half coin cell from 1 to 100 charge/discharge cycles.</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="41598_2019_50011_Fig6_HTML" id="d29e571"/></fig></p><p id="Par14">According to the differential capacity plots for the SiO<sub>x</sub> electrodes Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig6" ref-type="fig">6b</xref>, a broad peak is visible at ~0.8&#x02009;V, which is mainly associated with the SEI layer formation on the surface of the SiO<sub>x</sub> particles during the first charge. When the potential reaches ~0.25&#x02009;V vs Li/Li<sup>+</sup>, Si begins to react with Li<sup>+</sup>, resulting two delithiation peaks at ~0.3 and 0.45&#x02009;V vs Li/Li<sup>+</sup>, which are characteristics for the lithiation reactions of amorphous Li<sub>x</sub>Si.</p><p id="Par15">Figure&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig6" ref-type="fig">6c</xref> is a graph showing results of charge/discharge tests up to 100 cycles of the fabricated coin cell. The upper line of the graph shows coulombic efficiency change which means the ratio of the discharge capacity to the charge capacity. Lines at the bottom of the graph show change of charge and discharge capacity according to charge/discharge cycle. The battery capacity maintenance efficiency up to 100 cycles was 40.6% of the initial discharge capacity. This was lower than the average battery capacity retention efficiency (about 70%) of coin cells using modified Si as an anode material<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR13">13</xref>&#x02013;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR16">16</xref></sup>. The coulombic efficiency was 29.0% at the first charge/discharge and close to 100% after the 5th cycle. It is necessary to increase the initial coulombic efficiency through modification of particles.</p><p id="Par16">The reason why the initial coulombic efficiency was low during charging and discharging was due to reaction of Si and electrolyte. In this reaction, a layer called SEI was formed on the Si surface. During the reaction, Li<sup>+</sup> was lost and the capacity was reduced. When SEI was formed, the reaction was terminated and Li<sup>+</sup> was used in the charge and discharge processes to maintain a coulombic efficiency of about 99%. However, if SEI cracks, a new SEI is created, resulting in lower efficiency<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR18">18</xref>&#x02013;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR20">20</xref></sup>. Based on charge/discharge test results, we believe that, if accompanied with surface modification, SiO<sub>x</sub> particles collected from Si vapors in the ingot growing process could be utilized as an anode material of lithium ion battery.</p></sec></sec><sec id="Sec5"><title>Summary and Conclusion</title><p id="Par17">The purpose of this study was to investigate the possibility of using recycled SiO<sub>x</sub> particles as an anode material of a lithium ion battery. FE-SEM, EDS, TEM, XRD, PSA, BET and XPS analyses were done on SiO<sub>x</sub> particles collected at the vapor exhaust duct of the ingot growing furnace. In addition, a half coin cell was prepared using these collected particles as an anode material and electrical characteristics of the cell were measured through charge/discharge test. Through these analyses, it was confirmed that the collected particles were SiO<sub>x</sub> particles mixed with crystalline Si and amorphous SiO<sub>2</sub>. These particles were distributed in two groups with average sizes of 322.9 nm and 17.9 &#x003bc;m. The specific surface area was 184.4 m<sup>2</sup>/g and the average pore size was 7.4 nm. In the charge/discharge test, the battery capacity maintenance efficiency was 40.6% compared to the initial discharge amount after up to 100 cycles and the coulombic efficiency was more than 99% after 5 cycles.</p><p id="Par18">This study showed that the recycling SiO<sub>x</sub> particles exhausted from the Si ingot grower is environmentally friendly and economical. Results also showed that these collected particles could be used as an anode material for lithium ion batteries.</p></sec><sec id="Sec6"><title>Experimental Details</title><sec id="Sec7"><title>Collection of Si particles</title><p id="Par19">Si particles were collected at a single crystal Si ingot grower made by S-Tech Co. Ltd. (Model SS1). The grower is currently operated by M company, one of domestic Si ingot producers in South Korea. The filtration system used for collecting Si particles was manufactured by H &#x00026; D Co. Ltd. It is cylindrical in shape with an outer diameter of 558&#x02009;mm, a length of 1315&#x02009;mm, and a thickness of 8.5&#x02009;mm. The filter installed for collecting particles was made by 3GS Co. Ltd. It has 10&#x02009;mm thick glass fiber material and pores of 30 to 40 &#x003bc;m in diameter. The filter has 50 wrinkles with an inner diameter of 224&#x02009;mm, an outer diameter of 359&#x02009;mm, and a length of 535&#x02009;mm. Details of particle collection were described in a previous work<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR21">21</xref></sup>.</p></sec><sec id="Sec8"><title>Characterization of collected particles</title><p id="Par20">To determine particle shape and compositions, field-emission scanning electron microscopy (FE-SEM) images were obtained and energy dispersive spectrometer (EDS) analysis was performed, respectively (SU-70, HITACHI). Brunauer-Emmett-Teller (BET) and Barrett-Joyner-Halenda (BJH) analyses from N<sub>2</sub> adsorption isotherms (77&#x02009;K) measured using volumetric equipment were performed to confirm the specific surface area and pore size distribution of particles, respectively (ASAP2010, Micromeritics). Particle size analysis (PSA) was also performed to know the particle size distribution of particles (UPA-150, Microtrac). Cs-corrected field emission transmission electron microscopy (FE-TEM) analysis was also performed to confirm the crystal structure of particles (JEM-ARM-200F, JEOL). X-ray diffraction (XRD, MAX-2500, RIGAKU) and X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS, K-Alpha XPS System, Thermo Fisher Scientific) were used to observe crystalline structures.</p></sec><sec id="Sec9"><title>Measurement of electrochemical property</title><p id="Par21">A half-coin cell (CR 2032) was fabricated to check the possibility of using these collected Si particles as an anode material of the lithium ion secondary battery. Electrode was prepared by mixing three components [active material: binder (35&#x02009;wt% PAA, Aldrich): conductive agent (Super P, Fisher Scientific)&#x02009;=&#x02009;8: 1: 1 by weight] to make a slurry which was then applied to copper foil and dried at 80&#x02009;&#x000b0;C for 6&#x02009;hours. The painted copper foil was squeezed using a roll press and dried under vacuum at 120&#x02009;&#x000b0;C for 12&#x02009;hours. After that, circular electrode plates (15&#x02009;mm in diameter, according to coin cell size) were made from the painted and completely dried copper foil using a punching machine. The electrolyte solution was 1&#x02009;M LiPF<sub>6</sub> (Aldrich) in which ethylene carbonate (EC) and diethyl carbonate (DEC) were mixed at the same volume. WBCS3000Le32 tester (WonA Tech Co.) was used for charge/discharge test of the fabricated battery. Test conditions were set to 0.2&#x02009;C rate for forming solid electrolyte interphase (SEI) up to the initial 3 cycles. Then 1.0&#x02009;C rate was maintained for the following 97 cycles. The cut off condition was 0.05 to 2&#x02009;V. It was the same for all 100 cycles.</p></sec></sec></body><back><fn-group><fn><p><bold>Publisher&#x02019;s note</bold> Springer Nature remains neutral with regard to jurisdictional claims in published maps and institutional affiliations.</p></fn></fn-group><ack><title>Acknowledgements</title><p>This work (Grant No. 0504805) was supported by Business for Cooperative R&#x00026;D between Industry, Academy, and Research Institute funded by Korea Small and Medium Business Administration in 2017.</p></ack><notes notes-type="author-contribution"><title>Author Contributions</title><p>J. Kim designed and prepared the material, conducted the experiments, and wrote the paper; S.Y. Kim and C.-M. Yang conducted experiments related to the electrochemical performance, and analyzed the result; G.W. Lee designed the study, analyzed the result and revised the paper.</p></notes><notes notes-type="COI-statement"><title>Competing Interests</title><p id="Par22">The authors declare no competing interests.</p></notes><ref-list id="Bib1"><title>References</title><ref id="CR1"><label>1.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Woditsch</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name><name><surname>Koch</surname><given-names>W</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Solar grade silicon feedstock supply for PV industry</article-title><source>Sol. Energy Mater. Sol. Cells</source><year>2002</year><volume>72</volume><fpage>11</fpage><lpage>26</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/S0927-0248(01)00146-5</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR2"><label>2.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Saga</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Advances in crystalline silicon solar cell technology for industrial mass production</article-title><source>NPG Asia Mater.</source><year>2010</year><volume>2</volume><fpage>96</fpage><lpage>102</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1038/asiamat.2010.82</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR3"><label>3.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Drouiche</surname><given-names>N</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Recovery of solar grade silicon from kerf loss slurry waste</article-title><source>Renew. Sustain. Energy Rev.</source><year>2014</year><volume>32</volume><fpage>936</fpage><lpage>943</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.rser.2014.01.059</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR4"><label>4.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Drouiche</surname><given-names>N</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Hidden values in kerf slurry waste recovery of high purity silicon</article-title><source>Renew. Sustain. Energy Rev.</source><year>2015</year><volume>52</volume><fpage>393</fpage><lpage>399</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.rser.2015.07.114</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR5"><label>5.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>TY</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Recovery of silicon from kerf loss slurry waste for photovoltaic applications</article-title><source>Prog. Photovoltaics Res. Appl.</source><year>2009</year><volume>17</volume><fpage>155</fpage><lpage>163</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/pip.863</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR6"><label>6.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Tsai</surname><given-names>TH</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Modified sedimentation system for improving separation of silicon and silicon carbide in recycling of sawing waste</article-title><source>Sep. Purif. Technol.</source><year>2011</year><volume>78</volume><fpage>16</fpage><lpage>20</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.seppur.2011.01.011</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR7"><label>7.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Tsai</surname><given-names>TH</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Silicon sawing waste treatment by electrophoresis and gravitational settling</article-title><source>J. Hazard. Mater.</source><year>2011</year><volume>189</volume><fpage>526</fpage><lpage>530</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.jhazmat.2011.02.070</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21402439</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR8"><label>8.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Tomono</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Recycling of kerf loss silicon derived from diamond-wire saw cutting process by chemical approach</article-title><source>Sep. Purif. Technol.</source><year>2013</year><volume>120</volume><fpage>304</fpage><lpage>309</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.seppur.2013.10.014</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR9"><label>9.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Sergiienko</surname><given-names>SA</given-names></name><name><surname>Pogorelov</surname><given-names>BV</given-names></name><name><surname>Daniliuk</surname><given-names>VB</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Silicon and silicon carbide powders recycling technology from wire-saw cutting waste in slicing process of silicon ingots</article-title><source>Sep. Purif. Technol.</source><year>2014</year><volume>133</volume><fpage>16</fpage><lpage>21</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.seppur.2014.06.036</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR10"><label>10.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Xie</surname><given-names>X</given-names></name><name><surname>Mao</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name><surname>Qi</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name><surname>Ma</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>ReS2-Based electrode materials for alkali-metal ion batteries</article-title><source>CrystEngComm</source><year>2019</year><volume>21</volume><fpage>3755</fpage><lpage>3769</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1039/C9CE00531E</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR11"><label>11.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Liao</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Controlling the morphology, size and phase of Nb2O5 crystals for high electrochemical performance</article-title><source>Chinese Chem. Lett.</source><year>2018</year><volume>29</volume><fpage>1785</fpage><lpage>1790</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.cclet.2018.11.018</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR12"><label>12.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name><name><surname>Xie</surname><given-names>X</given-names></name><name><surname>Dinh</surname><given-names>KN</given-names></name><name><surname>Yan</surname><given-names>Q</given-names></name><name><surname>Ma</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Synthesis, characterizations, and utilization of oxygen-deficient metal oxides for lithium/sodium-ion batteries and supercapacitors</article-title><source>Coord. Chem. Rev.</source><year>2019</year><volume>397</volume><fpage>138</fpage><lpage>167</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.ccr.2019.06.015</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR13"><label>13.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Jang</surname><given-names>HD</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Aerosol-Assisted Extraction of Silicon Nanoparticles from Wafer Slicing Waste for Lithium Ion Batteries</article-title><source>Sci. Rep.</source><year>2015</year><volume>5</volume><fpage>1</fpage><lpage>5</lpage></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR14"><label>14.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>SK</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>One-Step Formation of Silicon-Graphene Composites from Silicon Sludge Waste and Graphene Oxide via Aerosol Process for Lithium Ion Batteries</article-title><source>Sci. Rep.</source><year>2016</year><volume>6</volume><fpage>1</fpage><lpage>8</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1038/s41598-016-0001-8</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">28442746</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR15"><label>15.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Bao</surname><given-names>Q</given-names></name><name><surname>Huang</surname><given-names>YH</given-names></name><name><surname>Lan</surname><given-names>CK</given-names></name><name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>BH</given-names></name><name><surname>Duh</surname><given-names>JG</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Scalable Upcycling Silicon from Waste Slicing Sludge for High-performance Lithium-ion Battery Anodes</article-title><source>Electrochim. Acta</source><year>2015</year><volume>173</volume><fpage>82</fpage><lpage>90</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.electacta.2015.04.155</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR16"><label>16.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Chou</surname><given-names>CY</given-names></name><name><surname>Kuo</surname><given-names>JR</given-names></name><name><surname>Yen</surname><given-names>SC</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Silicon-Based Composite Negative Electrode Prepared from Recycled Silicon-Slicing Slurries and Lignin/Lignocellulose for Li-Ion Cells</article-title><source>ACS Sustain. Chem. Eng.</source><year>2018</year><volume>6</volume><fpage>4759</fpage><lpage>4766</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/acssuschemeng.7b03887</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR17"><label>17.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Takezawa</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name><name><surname>Iwamoto</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name><name><surname>Ito</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name><surname>Yoshizawa</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Electrochemical behaviors of nonstoichiometric silicon suboxides (SiOx) film prepared by reactive evaporation for lithium rechargeable batteries</article-title><source>J. Power Sources</source><year>2013</year><volume>244</volume><fpage>149</fpage><lpage>157</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.jpowsour.2013.02.077</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR18"><label>18.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name><name><surname>Wu</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>Q</given-names></name><name><surname>Su</surname><given-names>X</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Recent advancement of SiOxbased anodes for lithium-ion batteries</article-title><source>J. Power Sources</source><year>2017</year><volume>363</volume><fpage>126</fpage><lpage>144</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.jpowsour.2017.07.073</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR19"><label>19.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Ashuri</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name><surname>He</surname><given-names>Q</given-names></name><name><surname>Shaw</surname><given-names>LL</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Silicon as a potential anode material for Li-ion batteries: Where size, geometry and structure matter</article-title><source>Nanoscale</source><year>2016</year><volume>8</volume><fpage>74</fpage><lpage>103</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1039/C5NR05116A</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">26612324</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR20"><label>20.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Feng</surname><given-names>Kun</given-names></name><name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>Matthew</given-names></name><name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>Wenwen</given-names></name><name><surname>Kashkooli</surname><given-names>Ali Ghorbani</given-names></name><name><surname>Xiao</surname><given-names>Xingcheng</given-names></name><name><surname>Cai</surname><given-names>Mei</given-names></name><name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>Zhongwei</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Silicon-Based Anodes for Lithium-Ion Batteries: From Fundamentals to Practical Applications</article-title><source>Small</source><year>2018</year><volume>14</volume><issue>8</issue><fpage>1702737</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/smll.201702737</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR21"><label>21.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name><surname>Ahn</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name><surname>Kang</surname><given-names>HY</given-names></name><name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>GW</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Collection of Silicone Nanoparticles in Ingot Growing Process and Analysis of Particle Characteristics</article-title><source>Key Eng. Mater.</source><year>2018</year><volume>777</volume><fpage>145</fpage><lpage>149</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.4028/www.scientific.net/KEM.777.145</pub-id></element-citation></ref></ref-list></back></article>