<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD JATS (Z39.96) Journal Archiving and Interchange DTD v1.1 20151215//EN" "JATS-archivearticle1.dtd"> 
<article xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" article-type="research-article"><?properties open_access?><?DTDIdentifier.IdentifierValue -//Springer-Verlag//DTD A++ V2.4//EN?><?DTDIdentifier.IdentifierType public?><?SourceDTD.DTDName A++V2.4.dtd?><?SourceDTD.Version 2.4?><?ConverterInfo.XSLTName springer2nlmx2.xsl?><?ConverterInfo.Version 1?><front><journal-meta><journal-id journal-id-type="nlm-ta">Sci Rep</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="iso-abbrev">Sci Rep</journal-id><journal-title-group><journal-title>Scientific Reports</journal-title></journal-title-group><issn pub-type="epub">2045-2322</issn><publisher><publisher-name>Nature Publishing Group UK</publisher-name><publisher-loc>London</publisher-loc></publisher></journal-meta><article-meta><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid">6107536</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">30703</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1038/s41598-018-30703-3</article-id><article-categories><subj-group subj-group-type="heading"><subject>Article</subject></subj-group></article-categories><title-group><article-title>Mechanochemical synthesis of Si/Cu<sub>3</sub>Si-based composite as negative electrode materials for lithium ion battery</article-title></title-group><contrib-group><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Hou</surname><given-names>Shang-Chieh</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff1">1</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>Tsan-Yao</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff2">2</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Wu</surname><given-names>Yu-Hsien</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff3">3</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>Hung-Yuan</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff3">3</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Lin</surname><given-names>Xin-Dian</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff3">3</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>Yu-Qi</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff3">3</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author" corresp="yes"><name><surname>Huang</surname><given-names>Jow-Lay</given-names></name><address><email>jlh888@mail.ncku.edu.tw</email></address><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff1">1</xref><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff4">4</xref><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff5">5</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author" corresp="yes"><name><surname>Chang</surname><given-names>Chia-Chin</given-names></name><address><email>ccchang@mail.nutn.edu.tw</email></address><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff3">3</xref><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff5">5</xref></contrib><aff id="Aff1"><label>1</label><institution-wrap><institution-id institution-id-type="ISNI">0000 0004 0532 3255</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="GRID">grid.64523.36</institution-id><institution>Department of Materials Science and Engineering, </institution><institution>National Cheng Kung University, </institution></institution-wrap>Tainan, 70101 Taiwan </aff><aff id="Aff2"><label>2</label><institution-wrap><institution-id institution-id-type="ISNI">0000 0004 0532 0580</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="GRID">grid.38348.34</institution-id><institution>Department of Engineering and System Science, </institution><institution>National Tsing Hua University, </institution></institution-wrap>Hsinchu, 30013 Taiwan </aff><aff id="Aff3"><label>3</label><institution-wrap><institution-id institution-id-type="ISNI">0000 0004 0639 002X</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="GRID">grid.412120.4</institution-id><institution>Department of Greenergy, </institution><institution>National University of Tainan, </institution></institution-wrap>Tainan, 70005 Taiwan </aff><aff id="Aff4"><label>4</label><institution-wrap><institution-id institution-id-type="ISNI">0000 0004 0532 3255</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="GRID">grid.64523.36</institution-id><institution>Center for Micro/Nano Science and Technology, </institution><institution>National Cheng Kung University, </institution></institution-wrap>Tainan, 70101 Taiwan </aff><aff id="Aff5"><label>5</label><institution-wrap><institution-id institution-id-type="ISNI">0000 0004 0532 3255</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="GRID">grid.64523.36</institution-id><institution>Hierarchical Green-Energy Materials (Hi-GEM) Research Center, </institution><institution>National Cheng Kung University, </institution></institution-wrap>Tainan, 70101 Taiwan </aff></contrib-group><pub-date pub-type="epub"><day>23</day><month>8</month><year>2018</year></pub-date><pub-date pub-type="pmc-release"><day>23</day><month>8</month><year>2018</year></pub-date><pub-date pub-type="collection"><year>2018</year></pub-date><volume>8</volume><elocation-id>12695</elocation-id><history><date date-type="received"><day>22</day><month>5</month><year>2018</year></date><date date-type="accepted"><day>2</day><month>8</month><year>2018</year></date></history><permissions><copyright-statement>&#x000a9; The Author(s) 2018</copyright-statement><license license-type="OpenAccess"><license-p><bold>Open Access</bold> This article is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International License, which permits use, sharing, adaptation, distribution and reproduction in any medium or format, as long as you give appropriate credit to the original author(s) and the source, provide a link to the Creative Commons license, and indicate if changes were made. The images or other third party material in this article are included in the article&#x02019;s Creative Commons license, unless indicated otherwise in a credit line to the material. If material is not included in the article&#x02019;s Creative Commons license and your intended use is not permitted by statutory regulation or exceeds the permitted use, you will need to obtain permission directly from the copyright holder. To view a copy of this license, visit <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</ext-link>.</license-p></license></permissions><abstract id="Abs1"><p id="Par1">Mechanochemical synthesis of Si/Cu<sub>3</sub>Si-based composite as negative electrode materials for lithium ion battery is investigated. Results indicate that CuO is decomposed and alloyed with Si forming amorphous Cu-Si solid solution due to high energy impacting during high energy mechanical milling (HEMM). Upon carbonization at 800&#x02009;&#x000b0;C, heating energy induces Cu<sub>3</sub>Si to crystallize in nanocrystalline/amorphous Si-rich matrix enhancing composite rigidity and conductivity. In addition, residual carbon formed on outside surface of composite powder as a buff space further alleviates volume change upon lithiation/delithiation. Thus, coin cell made of C-coated Si/Cu<sub>3</sub>Si-based composite as negative electrode (active materials loading, 2.3&#x02009;mg&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;2</sup>) conducted at 100&#x02009;mA&#x02009;g<sup>&#x02212;1</sup> performs the initial charge capacity of 1812&#x02009;mAh&#x02009;g<sup>&#x02212;1</sup> (4.08 mAh cm<sup>&#x02212;2</sup>) columbic efficiency of 83.7% and retained charge capacity of 1470&#x02009;mAh&#x02009;g<sup>&#x02212;1</sup> (3.31 mAh cm<sup>&#x02212;2</sup>) at the end of the 100<sup>th</sup> cycle, opening a promised window as negative electrode materials for lithium ion batteries.</p></abstract><custom-meta-group><custom-meta><meta-name>issue-copyright-statement</meta-name><meta-value>&#x000a9; The Author(s) 2018</meta-value></custom-meta></custom-meta-group></article-meta></front><body><sec id="Sec1" sec-type="introduction"><title>Introduction</title><p id="Par2">Rechargeable lithium-ion batteries (LIBs) has been attracted much attention on energy storage due to its high energy density and long cycle life for increasing demand of portable electric devices, electric vehicles (EV), hybrid electric vehicles (HEV), plug-in hybrid electric vehicles (PHEV) and grid energy storage system<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR1">1</xref>&#x02013;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR3">3</xref></sup>. However, traditional graphite negative material is limited by its theoretical specific capacity of 372&#x02009;mAh&#x02009;g<sup>&#x02212;1</sup>. Thus, a lot of effort are paid to develop next generation materials for negative electrode for LIBs. Silicon is considered to be next generation anode material in lithium ion battery due to its high theoretical specific capacity of 4200&#x02009;mAh&#x02009;g<sup>&#x02212;1</sup>&#x02009;<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR4">4</xref></sup>, low discharge voltage (~0.4&#x02009;V versus Li<sup>+</sup>/Li), highly abundant resource and low toxicity. However, its huge volume change (&#x0003e;400%) during the lithiation/delithiation results in silicon crumbing and pulverizing, leading to loss of integration of the anode<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR5">5</xref></sup>. As a result, silicon negative electrode suffers from more irreversible loss, rapid fading of capacity and short cycle life.</p><p id="Par3">The strategies on improving silicon-based anode materials have been conducted including: (i) silicon nanostructure<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR6">6</xref>&#x02013;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR8">8</xref></sup> such as nanoparticles, nanowires, nanotubes, and porous silicon, (ii) silicon composite such as silicon/active<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR9">9</xref></sup> and silicon/inactive composites<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR10">10</xref></sup>, (iii) novel silicon architecture such as core/shell<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR11">11</xref></sup>, core/hollow/shell<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR12">12</xref></sup>. (iv) electrolyte additives<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR13">13</xref></sup> and (v) synthesis of new binders<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR14">14</xref></sup>.</p><p id="Par4">Silicon-based composites (silicon/active and silicon/inactive) have been widely studied as buffer space, strength and conductivity enhancement to accommodate volume change upon alloying/dealloying and improve intrinsic low conductivity of silicon. Recently, several works have been published utilizing Cu/copper silicide in silicon-based composites as negative electrode materials in LIBs due to its better conductivity and rigidity compared with silicon<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR15">15</xref>&#x02013;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR21">21</xref></sup>. As compared to sophisticated synthesis, mechanochemical reaction induced by high energy mechanical milling (HEMM) is known as a robust method conventionally employed in mass-production. HEMM reduce powder size, induce crystallite amorphizing and enable alloying reaction under non-equilibrium driven by high mechanical energy<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR22">22</xref></sup>. In our previous work, submicro-sized Si aggregate of nanocrystalline/amorphous phases prepared by combining HEMM with wet milling treatments improve Si negative electrode performance<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR23">23</xref></sup>. In this work, Cu<sub>3</sub>Si compound is further synthesized by mechanochemical reaction between CuO and Si upon HEMM. Resulted Cu<sub>3</sub>Si is embedded and dispersed into nanocrystalline/amorphous Si-rich matrix to fabricate Si/Cu<sub>3</sub>Si-based composite. Following, carbonization using glucose as carbon source on composite enhances Cu<sub>3</sub>Si nanocrystallite regardless of nanocrystalline/amorphous Si-rich matrix. Furthermore, residual carbon on composite surface accommodates volume expansion to further improve cycling stability of electrode. Conveniently, both mechanochemical reaction and carbonization are robustly conducted under solid-state condition.</p></sec><sec id="Sec2" sec-type="results"><title>Results</title><p id="Par5">Figure&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig1" ref-type="fig">1</xref> illustrates the synthesis for Si/Cu<sub>3</sub>Si-based composite powder. First, Mixture of micrometric Si<sub>P</sub>, CuO and VGCF was high energy mechanically milled to reduce particle size, which induces amorphizing to form micro-sized SCV<sub>H</sub> aggregate (nanocrystalline/amorphous phases)<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR23">23</xref></sup>. Meanwhile, high energy impacting supposedly leads CuO to decomposing and alloying with Si to form amorphous Cu-Si solid solution. Then, SCV<sub>H</sub> was wet milled in ethanol to get submicro-sized SCV<sub>H+W</sub> aggregate. Finally, carbonization using glucose as carbon source at 800&#x02009;&#x000b0;C, heating energy enabled Cu<sub>3</sub>Si to crystallize from Si-Cu solid solution, resulting in Cu<sub>3</sub>Si distributing into nanocrystalline/amorphous Si-rich matrix for C-SCV<sub>H+W</sub> aggregate. Besides, residual carbon was covered on surface of C-SCV<sub>H+W</sub> as buffer layer.<fig id="Fig1"><label>Figure 1</label><caption><p>Schematic illustration of the synthesis for Si/Cu<sub>3</sub>Si-based composite powder.</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="41598_2018_30703_Fig1_HTML" id="d29e466"/></fig></p><sec id="Sec3"><title>Powder morphology and TGA analyses</title><p id="Par6">Figure&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig2" ref-type="fig">2</xref> shows the SEM images of Si<sub>P</sub>, SCV<sub>H</sub>, SCV<sub>H+W</sub> and C-SCV<sub>H+W</sub>. Micrometric Si<sub>P</sub> presents in irregular flake-like shape (Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig2" ref-type="fig">2(a)</xref>). Upon HEMM, Si<sub>P</sub>, CuO and VGCF are repeatedly fractured and welded to form micro-sized SCV<sub>H</sub> aggregate constructed by nano-sized primary particles (Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig2" ref-type="fig">2(b)</xref>). SCV<sub>H</sub> is further reduced to submicro-sized SCV<sub>H+W</sub> after wet milling in ethanol (Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig2" ref-type="fig">2(c)</xref>). After pyrolysis, C-SCV<sub>H+W</sub> seems to be slightly adhered via residual carbon due to carbonization of glucose on surface (Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig2" ref-type="fig">2(d)</xref>). Supplementary Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">S1</xref> presents the SEM-EDS spectrum, revealing that C-SCV<sub>H+W</sub> is consisted of 75.0 wt.% Si, 10.1 wt.% Cu, 5.3 wt.% C, and 9.6 wt.% O. The detected O could be ascribed to the amorphous SiO<sub>2</sub> layer on the surface of Si/Cu<sub>3</sub>Si-based composite particles. More detailed observation using transmission electron microscope (TEM) is shown in Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig3" ref-type="fig">3(a&#x02013;c)</xref> for SCV<sub>H+W</sub> and Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig3" ref-type="fig">3(d&#x02013;g)</xref> for C-SCV<sub>H+W</sub>, respectively. Figure&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig3" ref-type="fig">3(a) and (b)</xref> present typical submicro-sized SCV<sub>H+W</sub> and its selected-area electron diffraction (SAED) pattern, SAED 1 corresponding to (111), (220) and (331) of Si without existing others crystalline phases. Figure&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig3" ref-type="fig">3(c)</xref> shows the high-resolution transmission electron microscopy (HRTEM) image indexed as pink circle in Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig3" ref-type="fig">3(a)</xref>, demonstrating that SCV<sub>H+W</sub> is constructed by amorphous laminar welds surrounding the nanocrystalline domain of 0.31&#x02009;nm d-spacing, corresponding to the (111) planes of Si. In contrast, after carbonization, C-SCV<sub>H+W</sub> presents darker spots that are embedded and dispersed in Si-rich matrix as blue dash line circle indexed in Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig3" ref-type="fig">3(d)</xref>. High-angle annular dark-field imaging and line scan of energy dispersive X-ray spectrometry (EDS) reveal that spot areas are highly concentrated by Cu element, suggesting the exhibition of Cu<sub>3</sub>Si as shown in Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig3" ref-type="fig">3(e)</xref>. Besides the Si pattern, SAED 2 further confirms the electron diffraction pattern for Cu<sub>3</sub>Si, corresponding to (300) plane as shown in Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig3" ref-type="fig">3(f)</xref>. It is consistent with observation of XRD pattern. Figure&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig3" ref-type="fig">3(g)</xref> shows the HRTEM image as pink circle indexed in Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig3" ref-type="fig">3(d)</xref>, indicating the outside surface of C-SCV<sub>H+W</sub> is covered by residual carbon originated from glucose carbonization and the inside core of C-SCV<sub>H+W</sub> is constructed by amorphous/nanocrystalline phases. Therefore, the construction of C-SCV<sub>H+W</sub> composite could be depicted as the aggregate that nanocrystalline Cu<sub>3</sub>Si disperses in nanocrystalline/amorphous Si-rich matrix. In addition, among these aggregates are associated via residual carbon. Thermogravimetric analysis (TGA) under air atmosphere for C-SCV<sub>H+W</sub> is shown in Supplementary Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">S2</xref>. The weight of C-SCV<sub>H+W</sub> is drastically decreased with temperature from 380&#x02009;&#x000b0;C to 550&#x02009;&#x000b0;C, which could be ascribe to the weight loss (~4.7&#x02009;wt%) of residual carbon. After 550&#x02009;&#x000b0;C, weight of C-SCV<sub>H+W</sub> is increased with temperature due to Si oxidation.<fig id="Fig2"><label>Figure 2</label><caption><p>SEM micrographs of the (<bold>a</bold>) Si<sub>P</sub>&#x0200a;, (<bold>b</bold>) SCV<sub>H</sub>, (<bold>c</bold>) SCV<sub>H+W</sub>, and (<bold>d</bold>) C-SCV<sub>H+W</sub>, respectively.</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="41598_2018_30703_Fig2_HTML" id="d29e644"/></fig><fig id="Fig3"><label>Figure 3</label><caption><p>(<bold>a</bold>) TEM image of SCV<sub>H+W</sub> aggregate, (<bold>b</bold>) SAED 1 pattern, (<bold>c</bold>) HRTEM image referred to pink cycle in (<bold>a)</bold>, (<bold>d</bold>) TEM image of C-SCV<sub>H+W</sub> aggregate, (<bold>e</bold>) corresponding high-angle annular dark-field image of (<bold>d)</bold>, (<bold>f</bold>) SAED 2 pattern and (<bold>g</bold>) HRTEM image referred to pink cycle in (<bold>d</bold>).</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="41598_2018_30703_Fig3_HTML" id="d29e691"/></fig></p></sec><sec id="Sec4"><title>Powder crystalline, XPS and ATR-FTIR analyses</title><p id="Par7">XRD patterns of the CuO, Si<sub>P</sub>, SCV<sub>H</sub>, SCV<sub>H+W</sub> and C-SCV<sub>H+W</sub> powders for 2 theta from 10 to 90 degree are shown in Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig4" ref-type="fig">4</xref>. CuO presents peaks (JCPDS card No. 48-1548) at 35.5&#x000b0;, 38.7&#x000b0;, 48.7&#x000b0;, 61.5&#x000b0; and 66.2&#x000b0; (Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig4" ref-type="fig">4(a)</xref>). As well, Si<sub>P</sub> demonstrates peaks (JCPDS card No. 65-1060), indexing to (111) at 28.4&#x000b0;, (220) at 47.3&#x000b0;, (311) at 56.1&#x000b0; and (422) at 88.0&#x000b0; (Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig4" ref-type="fig">4(b)</xref>). After high energy mechanical milling for mixture of CuO, Si<sub>P</sub> and VGCF, the micro-sized SCV<sub>H</sub> shows the broaden peaks similar as Si<sub>P</sub> without observation of peaks of CuO. CuO in the SCV<sub>H</sub> composite is suspected to decompose and form amorphous Cu-Si solid solution due to high energy impacting upon HEMM (Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig4" ref-type="fig">4(c)</xref>). Followed by moderate wet milling, submicro-sized SCV<sub>H+W</sub> (Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig4" ref-type="fig">4(d)</xref>) shows no significant difference from micro-sized SCV<sub>H</sub> in XRD pattern. After pyrolysis at 800&#x02009;&#x000b0;C for C-SCV<sub>H+W</sub>, Cu<sub>3</sub>Si peaks (JCPDS card No. 51-0916) indexed to (300) at 45.0&#x000b0; and (012) at 44.6&#x000b0; appear as shown in Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig4" ref-type="fig">4(e)</xref>. The average crystallite size of Si calculated by the Scherrer formula from XRD patterns for SCV<sub>H+W</sub> and C-SCV<sub>H+W</sub> is 21&#x02009;nm and 23&#x02009;nm, respectively. It implies that heat energy enhances crystalline Cu<sub>3</sub>Si formation and slightly increases domain size of Si.<fig id="Fig4"><label>Figure 4</label><caption><p>X-ray diffraction patterns of the (<bold>a</bold>) CuO, (<bold>b</bold>) Si<sub>P</sub>&#x0200a;, (<bold>c</bold>) SCV<sub>H</sub>, (<bold>d</bold>) SCV<sub>H+W</sub> and (<bold>e</bold>) C-SCV<sub>H+W</sub>.</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="41598_2018_30703_Fig4_HTML" id="d29e802"/></fig></p><p id="Par8">The surface composition for Si<sub>P</sub>, SCV<sub>H</sub>, SCV<sub>H+W</sub> and C-SCV<sub>H+W</sub> powders is analyzed by X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS). Figure&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig5" ref-type="fig">5</xref> demonstrates deconvoluted Si2p spectra fitted with five oxidation states with binding energy of 99.2, 100.2, 101.3, 102.1 and 103.4&#x02009;eV for Si<sup>0</sup>, Si<sup>+</sup>, Si<sup>2+</sup>, Si<sup>3+</sup> and Si<sup>4+</sup>, respectively<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR24">24</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR25">25</xref></sup>. Summary of concentrations by integrating the peak intensities for the Si oxidation states of Si2p spectra is shown in Table&#x000a0;<xref rid="Tab1" ref-type="table">1</xref>. In all samples as shown in Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig5" ref-type="fig">5(a&#x02013;d)</xref>, the first peak occurring at around 99&#x02009;eV is assigned to bulk silicon, corresponding to Si<sup>0</sup>. Another peak occurring at around 103&#x02009;eV is ascribed to SiO<sub>2</sub>, corresponding to Si<sup>4+</sup>. Compared to Si<sub>P</sub>, SCV<sub>H</sub>, SCV<sub>H+W</sub> and C-SCV<sub>H+W</sub> show the peak shifting to lower binding energy from 103.0&#x02009;eV to 102.5&#x02009;eV. It might be attributed to mechanochemical reaction between CuO and Si upon HEMM resulting in formations of copper silicide and silicon oxide. As compared to Si<sub>P</sub>, Cu2p<sub>3/2</sub> peak located around 932.8&#x02009;eV is observed for SCV<sub>H</sub>, SCV<sub>H+W</sub> and C-SCV<sub>H+W</sub> (Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig5" ref-type="fig">5(e)</xref>). The binding energy of Cu<sup>2+</sup> (CuO) located around 934.0&#x02009;eV shifts to lower binding energy around 932.8&#x02009;eV, suggesting CuO is reduced<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR26">26</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR27">27</xref></sup> upon HEMM.<fig id="Fig5"><label>Figure 5</label><caption><p>XPS spectra of the Si2p for (<bold>a</bold>) Si<sub>P</sub>&#x0200a;, (<bold>b</bold>) SCV<sub>H</sub>, (<bold>c</bold>) SCV<sub>H+W</sub>, (<bold>d</bold>) C-SCV<sub>H+W</sub> and (<bold>e</bold>) Cu2p<sub>3/2</sub> for Si<sub>P</sub>&#x0200a;, SCV<sub>H</sub>, SCV<sub>H+W</sub> and C-SCV<sub>H+W</sub>, respectively.</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="41598_2018_30703_Fig5_HTML" id="d29e953"/></fig><table-wrap id="Tab1"><label>Table 1</label><caption><p>Surface concentration measured by XPS deconvoluted by variety of oxidation states for Si2p spectra of Si<sub>P</sub>&#x0200a;, SCV<sub>H</sub>, SCV<sub>H+W</sub> and C-SCV<sub>H+W</sub> powders.</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th>Samples</th><th>Si<sup>0</sup> (%)</th><th>Si<sup>1+</sup> (%)</th><th>Si<sup>2+</sup> (%)</th><th>Si<sup>3+</sup> (%)</th><th>Si<sup>4+</sup> (%)</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td>Si<sub>p</sub></td><td>23.3</td><td>19.1</td><td>16.7</td><td>19.3</td><td>21.7</td></tr><tr><td>SCV<sub>H</sub></td><td>21.1</td><td>32.2</td><td>21.0</td><td>13.8</td><td>12.0</td></tr><tr><td>SCV<sub>H+W</sub></td><td>25.6</td><td>20.7</td><td>18.3</td><td>22.5</td><td>12.9</td></tr><tr><td>C-SCV<sub>H+W</sub></td><td>22.4</td><td>25.0</td><td>19.4</td><td>23.2</td><td>10.0</td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap></p><p id="Par9">Herein, Si/Cu<sub>3</sub>Si-based composite is synthesized by solid-state reaction combining HEMM with heat treatment of carbonization at 800&#x02009;&#x000b0;C. The sequence is proposed as following reaction (1) and reaction (2). First, CuO is reduced to Cu by Si upon HEMM due to high energy impacting (reaction (1))<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR28">28</xref></sup>. Simultaneously, embryo Cu could diffuse into amorphous Si (reaction (2))<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR29">29</xref></sup> in excess nanocrystalline/amorphous Si-rich matrix. Followed by carbonization, heat energy further enhance the crystallinity of Cu<sub>3</sub>Si. Otherwise, silicon oxide seems to exist in shape of amorphous even after heat treatment at 800&#x02009;&#x000b0;C for C-SCV<sub>H+W</sub>.<disp-formula id="Equ1"><label>1</label><alternatives><tex-math id="M1">\documentclass[12pt]{minimal}
				\usepackage{amsmath}
				\usepackage{wasysym} 
				\usepackage{amsfonts} 
				\usepackage{amssymb} 
				\usepackage{amsbsy}
				\usepackage{mathrsfs}
				\usepackage{upgreek}
				\setlength{\oddsidemargin}{-69pt}
				\begin{document}$$2{\rm{CuO}}+{\rm{Si}}\to 2{\rm{Cu}}+{{\rm{SiO}}}_{2}$$\end{document}</tex-math><mml:math id="M2" display="block"><mml:mn>2</mml:mn><mml:mi mathvariant="normal">CuO</mml:mi><mml:mo>+</mml:mo><mml:mi mathvariant="normal">Si</mml:mi><mml:mo>&#x02192;</mml:mo><mml:mn>2</mml:mn><mml:mi mathvariant="normal">Cu</mml:mi><mml:mo>+</mml:mo><mml:msub><mml:mrow><mml:mi mathvariant="normal">SiO</mml:mi></mml:mrow><mml:mrow><mml:mn>2</mml:mn></mml:mrow></mml:msub></mml:math><graphic xlink:href="41598_2018_30703_Article_Equ1.gif" position="anchor"/></alternatives></disp-formula><disp-formula id="Equ2"><label>2</label><alternatives><tex-math id="M3">\documentclass[12pt]{minimal}
				\usepackage{amsmath}
				\usepackage{wasysym} 
				\usepackage{amsfonts} 
				\usepackage{amssymb} 
				\usepackage{amsbsy}
				\usepackage{mathrsfs}
				\usepackage{upgreek}
				\setlength{\oddsidemargin}{-69pt}
				\begin{document}$$3{\rm{Cu}}+{\rm{Si}}\to {{\rm{Cu}}}_{3}{\rm{Si}}$$\end{document}</tex-math><mml:math id="M4" display="block"><mml:mn>3</mml:mn><mml:mi mathvariant="normal">Cu</mml:mi><mml:mo>+</mml:mo><mml:mi mathvariant="normal">Si</mml:mi><mml:mo>&#x02192;</mml:mo><mml:msub><mml:mrow><mml:mi mathvariant="normal">Cu</mml:mi></mml:mrow><mml:mrow><mml:mn>3</mml:mn></mml:mrow></mml:msub><mml:mi mathvariant="normal">Si</mml:mi></mml:math><graphic xlink:href="41598_2018_30703_Article_Equ2.gif" position="anchor"/></alternatives></disp-formula>ATR-IR spectra of glucose, Si<sub>P</sub>, SCV<sub>H</sub>, SCV<sub>H+W</sub> and C-SCV<sub>H+W</sub> present in Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig6" ref-type="fig">6</xref>. The broad band between 1025 and 1257&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;1</sup> can be assigned to Si&#x02013;O&#x02013;Si asymmetric stretching and 800&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;1</sup> to Si&#x02013;O symmetric stretching band, respectively, revealing oxide layer on the surface of these samples. Compared with Si<sub>P</sub>&#x0200a;, SCV<sub>H</sub> and SCV<sub>H+W</sub> exhibits peak around 966&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;1</sup>, assigning to Si&#x02013;O&#x02013;H deformation vibration. It might be ascribed to adsorption of H<sub>2</sub>O from ambient surroundings by highly reactive dangling bonds on Si surface attributed to HEMM<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR30">30</xref></sup>. SCV<sub>H+W</sub> presents the symmetric stretching vibration of C&#x02013;O bond<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR31">31</xref>&#x02013;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR33">33</xref></sup> after wet milling in ethanol, suggesting that ethanol might be modified on the surface of SCV<sub>H+W</sub>. After carbonization for C-SCV<sub>H+W</sub>, Si&#x02013;O&#x02013;H and C&#x02013;O peaks decrease but Si&#x02013;O peak around 800&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;1</sup> becomes more significant than Si<sub>P</sub>, SCV<sub>H</sub> and SCV<sub>H+W</sub>.<fig id="Fig6"><label>Figure 6</label><caption><p>ATR-FTIR spectra for glucose, Si<sub>P</sub>&#x0200a;, SCV<sub>H</sub>, SCV<sub>H+W</sub> and C-SCV<sub>H+W</sub>, respectively.</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="41598_2018_30703_Fig6_HTML" id="d29e1273"/></fig></p></sec><sec id="Sec5"><title>Electrochemical behavior</title><p id="Par10">Voltage vs. capacity for coin cells with negative electrodes of SCV<sub>H</sub>, SCV<sub>H+W</sub> and C-SCV<sub>H+W</sub> in the 1<sup>st</sup> and 2<sup>nd</sup> lithiation/delithiation cycle are shown in Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig7" ref-type="fig">7(a) and (b)</xref>, respectively. In the lithiation/delithiation cycles, current density is 200&#x02009;mA&#x02009;g<sup>&#x02212;1</sup> and voltage is ranged between 0.002&#x02009;V and 1.5&#x02009;V at room temperature. In the first cycle, initial specific charge (delithiation) capacities is 2273&#x02009;mAh&#x02009;g<sup>&#x02212;1</sup> for SCV<sub>H</sub>, 2264&#x02009;mAh&#x02009;g<sup>&#x02212;1</sup> for SCV<sub>H+W</sub> and 1671&#x02009;mAh&#x02009;g<sup>&#x02212;1</sup> for C-SCV<sub>H+W</sub>. Columbic efficiencies of the three negative electrodes in the first cycle are 86.9%, 83.2%, and 83.2%, respectively. C-SCV<sub>H+W</sub> performs distinguished lithiation from SCV<sub>H</sub> and SCV<sub>H+W</sub>, existing a steep potential drop from 1.5 to 0.06&#x02009;V vs. Li/Li<sup>+</sup> (0 to ~200&#x02009;mAh&#x02009;g<sup>&#x02212;1</sup>) in the first cycle. It could be attributed to recovery of crystallite size for Si (i.e. 21&#x02009;nm and 23&#x02009;nm for SCV<sub>H+W</sub> and C-SCV<sub>H+W</sub>, respectively) and residual carbon coating derived from glucose carbonization on C-SCV<sub>H+W</sub> surface, resulting in various SEI formations.<fig id="Fig7"><label>Figure 7</label><caption><p>Voltage profiles of SCV<sub>H</sub>, SCV<sub>H+W</sub> and C-SCV<sub>H+W</sub> for (<bold>a</bold>) 1<sup>st</sup> cycle and (<bold>b</bold>) 2<sup>nd</sup> cycle conducted at current density 200&#x02009;mA&#x02009;g<sup>&#x02212;1</sup> between 0.002&#x02009;V to 1.5&#x02009;V.</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="41598_2018_30703_Fig7_HTML" id="d29e1378"/></fig></p><p id="Par11">Supplementary Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">S3(a) and (b)</xref> online present the cyclic voltammetry curves of first and second cycle for SCV<sub>H+W</sub>, C-SCV<sub>H+W</sub> and Si<sub>H+W</sub>, respectively in a voltage window of 0.005 to 2.0&#x02009;V at a scan rate of 0.1&#x02009;mV&#x02009;s<sup>&#x02212;1</sup>. Here, Si<sub>H+W</sub><sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR23">23</xref></sup> is pure Si processed high mechanical milling and wet milling as the one of SCV<sub>H+W</sub>. Accordingly, onset voltage of first cathodic curves is 0.36&#x02009;V for SCV<sub>H+W</sub> and 0.13&#x02009;V for C-SCV<sub>H+W</sub>, corresponding to observation of steep potential dropping for C-SCV<sub>H+W</sub> as shown in Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig7" ref-type="fig">7(a)</xref>. The different onset voltage in first cycle between SCV<sub>H+W</sub> and C-SCV<sub>H+W</sub> might be ascribed to glucose-derived carbon coated on surface of C-SCV<sub>H+W</sub>, resulting in particular SEI formations. After SEI formation, onset voltage of second cathodic curves for C-SCV<sub>H+W</sub> is started similar with SCV<sub>H+W</sub> (Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">S3(b)</xref>), consistent with observation in Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig7" ref-type="fig">7(b)</xref>. Otherwise, the cathodic peaks around 0.23&#x02009;V and 0.09&#x02009;V could be attributed to the alloying reaction upon lithiation between Si and lithium, resulting in phase transformation of Li<sub>x</sub>Si. The sharp anodic peak at around 0.09&#x02009;V might be ascribed to the lithium stripping current from the lithium accumulation on surface of SCV<sub>H+W</sub> during cathodic polarization. Two broad anodic peaks (0.29 and 0.47&#x02009;V) can be attributed to the two-step delithiation of Li<sub>x</sub>Si. In addition, we compare cyclic voltammetry between SCV<sub>H+W</sub> and Si<sub>H+W</sub>. The examination of the first lithiation scan of cyclic voltammetry (Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">S3(a)</xref>), the onset voltage (0.36&#x02009;V) and cathodic peaks (0.23&#x02009;V, 0.09&#x02009;V) for SCV<sub>H+W</sub> present slightly shifting to higher voltage than Si<sub>H+W</sub>, onset voltage (0.30&#x02009;V) and cathodic peaks (0.20&#x02009;V, 0.05&#x02009;V). Moreover, the first delithiation scan shows that anodic peaks (0.47&#x02009;V, 0.29&#x02009;V) for SCV<sub>H+W</sub> slightly shift to lower voltage than Si<sub>H+W</sub>, anodic peaks (0.50&#x02009;V, 0.33&#x02009;V). This implies that the formation of Cu<sub>3</sub>Si in pure Si could relatively enhances lithiation/delithiation kinetics.</p><p id="Par12">Cycling tests of experimental electrodes conducted at 200&#x02009;mA&#x02009;g<sup>&#x02212;1</sup> in a voltage range of 0.002&#x02013;1.5&#x02009;V (vs. Li<sup>+</sup>/Li) in specific capacity is shown in Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig8" ref-type="fig">8(a)</xref>. Initial capacity and retention capacity after 100 cycles are summarized in Table&#x000a0;<xref rid="Tab2" ref-type="table">2</xref>. Compared to SCV<sub>H</sub> and SCV<sub>H+W</sub>, suppression of fading for C-SCV<sub>H+W</sub> within initial cycles could be contributed to residual carbon coated on surface as buffer space which leaving sufficient room for relaxing volume expansion between composite particles in lithiation/delithiation processes. Moreover, the construction of nanocrystalline Cu<sub>3</sub>Si distributed in amorphous/nanocrystalline Si matrix is suspected to enhance the conductivity and strength inside the Si/Cu<sub>3</sub>Si-based composite. Thus, the specific charge (delithiation) capacities of SCV<sub>H</sub>, SCV<sub>H+W</sub> and C-SCV<sub>H+W</sub> after 100 cycles are 1022&#x02009;mAh&#x02009;g<sup>&#x02212;1</sup>, 1317&#x02009;mAh&#x02009;g<sup>&#x02212;1</sup> and 1224&#x02009;mAh&#x02009;g<sup>&#x02212;1</sup>, corresponding to retention of 45.0%, 58.2% and 73.2%.<fig id="Fig8"><label>Figure 8</label><caption><p>(<bold>a</bold>) Cycling performance of specific discharge (lithiation)/charge (delithiation) capacity for SCV<sub>H</sub>, SCV<sub>H+W</sub> and C-SCV<sub>H+W</sub> conducted at current density 200&#x02009;mA&#x02009;g<sup>&#x02212;1</sup> between 0.002&#x02009;V to 1.5&#x02009;V. (<bold>b</bold>) Areal charge (delithiation) capacity comparison for C-SCV<sub>H+W</sub> of varied loading (0.8/2.3&#x02009;mg&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;2</sup>) conducted at current density 100 and 200&#x02009;mA&#x02009;g<sup>&#x02212;1</sup> between 0.002&#x02009;V to 1.5&#x02009;V. (<bold>c</bold>) Charge (delithiation) capability of SCV<sub>H</sub>, SCV<sub>H+W</sub> and C-SCV<sub>H+W</sub> at various charge and discharge rates conducted at current density 0.1, 0.2, 0.4, 1.0, 2.0, 4.0 then 0.2, 0.1&#x02009;A&#x02009;g<sup>&#x02212;1</sup> between 0.002&#x02009;V to 1.5&#x02009;V.</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="41598_2018_30703_Fig8_HTML" id="d29e1577"/></fig><table-wrap id="Tab2"><label>Table 2</label><caption><p>Electrochemical properties of SCV<sub>H</sub>, SCV<sub>H+W</sub> and C-SCV<sub>H+W</sub> conducted at 200&#x02009;mA&#x02009;g<sup>&#x02212;1</sup> between 0.002&#x02009;V to 1.5&#x02009;V.</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th>Samples</th><th>1st discharge capacity (mAh g<sup>&#x02212;1</sup>)</th><th>1st charge capacity (mAh g<sup>&#x02212;1</sup>)</th><th>1st Columbic efficiency (%)</th><th>100th capacity (mAh g<sup>&#x02212;1</sup>)</th><th>Retention (%)</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td>SCV<sub>H</sub></td><td>2617</td><td>2273</td><td>86.9</td><td>1022</td><td>45.0</td></tr><tr><td>SCV<sub>H+W</sub></td><td>2722</td><td>2264</td><td>83.2</td><td>1317</td><td>58.2</td></tr><tr><td>C-SCV<sub>H+W</sub></td><td>2009</td><td>1671</td><td>83.2</td><td>1224</td><td>73.2</td></tr></tbody></table><table-wrap-foot><p>The specific capacity was calculated based on the mass of active materials.</p></table-wrap-foot></table-wrap></p><p id="Par13">In order to investigate effects of active materials loading and current density on cycling performance for C-SCV<sub>H+W</sub>, varied current density (100/200&#x02009;mA&#x02009;g<sup>&#x02212;1</sup> in a voltage range of 0.002&#x02013;1.5&#x02009;V (vs. Li<sup>+</sup>/Li)) and active materials loading (0.8/2.3&#x02009;mg&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;2</sup>) are examined in areal capacity variation. Results of initial areal capacity (delithiation) and retained capacity after 100 cycles are summarized in Table&#x000a0;<xref rid="Tab3" ref-type="table">3</xref>. Figure&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig8" ref-type="fig">8(b)</xref> presents the trend that C-SCV<sub>H+W</sub> of lower loading (0.8&#x02009;mg&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;2</sup>) or lower conducted current density (100&#x02009;mA&#x02009;g<sup>&#x02212;1</sup>) performs better relatively retained capacity. However, too low active materials loading means lower areal capacity to practical application in LIBs. To the optimum practice, coin cell made by C-SCV<sub>H+W</sub> as negative electrode of active materials loading, 2.3&#x02009;mg&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;2</sup> conducted at 100&#x02009;mA&#x02009;g<sup>&#x02212;1</sup> enables an initial charge (delithiation) capacity 1812&#x02009;mAh&#x02009;g<sup>&#x02212;1</sup> (4.08 mAh cm<sup>&#x02212;2</sup>) with columbic efficiency of 83.7% and 1470&#x02009;mAh&#x02009;g<sup>&#x02212;1</sup> (3.31 mAh cm<sup>&#x02212;2</sup>) at the end of the 100<sup>th</sup> cycle. Rate capabilities of SCV<sub>H</sub>, SCV<sub>H+W</sub> and C-SCV<sub>H+W</sub> at current density 0.1, 0.2, 0.4, 1.0, 2.0, 4.0 then 0.2, 0.1&#x02009;A&#x02009;g<sup>&#x02212;1</sup> between 0.002&#x02009;V to 1.5&#x02009;V are compared in Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig8" ref-type="fig">8(c)</xref>. SCV<sub>H+W</sub> and C-SCV<sub>H+W</sub> exhibits better rate performance than SCV<sub>H</sub>.<table-wrap id="Tab3"><label>Table 3</label><caption><p>Effects of active materials loading and current density on areal capacity (delithiation) performance for C-SCV<sub>H+W</sub> conducted between 0.002&#x02009;V to 1.5&#x02009;V.</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th>Loading (mg cm<sup>&#x02212;2</sup>)</th><th>Current density (mAh g<sup>&#x02212;1</sup>)</th><th>1st areal capacity (mAh cm<sup>&#x02212;2</sup>)</th><th>100th areal capacity (mAh cm<sup>&#x02212;2</sup>)</th><th>Retention (%)</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td>0.8</td><td>200</td><td>1.28</td><td>1.14</td><td>89.1</td></tr><tr><td>2.3</td><td>100</td><td>4.08</td><td>3.31</td><td>81.1</td></tr><tr><td>2.3</td><td>200</td><td>3.68</td><td>2.69</td><td>73.1</td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap></p><p id="Par14">In addition, electrodes of blank Cu collector, pristine C-SCV<sub>H+W</sub> and 100th cycled C-SCV<sub>H+W</sub> are characterized by XRD in 2&#x003b8; range from 42.5&#x000b0; to 48.0&#x000b0; as shown in Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">S4</xref>. For pristine C-SCV<sub>H+W</sub> electrode (Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">S4(b)</xref>), diffraction peak at 47.3&#x000b0; is attributed to the (220) for Si. In addition, diffraction peaks at 44.6&#x000b0;, 45.0&#x000b0; are attributed to the (012) and (300), respectively for Cu<sub>3</sub>Si. After repeatedly lithiation/delithiation reactions, Si crystalline phase transforms into amorphous phase as shown in Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">S4(c)</xref>. In contrast, diffraction peaks of (012) and (300) for Cu<sub>3</sub>Si are clearly observed after lithiation/delithiation process.</p></sec></sec><sec id="Sec6" sec-type="discussion"><title>Discussion</title><p id="Par15">In this work, the robust method to synthesize Si/Cu<sub>3</sub>Si-based composite as negative electrode materials for lithium ion battery is disclosed. Our results reveal that high energy mechanical milling on Si/CuO mixture induces mechanochemical reaction, resulting in CuO decomposing, amorphizing and alloying with Si. In addition, Si is transformed from well crystalline structure to nanocrystalline/amorphous construction upon high energy impacting. Followed by carbonization, heating energy leads Cu<sub>3</sub>Si to crystallizing and distributing in nanocrystalline/amorphous Si-rich matrix as rigid and conductive enhancer. Furthermore, residual carbon on surface of composite as buffer space alleviates the volume change upon lithiation/delithiation processes. Thus, coin cell made of C-coated Si/Cu<sub>3</sub>Si-based composite (active materials loading, 2.3&#x02009;mg&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;2</sup>) as negative electrode conducted at 100&#x02009;mA&#x02009;g<sup>&#x02212;1</sup> enables an initial charge capacity 1812&#x02009;mAh&#x02009;g<sup>&#x02212;1</sup> (4.08 mAh cm<sup>&#x02212;2</sup>) with columbic efficiency of 83.7% and 1470&#x02009;mAh&#x02009;g<sup>&#x02212;1</sup> (3.31 mAh cm<sup>&#x02212;2</sup>) at the end of the 100<sup>th</sup> cycle. Such a performance enables the Si/Cu<sub>3</sub>Si-based composite as potential candidate for negative electrode materials for lithium ion battery.</p></sec><sec id="Sec7"><title>Methods</title><sec id="Sec8"><title>Materials Preparation</title><p id="Par16">Commercial silicon powder (Si<sub>P</sub>, 99.9%, 10&#x02009;&#x000b5;m, Fuzhou Hokin Chemical Technology, China), CuO powder (99.9%, 0.7&#x02009;um, Nissin Chemco, Japan) and vapor grown carbon fiber (VGCF, Showa Denko K.K, Japan) were used as starting materials without further purifying. Si, CuO and VGCF powders were weighted stoichiometrically with weight ratio of 89: 10: 1. The mixture powder was loaded into stainless vial of 500&#x02009;ml along with stain-less balls of 3&#x02009;mm in dimension. The ball-to-powder mass ratio was 20:1. The vials were sealed under Ar atmosphere in the glove box. High energy mechanical milling (HEMM) was carried out at room temperature for 9&#x02009;hours using a planetary miller (PM 400, Retsch, Germany) with a rotation speed of 300&#x02009;rpm. The milled mixture was denoted as SCV<sub>H</sub> (micro-sized aggregate). Then, SCV<sub>H</sub> is introduced into polypropylene jar along with ZrO<sub>2</sub> balls of 2&#x02009;mm dimension and ethanol medium. The ball-to-powder mass ratio was 10:1. The wet milling was carried out at room temperature using a rotation mixer at 250&#x02009;rpm. After wet milling, powder was filtered and dried at 120&#x02009;&#x000b0;C in vacuum for 12&#x02009;hours. The wet milled SCV<sub>H</sub> was denoted as SCV<sub>H+W</sub> (submicro-sized aggregate). Particle size distribution at 50%, D50 for SCV<sub>H+W</sub> was controlled around 0.4 &#x003bc;m. Meanwhile, SCV<sub>H+W</sub> was mixed with glucose (weight ratio 1: 0.4) in ethanol then dried at 120&#x02009;&#x000b0;C in vacuum for 12&#x02009;hours. The dried mixture of SCV<sub>H+W</sub>/glucose was placed in an alumina crucible, followed by loading into the alumina tube furnace. The temperature was increased to 800&#x02009;&#x000b0;C at heating rate 10&#x02009;&#x000b0;C min<sup>&#x02212;1</sup> and held for 1&#x02009;hour under a mixture gas flow of argon (150&#x02009;ml&#x02009;min<sup>&#x02212;1</sup>), hydrogen (20&#x02009;ml&#x02009;min<sup>&#x02212;1</sup>). Then, the furnace was nature cooled, while the argon gas (150&#x02009;ml&#x02009;min<sup>&#x02212;1</sup>) was continuously flushed through the alumina tube until to room temperature. The carbonization of glucose modified SCV<sub>H+W</sub> was denoted as C- SCV<sub>H+W</sub>.</p></sec><sec id="Sec9"><title>Characterization</title><p id="Par17">The morphology was observed by field emission scanning electron microscope (Carl Zeiss AURIGA CrossBeam (FIB-SEM) Workstation) using an accelerating voltage of 5&#x02009;kV and high-resolution transmission electron microscope (HRTEM, JEM-2100F, JEOL) with an accelerating voltage of 200&#x02009;kV. Si composite powders were dispersed in ethanol, and then transferred onto a Formvar carbon coated nickel grid for TEM sample preparation.</p><p id="Par18">The crystal structure was characterized by X-ray diffractometer (D8 ADVANCE Eco) with Cu K&#x003b1; radiation (&#x003bb;&#x02009;=&#x02009;0.15418&#x02009;nm). Particle size distribution was determined by the laser scattering method using a laser diffraction particle size analyzer (Horiba LA960). Chemical surface composition analysis of the Si powders was conducted using X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS, PHI 5000 VersaProbe) equipped with an Al K&#x003b1; X-ray radiation source operating at 1486.6&#x02009;eV. All spectra were calibrated using C (sp<sup>2</sup>) as a reference binding energy of 284.6&#x02009;eV. Thermogravimetric analysis (TGA) was carried out using thermogravimetric analyzer (TA Instruments, USA) from 25&#x02009;&#x000b0;C to 800&#x02009;&#x000b0;C with a heating rate of 10&#x02009;&#x000b0;C min<sup>&#x02212;1</sup> under air atmosphere. Fourier transform infrared (FTIR) measurement of the Si powders was performed on attenuated total reflectance (ATR) mode using a Cary 660 (Agilent Technologies) FT-IR system equipped with an MCT detector. All spectra were scanned from 650&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;1</sup> to 2000 cm<sup>&#x02212;1</sup> with resolution of 2&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;1</sup> for 256 scans.</p></sec><sec id="Sec10"><title>Electrochemical Measurements</title><p id="Par19">The slurry was prepared by combining the solid components as 65&#x02009;wt% of SCV<sub>H</sub>, SCV<sub>H+W</sub> and C-SCV<sub>H+W</sub>, respectively, 20&#x02009;wt% of Super P (MMM Carbon, Blegium), 9&#x02009;wt% of poly(acrylic acid) (PAA, Sigma-Aldrich Co.), 2.5&#x02009;wt% of carboxymethyl cellulose (CMC, Sigma-Aldrich Co.) and 3.5&#x02009;wt% of styrene butadiene rubber (SBR, Zeon Co.) in deionized water. Mixing was carried out by a planetary mixer (G-Mixer 400&#x02009;S, Gold Max Applied Materials Co.) at 500&#x02009;rpm for 60&#x02009;min. Electrodes were prepared by casting the slurry onto a sheet of copper foil (Nippon Foil Co.) and dried in the oven at 90&#x02009;&#x000b0;C for 1&#x02009;hour. The anodes were stored in a glove box (with oxygen and humidity content maintained below 10 ppm) for more than 24&#x02009;hours before electrochemical testing. The 2032 coin-type cells were assembled, consisting of a test electrode, lithium foil as a counter electrode and a glass fiber separator (GA-100, Advantec) in an Ar-filled glove box. Electrolyte solution was 1&#x02009;M LiPF<sub>6</sub> in a mixture of ethylene carbonate (EC, Ferro Co.), dimethyl carbonate (DMC, Ferro Co.) (1:1 by weight) and additive of 10&#x02009;wt% fluorinated ethylene carbonate (FEC, Sigma-Aldrich Co.). For the cycle test, the cells were conducted in galvanostatic discharge (lithiation)/charge (delithiation) tests between 0.002 and 1.5&#x02009;V versus Li<sup>+</sup>/Li using a multi-channel battery testing system (AcuTech Sys-tems BAT-750B). The specific capacity was calculated based on the mass of active materials. Cyclic voltammetry (CV) measurement was carried out using an Autolab electrochemical analyzer (Autolab PGSTAT30, Eco Chemie) with scan rate of 0.1&#x02009;mV&#x02009;s<sup>&#x02212;1</sup> and a potential range of 0.005&#x02013;2&#x02009;V (vs. Li<sup>+</sup>/Li). All electrochemical tests were performed at 25&#x02009;&#x000b0;C.</p></sec></sec><sec sec-type="supplementary-material"><title>Electronic supplementary material</title><sec id="Sec11"><p>
<supplementary-material content-type="local-data" id="MOESM1"><media xlink:href="41598_2018_30703_MOESM1_ESM.docx"><caption><p>Supporting Information</p></caption></media></supplementary-material>
</p></sec></sec></body><back><fn-group><fn><p><bold>Publisher's note:</bold> Springer Nature remains neutral with regard to jurisdictional claims in published maps and institutional affiliations.</p></fn></fn-group><sec><title>Electronic supplementary material</title><p><bold>Supplementary information</bold> accompanies this paper at 10.1038/s41598-018-30703-3.</p></sec><ack><title>Acknowledgements</title><p>This work was supported by the Hierarchical Green-Energy Materials (Hi-GEM) Research Center, from The Featured Areas Research Center Program within the framework of the Higher Education Sprout Project by the Ministry of Education (MOE) in Taiwan and by the Ministry of Science and Technology of Taiwan under the following contracts: MOST 107-2622-8-024-001 TE4. The authors thank the help of National Synchrotron Radiation Research Center (NSRRC), Hsinchu, Taiwan.</p></ack><notes notes-type="author-contribution"><title>Author Contributions</title><p>J.-L.H. and C.-C.C. managed and coordinated the research teams. S.-C.H. designed the experiments and wrote the manuscript. Y.-H.W. and H.-Y.C. conducted the synthesis experiments and analyzed the composite powders. X.-D.L. and Y.-Q.C. prepared the testing cells and performed the electrochemical measurements. T.-Y.C. helped in data analysis and manuscript writing. All the authors participated in discussions of the results</p></notes><notes notes-type="COI-statement"><sec id="FPar1"><title>Competing Interests</title><p>The authors declare no competing interests.</p></sec></notes><ref-list id="Bib1"><title>References</title><ref id="CR1"><label>1.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Larcher</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name><name><surname>Tarascon</surname><given-names>JM</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Towards greener and more sustainable batteries for electrical energy storage</article-title><source>Nat. Chem.</source><year>2014</year><volume>7</volume><fpage>19</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1038/nchem.2085</pub-id><?supplied-pmid 25515886?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">25515886</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR2"><label>2.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Choi</surname><given-names>JW</given-names></name><name><surname>Aurbach</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Promise and reality of post-lithium-ion batteries with high energy densities</article-title><source>Nat. Rev. Mater.</source><year>2016</year><volume>1</volume><fpage>16013</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1038/natrevmats.2016.13</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR3"><label>3.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Materials Science and Materials Chemistry for Large Scale Electrochemical Energy Storage: From Transportation to Electrical Grid</article-title><source>Adv. Funct. Mater.</source><year>2013</year><volume>23</volume><fpage>929</fpage><lpage>946</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/adfm.201200690</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR4"><label>4.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Boukamp</surname><given-names>BA</given-names></name><name><surname>Lesh</surname><given-names>GC</given-names></name><name><surname>Huggins</surname><given-names>RA</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>All&#x02010;Solid Lithium Electrodes with Mixed&#x02010;Conductor Matrix</article-title><source>J. Electrochem. Soc.</source><year>1981</year><volume>128</volume><fpage>725</fpage><lpage>729</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1149/1.2127495</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR5"><label>5.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Kasavajjula</surname><given-names>U</given-names></name><name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>CS</given-names></name><name><surname>Appleby</surname><given-names>AJ</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Nano- and bulk-silicon-based insertion anodes for lithium-ion secondary cells</article-title><source>J. Power Sources</source><year>2007</year><volume>163</volume><fpage>1003</fpage><lpage>1039</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.jpowsour.2006.09.084</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR6"><label>6.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>XH</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Size-dependent fracture of silicon nanoparticles during lithiation</article-title><source>ACS Nano</source><year>2012</year><volume>6</volume><fpage>1522</fpage><lpage>1531</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/nn204476h</pub-id><?supplied-pmid 22217200?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">22217200</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR7"><label>7.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Chan</surname><given-names>CK</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>High-performance lithium battery anodes using silicon nanowires</article-title><source>Nat. Nanotech.</source><year>2008</year><volume>3</volume><fpage>31</fpage><lpage>35</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1038/nnano.2007.411</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR8"><label>8.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Ge</surname><given-names>MY</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Large-Scale Fabrication, 3D Tomography, and Lithium-Ion Battery Application of Porous Silicon</article-title><source>Nano Lett.</source><year>2014</year><volume>14</volume><fpage>261</fpage><lpage>268</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/nl403923s</pub-id><?supplied-pmid 24279924?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">24279924</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR9"><label>9.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>IS</given-names></name><name><surname>Kumta</surname><given-names>PN</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>High capacity Si/C nanocomposite anodes for Li-ion batteries</article-title><source>J. Power Sources</source><year>2004</year><volume>136</volume><fpage>145</fpage><lpage>149</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.jpowsour.2004.05.016</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR10"><label>10.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>J-H</given-names></name><name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name><name><surname>Sohn</surname><given-names>H-J</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Addition of Cu for carbon coated Si-based composites as anode materials for lithium-ion batteries</article-title><source>Electrochem. Commun.</source><year>2005</year><volume>7</volume><fpage>557</fpage><lpage>561</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.elecom.2005.03.013</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR11"><label>11.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Hwang</surname><given-names>TH</given-names></name><name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>YM</given-names></name><name><surname>Kong</surname><given-names>BS</given-names></name><name><surname>Seo</surname><given-names>JS</given-names></name><name><surname>Choi</surname><given-names>JW</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Electrospun Core-Shell Fibers for Robust Silicon Nanoparticle-Based Lithium Ion Battery Anodes</article-title><source>Nano Lett.</source><year>2012</year><volume>12</volume><fpage>802</fpage><lpage>807</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/nl203817r</pub-id><?supplied-pmid 22206272?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">22206272</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR12"><label>12.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Pan</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Facile synthesis of yolk-shell structured Si-C nanocomposites as anodes for lithium-ion batteries</article-title><source>Chem. Commun.</source><year>2014</year><volume>50</volume><fpage>5878</fpage><lpage>5880</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1039/C4CC01728E</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR13"><label>13.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Schroder</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>The Effect of Fluoroethylene Carbonate as an Additive on the Solid Electrolyte Interphase on Silicon Lithium-Ion Electrodes</article-title><source>Chem. Mater.</source><year>2015</year><volume>27</volume><fpage>5531</fpage><lpage>5542</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/acs.chemmater.5b01627</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR14"><label>14.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Magasinski</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Toward Efficient Binders for Li-Ion Battery Si-Based Anodes: Polyacrylic Acid</article-title><source>ACS Appl. Mater. Interfaces</source><year>2010</year><volume>2</volume><fpage>3004</fpage><lpage>3010</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/am100871y</pub-id><?supplied-pmid 21053920?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21053920</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR15"><label>15.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Zhou</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Cu<sub>3</sub>Si@Si core-shell nanoparticles synthesized using a solid-state reaction and their performance as anode materials for lithium ion batteries</article-title><source>Nanoscale</source><year>2015</year><volume>7</volume><fpage>15075</fpage><lpage>15079</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1039/C5NR04456A</pub-id><?supplied-pmid 26349812?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">26349812</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR16"><label>16.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Shimoi</surname><given-names>N</given-names></name><name><surname>Qiwu</surname><given-names>Z</given-names></name><name><surname>Bahena-Garrido</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name><surname>Tanaka</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Mechanochemical approaches to employ silicon as a lithium-ion battery anode</article-title><source>AIP Adv.</source><year>2015</year><volume>5</volume><fpage>057142</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1063/1.4921563</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR17"><label>17.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Du</surname><given-names>Z</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Electrochemistry of Cu<sub>x</sub>Si<sub>1&#x02212;x</sub> Alloys in Li Cells</article-title><source>J. Electrochem. Soc.</source><year>2016</year><volume>163</volume><fpage>A1275</fpage><lpage>A1279</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1149/2.0811607jes</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR18"><label>18.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Cheng</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Influence of copper addition for silicon-carbon composite as anode materials for lithium ion batteries</article-title><source>RSC Adv.</source><year>2016</year><volume>6</volume><fpage>56756</fpage><lpage>56764</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1039/C6RA12332E</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR19"><label>19.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>S-O</given-names></name><name><surname>Manthiram</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Low-cost carbon-coated Si-Cu<sub>3</sub>Si-Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub> nanocomposite anodes for high-performance lithium-ion batteries</article-title><source>J. Power Sources</source><year>2016</year><volume>332</volume><fpage>222</fpage><lpage>229</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.jpowsour.2016.09.089</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR20"><label>20.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Woo</surname><given-names>J-Y</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Cu<sub>3</sub>Si-doped porous-silicon particles prepared by simplified chemical vapor deposition method as anode material for high-rate and long-cycle lithium-ion batteries</article-title><source>J. Alloys Compd.</source><year>2017</year><volume>701</volume><fpage>425</fpage><lpage>432</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.jallcom.2017.01.137</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR21"><label>21.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Deng</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Facile synthesis of N-doped carbon-coated Si/Cu alloy with enhanced cyclic performance for lithium ion batteries</article-title><source>RSC Adv.</source><year>2016</year><volume>6</volume><fpage>78100</fpage><lpage>78105</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1039/C6RA15847A</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR22"><label>22.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Suryanarayana</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Mechanical alloying and milling</article-title><source>Prog. Mater. Sci.</source><year>2001</year><volume>46</volume><fpage>1</fpage><lpage>184</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/S0079-6425(99)00010-9</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR23"><label>23.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Hou</surname><given-names>S-C</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>The synergistic effects of combining the high energy mechanical milling and wet milling on Si negative electrode materials for lithium ion battery</article-title><source>J. Power Sources</source><year>2017</year><volume>349</volume><fpage>111</fpage><lpage>120</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.jpowsour.2017.03.024</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR24"><label>24.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Yubero</surname><given-names>F</given-names></name><name><surname>Barranco</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name><surname>Mejias</surname><given-names>JA</given-names></name><name><surname>Espinos</surname><given-names>JP</given-names></name><name><surname>Gonzalez-Elipe</surname><given-names>AR</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Spectroscopic characterisation and chemical reactivity of silicon monoxide layers deposited on Cu(100)</article-title><source>Surf Sci.</source><year>2000</year><volume>458</volume><fpage>229</fpage><lpage>238</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/S0039-6028(00)00443-X</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR25"><label>25.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name><name><surname>Gao</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name><surname>Pan</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name><name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>High performance amorphous-Si@SiO<sub>x</sub>/C composite anode materials for Li-ion batteries derived from ball-milling and <italic>in situ</italic> carbonization</article-title><source>J. Power Sources</source><year>2014</year><volume>256</volume><fpage>190</fpage><lpage>199</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.jpowsour.2013.12.128</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR26"><label>26.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Dahlang</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name><name><surname>Sven</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Electronic and optical properties of Cu, CuO and Cu<sub>2</sub>O studied by electron spectroscopy</article-title><source>J. Phys.: Condens. Matter</source><year>2012</year><volume>24</volume><fpage>175002</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">22475683</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR27"><label>27.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>V.</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name><name><surname>A.</surname><given-names>F</given-names></name><name><surname>A.</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name><name><surname>H.</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>XPS study of the atmospheric corrosion of copper alloys of archaeological interest</article-title><source>Surf. Interface Anal.</source><year>2004</year><volume>36</volume><fpage>876</fpage><lpage>879</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/sia.1790</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR28"><label>28.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Shengqi</surname><given-names>X</given-names></name><name><surname>Jingen</surname><given-names>Z</given-names></name><name><surname>Xiaotian</surname><given-names>W</given-names></name><name><surname>Dongwen</surname><given-names>Z</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>The reduction of CuO by Si during ball milling</article-title><source>J. Mater. Sci. Lett.</source><year>1996</year><volume>15</volume><fpage>634</fpage><lpage>635</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/BF00579274</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR29"><label>29.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Chromik</surname><given-names>RR</given-names></name><name><surname>Neils</surname><given-names>WK</given-names></name><name><surname>Cotts</surname><given-names>EJ</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Thermodynamic and kinetic study of solid state reactions in the Cu&#x02013;Si system</article-title><source>J. Appl. Phys.</source><year>1999</year><volume>86</volume><fpage>4273</fpage><lpage>4281</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1063/1.371357</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR30"><label>30.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>Z</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Silica-Derived Hydrophobic Colloidal Nano-Si for Lithium-Ion Batteries</article-title><source>ACS Nano</source><year>2017</year><volume>11</volume><fpage>6065</fpage><lpage>6073</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/acsnano.7b02021</pub-id><?supplied-pmid 28570805?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">28570805</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR31"><label>31.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wei, L. M., Chen, C. X., Hou, Z. Y. &#x00026; Wei, H. Poly (acrylic acid sodium) grafted carboxymethyl cellulose as a high performance polymer binder for silicon anode in lithium ion batteries. <italic>Sci. Rep</italic>. <bold>6</bold> (2016).</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR32"><label>32.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Nanosilica/carbon composite spheres as anodes in Li-ion batteries with excellent cycle stability</article-title><source>J. Mater. Chem. A</source><year>2015</year><volume>3</volume><fpage>1476</fpage><lpage>1482</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1039/C4TA05288A</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR33"><label>33.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Rahman</surname><given-names>IA</given-names></name><name><surname>Vejayakumaran</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name><name><surname>Sipaut</surname><given-names>CS</given-names></name><name><surname>Ismail</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name><surname>Chee</surname><given-names>CK</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Size-dependent physicochemical and optical properties of silica nanoparticles</article-title><source>Mater. Chem. Phys.</source><year>2009</year><volume>114</volume><fpage>328</fpage><lpage>332</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.matchemphys.2008.09.068</pub-id></element-citation></ref></ref-list></back></article>