<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD JATS (Z39.96) Journal Archiving and Interchange DTD with MathML3 v1.2 20190208//EN" "JATS-archivearticle1-mathml3.dtd"> 
<article xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" article-type="news" xml:lang="EN"><?properties open_access?><?DTDIdentifier.IdentifierValue -//ACS//DTD ACS Journal DTD v1.02 20061031//EN?><?DTDIdentifier.IdentifierType public?><?SourceDTD.DTDName ACSJournal-v102.dtd?><?SourceDTD.Version 1.02?><?ConverterInfo.XSLTName acs2nlmx2.xsl?><?ConverterInfo.Version 1?><front><journal-meta><journal-id journal-id-type="nlm-ta">ACS Cent Sci</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="iso-abbrev">ACS Cent Sci</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">oc</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="coden">acscii</journal-id><journal-title-group><journal-title>ACS Central Science</journal-title></journal-title-group><issn pub-type="ppub">2374-7943</issn><issn pub-type="epub">2374-7951</issn><publisher><publisher-name>American Chemical Society</publisher-name></publisher></journal-meta><article-meta><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid">6891848</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmid">31807672</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/acscentsci.9b01133</article-id><article-categories><subj-group><subject>The Hub</subject></subj-group></article-categories><title-group><article-title>Batteries Need a Boost To Fly the Friendly Skies</article-title></title-group><contrib-group><contrib contrib-type="author" id="ath1"><name><surname>Nguyen</surname><given-names>Tien</given-names></name></contrib></contrib-group><pub-date pub-type="epub"><day>14</day><month>11</month><year>2019</year></pub-date><pub-date pub-type="ppub"><day>27</day><month>11</month><year>2019</year></pub-date><volume>5</volume><issue>11</issue><fpage>1738</fpage><lpage>1740</lpage><history/><permissions><copyright-statement>Copyright &#x000a9; 2019 American Chemical Society</copyright-statement><copyright-year>2019</copyright-year><copyright-holder>American Chemical Society</copyright-holder><license><license-p>This is an open access article published under an ACS AuthorChoice <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://pubs.acs.org/page/policy/authorchoice_termsofuse.html">License</ext-link>, which permits copying and redistribution of the article or any adaptations for non-commercial purposes.</license-p></license></permissions><custom-meta-group><custom-meta><meta-name>document-id-old-9</meta-name><meta-value>oc9b01133</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>document-id-new-14</meta-name><meta-value>oc9b01133</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>ccc-price</meta-name><meta-value/></custom-meta></custom-meta-group></article-meta><notes id="notes-d4e21-autogenerated"><title>&#x0200b;</title><p>In collaboration with <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://cen.acs.org/index.html">C&#x00026;EN</ext-link>.</p></notes></front><body><p id="sec98">In August, a two-seater plane
crashed into a lake in Norway. Afterward, the abandoned aircraft,
its passengers unharmed, appeared in photographs with the plane&#x02019;s
tail jutting into the air. The words printed on either wing were upside
down yet easy to read: &#x0201c;Avinor&#x0201d; and &#x0201c;100% electric.&#x0201d;</p><p>For Avinor, the state-run Norwegian company that owns the plane,
the accident was a serious setback. Its downed aircraft was the first
electric model in the world approved for commercial production, according
to the company. And last year, the firm was tasked by Norway&#x02019;s
government with developing a plan to make all domestic flights electric
by 2040.</p><p>Norway isn&#x02019;t alone in its ambitions for green
aviation.
As the climate crisis worsens, governments and consumers worldwide
are looking to reduce air travel&#x02019;s environmental impact. Flights
generate 2.7% of energy-related carbon dioxide emissions worldwide.
And they emit NO<sub><italic>x</italic></sub> and leave behind climate-changing
contrail clouds that scientists have linked to an estimated <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/s41560-018-0294-x">16,000 premature
deaths every year</ext-link>.</p><p>More than 170 programs aiming
to develop electric aircraft are
underway globally, with about half of them dedicated to urban air
taxis that could transport residents from one end of a city to another, <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://www.flightglobal.com/news/articles/electric-aircraft-projects-to-top-200-by-year-end-r-458135/">according to an estimate</ext-link> by Roland Berger, a German consulting
firm. Whether these planes get off the ground depends, mainly, on
their electrical power source: their batteries.</p><p>For small, short-distance
electric aircraft like the one that crashed
in Norway, makers are adapting lithium-ion batteries, a common technology
already on the market (<ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://cen.acs.org/people/nobel-prize/Li-ion-batteries-win-2019-Nobel-Prize-in-Chemistry/97/web/2019/10">and recently recognized with a Nobel Prize</ext-link>). Creating
batteries for bigger planes, capable of traveling farther, poses a
much bigger problem. Today&#x02019;s best Li-ion batteries have a specific
energy&#x02014;or energy per unit mass&#x02014;of around 250 W h/kg,
which falls short of the 800 W h/kg scientists say is needed to keep
a Boeing 737-sized aircraft in the air for a 1,111 km journey (about
the distance from Chicago to New York City).</p><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="oc9b01133_0005" id="gr1" position="float"><caption><p>Avinor&#x02019;s
Alpha Electro G2 is one of many models vying to
enter the electric-airplane market. Credit: Avinor.</p></caption></graphic><p>&#x0201c;Lithium ion is not going to get us there,&#x0201d;
says
John W. Lawson of NASA&#x02019;s Ames Research Center. Over the summer,
his team of collaborators, which included researchers at Ames; NASA&#x02019;s
Glenn Research Center; NASA&#x02019;s Armstrong Flight Research Center;
the University of California, Berkeley; Carnegie Mellon University;
and IBM Research&#x02013;Almaden, wrapped up a 3-year research project
to evaluate another technology that might: the lithium&#x02013;air
battery.</p><p>Scientists have calculated that Li&#x02013;air batteries
(technically,
Li&#x02013;O<sub>2</sub> batteries) could have a maximum specific energy
of 3,460 W h/kg, far greater than what&#x02019;s needed to power large
passenger planes. A bonus feature, Lawson says, is that the oxygen
for these batteries might be supplied by the plane&#x02019;s onboard
air storage and filtration systems, which send air to the cabin and
passengers&#x02019; drop-down emergency masks.</p><p>Li&#x02013;air
batteries&#x02019; potential has tantalized scientists
ever since the technology&#x02019;s introduction decades ago. But a
spate of obstacles, such as extreme degradation that eats away at
the battery&#x02019;s insides as it charges and discharges, has tempered
the field&#x02019;s expectations. No commercial Li&#x02013;air battery
yet exists; at the moment, the technology is limited to the lab. In
recent years, however, researchers have gained a better understanding
of these roadblocks, reinvigorating their attempts to make Li&#x02013;air
batteries one day take flight.</p><p>In 1996, K. M. Abraham and Zhiping
Jiang at EIC Laboratories filed
the first patent for a rechargeable Li&#x02013;air battery. That one
worked with a non-water-based electrolyte. Water-based Li&#x02013;air
batteries, which have lower calculated specific energies than their
nonaqueous counterparts, emerged about a decade later with only limited
examples. The discovery of the non-water-based batteries, Abraham
says, happened by accident.</p><p>Abraham had been working on a Li-ion
battery when he noticed voltage
readings that were slightly off. He realized that the strange measurements
were due to air sneaking into the system, so his team started intentionally
introducing oxygen into its battery setups, eventually leading to
the Li&#x02013;air battery.</p><p>Although its origin was inspired
by Li-ion technology, the Li&#x02013;air
battery has a much more complicated chemistry, Abraham says. The components
inside Li-ion batteries don&#x02019;t change much during charging and
discharging, for instance. Li&#x02013;air batteries, on the other hand,
have to undergo several phase changes. &#x0201c;Whenever there are
phase changes, there will be problems,&#x0201d; Abraham says.</p><p>Li-ion batteries are generally made of an organic electrolyte,
a graphite anode, and a lithium cobalt oxide cathode connected by
a circuit. Discharging them pushes electrons through the circuit and
pushes lithium ions through the electrolyte from one electrode to
the other. When you charge them, everything runs in reverse. A key
feature that makes this design so popular is that the lithium ions
trickle into and out of the pores of the anode and cathode without
significantly changing their structure and volume.</p><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="oc9b01133_0002" id="gr2" position="float"><caption><p>To
discharge energy, lithium&#x02013;air batteries push electrons
to the porous cathode, where they combine with lithium ions and oxygen
in a two-step chemical process. To charge, the process must run in
reverse. Credit: C&#x00026;EN.</p></caption></graphic><p>By volume, Li&#x02013;air
batteries are made mostly of an organic
electrolyte, a porous carbon cathode, and a lithium&#x02013;metal anode.
The porous carbon cathode material remains empty until oxygen arrives.
Discharging a Li&#x02013;air battery takes place through a two-step
chemical process: first, the battery &#x0201c;breathes in&#x0201d; oxygen
through the porous cathode to oxidize the lithium&#x02013;metal anode.
Solid lithium superoxide (LiO<sub>2</sub>) forms at the cathode while
electrons travel through the circuit for use. During the second step,
the electrolyte dissolves the LiO<sub>2</sub>, which reacts with itself
to form solid lithium peroxide (Li<sub>2</sub>O<sub>2</sub>), also
in the cathode. Charging the device breaks down the Li<sub>2</sub>O<sub>2</sub>. This means that each charging cycle significantly
changes the size of the cathode.</p><p>Battery researchers are working
to solve Li&#x02013;air batteries&#x02019;
many challenges, including stabilizing the cathode, protecting the
anode, and efficiently delivering oxygen while keeping out other gas
contaminants. But perhaps the technology&#x02019;s biggest problem
is that the electrolyte decomposes rapidly because of destructive
species formed inside the battery, limiting its rechargeability. To
power aircraft, Li&#x02013;air batteries need to withstand a practical
number of charging cycles; for instance, current Li-ion batteries
last for thousands of cycles. Scientists don&#x02019;t yet know if
this will be possible for Li&#x02013;air batteries, NASA&#x02019;s Lawson
says.</p><p>But his team is working to find out.</p><p>The NASA researchers
have built research-quality Li&#x02013;air
battery packs for demonstration in the context of powering electric
aircraft, according to Lawson. Each pack is a five-cell unit made
of a lithium&#x02013;metal anode, a porous carbon cathode, and an ether-based
electrolyte. With this setup, the team calculates, it should have
a practical specific energy of about 200 W h/kg at the cell level.
This is only about 5% of Li&#x02013;air batteries&#x02019; elusive theoretical
maximum specific energy, Lawson says. But he thinks that when optimized,
the battery pack could reach 700&#x02013;800 W h/kg, the estimated
energy requirement for regional planes. The team also ran a simulation
of a flight profile, including takeoff, cruising, and landing. Model
calculations indicated that the optimized Li&#x02013;air battery could
handle the power requirements for electric aircraft, Lawson says.</p><p>But like many other Li&#x02013;air batteries demonstrated in the
lab, NASA&#x02019;s battery currently lasts for only a handful of recharging
cycles. By switching the electrolyte from an ether-based liquid to
one made of inorganic molten nitrate salts, the team raised the number
of cycles from about 5 to 25. Inorganic electrolytes have previously
been shown to be <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.5b11744">stabler than ether-based ones</ext-link>. They&#x02019;re also generally
safer than organic electrolytes, which can catch fire, as demonstrated
by the defective Samsung Galaxy Note 7 phones that were banned from
planes by the US Federal Aviation Administration in 2016.</p><p>Many
researchers, including battery expert Yang Shao-Horn and organic
materials chemist Jeremiah A. Johnson of the Massachusetts Institute
of Technology, are on the search for better electrolytes.</p><p>&#x0201c;None
of the known lithium-ion electrolytes are stable for
Li&#x02013;O<sub>2</sub> chemistry,&#x0201d; says Shao-Horn, who has
worked on Li-ion batteries for more than 20 years. For decades, she
says, researchers in the battery field have focused on just a few
electrolyte materials. So a few years ago, she decided to knock on
Johnson&#x02019;s door to get a fresh perspective.</p><p>&#x0201c;From
an organic chemistry perspective, the challenge of
Li&#x02013;O<sub>2</sub> is that you&#x02019;re basically asking an
electrolyte to face many of the harshest reactive oxygen species possible,&#x0201d;
including singlet oxygen, Johnson says. Scientists have proposed that
singlet oxygen arises from lithium superoxide, either when the compound
breaks down or when it gets oxidized during charging. &#x0201c;That&#x02019;s
why when people use the same electrolytes used for Li-ion batteries,
where those reactive species don&#x02019;t exist, they often don&#x02019;t
work. They degrade very rapidly upon charging of the cell.&#x0201d;</p><p>Together, Shao-Horn&#x02019;s and Johnson&#x02019;s laboratories
developed a framework to <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://doi.org/10.1039/C7TA08321A">identify electrolyte molecules
that could survive Li&#x02013;air batteries&#x02019; conditions</ext-link>. An ideal electrolyte molecule would meet four criteria: its hydrogens
would be bound strongly to the compound to avoid being plucked off
by radicals, it would have a high p<italic>K</italic><sub>a</sub> so
it can&#x02019;t react with bases and degrade, it would lack sites
vulnerable to nucleophilic attack, and it would be able to resist
electrochemical oxidation. This dream electrolyte would possess all
these features while also being able to perform its primary job inside
the battery, which is to solubilize lithium ions and ferry them back
and forth between electrodes.</p><p>That&#x02019;s a tall order for
any molecule, but Shao-Horn and
Johnson think it exists. This past summer, they <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://doi.org/10.1016/j.chempr.2019.07.003">published work</ext-link> on sulfamide- and sulfonamide-based electrolytes in a Li&#x02013;air
battery. One robust molecule in particular, <italic>N</italic>,<italic>N</italic>-dimethyl-trifluoromethanesulfonamide, resisted degradation
for greater than 90 cycles in a Li&#x02013;O<sub>2</sub> battery cell
below 4.2 V.</p><p>Next, the MIT team hopes to take what it&#x02019;s
learned and incorporate
these functional groups into a solid, polymer-based electrolyte, which
would also be safer than flammable liquid organic electrolytes.</p><p>Another looming challenge for Li&#x02013;air technology in an airborne
setting is whether the batteries can run on air rather than pure oxygen.
Laboratory-scale batteries have so far run on purified O<sub>2</sub>, but ambient air includes nonoxygen constituents, such as carbon
dioxide and water.</p><p>Water has long been thought of as problematic
for nonaqueous Li&#x02013;air
batteries because it can react with lithium metal to form unwanted
lithium hydroxide, which is difficult to break down. But recent experiments
suggest that this side reaction requires more water than scientists
thought, which makes operating the battery in air much easier, says
the University of Oxford&#x02019;s Peter Bruce, who has been working
on Li&#x02013;air batteries over the past decade. To get around any
problems that carbon dioxide might cause in Li&#x02013;air batteries,
Bruce suggests that researchers could apply carbon-capture technology,
which pulls CO<sub>2</sub> from gas streams, to air-processing systems
on planes.</p><p>Although Li&#x02013;air batteries haven&#x02019;t entered
the market,
manufacturers have shown interest in developing the batteries. IBM
ran a robust research program for developing Li&#x02013;air batteries
earlier this decade, but the firm has since shifted away from this
type of battery. Samsung recently reported a Li&#x02013;air battery
that has a folded cell structure a few hundred micrometers thick and
contains a proprietary polymeric electrolyte that achieved a specific
energy of 1,214 W h/kg. In terms of rechargeability, the <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://doi.org/10.1016/j.joule.2018.11.016">team demonstrated</ext-link> that a cell with a specific energy of 300 W h/kg could cycle eight
times.</p><p>For now, Li&#x02013;air technology has a long way to go
before becoming
practical, for electric aircraft or any other use. But researchers
are still eager to see how far Li&#x02013;air batteries&#x02019; development
can go. &#x0201c;Recent progress has been very encouraging,&#x0201d;
Bruce says, adding that &#x0201c;we haven&#x02019;t come up against
any showstoppers.&#x0201d; So they&#x02019;re not only eager&#x02014;they&#x02019;re
optimistic.</p><sec id="sec99"><p><italic>Tien Nguyen is a freelance science writer
based in Washington,
DC. This story appeared in</italic><ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://cen.acs.org/"><italic>Chemical &#x00026; Engineering News</italic></ext-link><italic>, the weekly news magazine of the American Chemical
Society.</italic></p></sec></body></article>